<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="sw_schema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<root>
   <title>Star Wars: Episode II - Attack of the Clones (2002)</title>
by <writer>George Lucas.</writer>
   <script>
      <setting>EXT. <name type="LOC">SPACE</name>
      </setting>
      <sd>A vast sea of stars severas as a backdrop for <name type="ORG">the Main</name> Title, following by a rollup, which crawls into infinity.</sd>
      <subTitle epNum="2">EPISODE 2 ATTACK OF THE <name type="ORG">CLONES</name>
      </subTitle>
      <crawl>There is unrest in the <name type="NORP">Galactic</name>
         <name type="LOC">Senate</name>
Several hundred solar systems under
the leadership of the rebel leader, <name type="ORG">Count</name>
         <name type="PERSON">Dooku</name>, have decalred their intentions to
secede from the Republic.
This separatist movement has made it
difficult for the limited number of
<name type="GPE">Jedi Kights</name> to maintain peace and
order in the galaxy.
<name type="PERSON">Senator</name>
         <name type="PERSON">Amidala</name>, the former <name type="PERSON">Queen</name> of
<name type="LOC">Naboo</name>, is returning to <name type="LOC">Coruscant</name>
to vote on the critical issue
of creating an army to assist the
overwhelmed Jedi.</crawl>
      <sd>
         <name type="ORG">PAN</name> UP to reveal the amber city planet of <name type="LOC">Coruscant</name>. A yellow <name type="LOC">Naboo</name> Fighter flies OVER CAMERA toward the planet, followed by a large <name type="ORG">Royal Cruiser</name> and two more Fighters.</sd>
      <setting>EXT. CITYSCAPE, CORUSCANT - DAWN</setting>
      <sd>The ships skim across the surface of the city landscape. The sun glints off the chrome hulls of the sleek <name type="LOC">Naboo</name> spacecraft as they navigate between the buildings of the capital planet.</sd>
      <setting>EXT. CORUSCANT, LANDING PLATFORM - DAWN</setting>
      <sd>Two <name type="LOC">Naboo</name> Fighters land on one leaf of a three-leaf-clover landing platform. The Royal Starship lands on the central lead, and the third Fighter lands on the remaining plaform.</sd>
      <sd>A small <name type="ORG">GROUP</name> OF <name type="ORG">DIGNITARIES</name> waits to welcome the <name type="PERSON">Senator</name>. One of the members of the group os a well dressed <name type="ORG">JAR</name>
         <name type="ORG">JAR</name> BINKS, a member of the <name type="NORP">Galactic</name> Representative Commission, and DORME, <name type="PERSON">Senator</name>
         <name type="PERSON">Amidala</name>'s handmaiden.</sd>
      <sd>One of the FIGHTER PILOTS jumps from the wing of his ship and removes his helmet. He is CAPTAIN <name type="ORG">TYPHO</name>, <name type="PERSON">SENATOR</name> PADME'S Security Officer. He moves over to a WOMAN PILOT.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>CAPTAIN <name type="ORG">TYPHO</name>
         </speaker>
			We made it. I guess I was wrong,
			there was no danger at all.</sp>
      <sd>The ramp ;pwers. TWO <name type="LOC">NABOO</name> GUARDS appear. <name type="PERSON">SENATOR</name> PADME, ONE HANDMAIDEN (VERSE) and FOUR TROOPERS descend the ramp. PADME is more beautiful now than she was ten years earlier when, as <name type="PERSON">Queen</name>, she was freeing her people from the yoke of the Trade <name type="ORG">Federation</name>.</sd>
      <sd>The <name type="ORG">DIGNITARIES</name> start to move forward. <name type="PERSON">SENATOR</name> PADME reaches the foot of the ramp, when suddenly there is a blinding FLASH and a huge <name type="ORG">EXPLOSION</name>. The <name type="ORG">DIGNITARIES</name> and PILOTS are hurled to the ground as the starship is destroyed.</sd>
      <sd>Klaxons blare, alarms sound! CAPTAIN <name type="ORG">TYPHO</name> and the TWO ESCORT PILOTS get up and run to where <name type="PERSON">SENATOR</name> PADME lies dying. Beyond, <name type="PERSON">ARTOO</name> DETOO drops down from the <name type="LOC">Naboo</name> Fighter and rolls toward the wreckage. The FEMALE ESCORT PILOT kneels by <name type="PERSON">SENATOR</name> PADME and takes off her helmet, revealing <name type="PERSON">SENATOR</name> PADME PADME.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>PADME </speaker>
			Cord�...</sp>
      <sd>She gathers up her decoy double in her arms. Cord�'s eyes are open. She looks up at her.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>CORDE</speaker>
			... I'm sorry, m'lady... I'm... not sure I... </sp>
      <sd>CORDE dies. PADME hugs her.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>PADME</speaker>
			No!... No!... No!...</sp>
      <sd>PADME lowers CORDE to the ground. She gets up and looks around at the devastation. There are tears in her eyes.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>PADME</speaker>
			I should not have come back.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>CAPTAIN <name type="ORG">TYPHO</name>
         </speaker>
			M'Lady, you are still in danger.</sp>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">Amidala</name> says nothing.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>CAPTAIN <name type="ORG">TYPHO</name>
         </speaker>
			This vote is very important. You did
			your duty and Cord� did hers. Now
			come. (she doesn't respond) M'Lady,
			please!</sp>
      <sd>She turns. They walk away. <name type="PERSON">ARTOO</name> lets out a small whimper and rolls off after them.</sd>
      <setting>EXT. SENATE BUILDING - DAY </setting>
      <sd>The massive <name type="LOC">Senate</name> Building glistens in the afternoon sun. Small patches of fog have still to burn off.</sd>
      <setting>INT. SENATE CHAMBER - DAY</setting>
      <sd>The vast rotunda is buzzing with chatter. <name type="ORG">MAS</name> AMEDDA, the <name type="ORG">Supreme</name> Chancellor's majordomo, tries to quiet things down as <name type="PERSON">PALPATINE</name> confers with an AIDE, UV GIZEN, riding a small one man floating scooter.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="ORG">MAS</name> AMEDDA</speaker>
			Order! We shall have order! The motion
			for the Republic to commission an army
			takes precedent, and that is what we
			will vote on at this time.</sp>
      <sd>Everything quiets down. The AIDE disperses, and <name type="ORG">SUPREME CHANCELLOR</name>
         <name type="PERSON">PALPATINE</name> steps to the podium.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">PALPATINE</name>
         </speaker>
			...My esteemed colleagues, excuse
			me... I have just received some
			tragic and disturbing news. <name type="PERSON">Senator</name>
         <name type="PERSON">Amidala</name> of the <name type="LOC">Naboo</name> system... Has
			been assassinated!</sp>
      <sd>There is a shock silence in the vast arena.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">PALPATINE</name>
         </speaker>
				(continued)
			This grievous blow is especially
			personal to me. Before I became
			Chancellor, I served <name type="PERSON">Amidala</name> when
			she was <name type="PERSON">Queen</name>. She was a great
			leader who fought for justice, not
			only in this honourable assembly,
			but also on her home planet. She
			was so loved she could have been
			elected queen for life. She
			believed in public service, and
			she fervently believed in
			democracy. Her death is a great
			loss to us all. We will all mourn
			her as a relentless champion of
			freedom... and as a dear friend.</sp>
      <sd>There is a moment of silence. <name type="ORG">ASK AAK</name>, the <name type="PERSON">SENATOR</name> of <name type="ORG">MALASTARE</name>, moves his pod into the centre of the arena.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">SENATOR</name>
            <name type="ORG">ASK AAK</name>
         </speaker>
			How many more <name type="PERSON">Senator</name>s will die
			before this civil strife ends! We
			must confront these rebels now,
			and they need an army to do it.</sp>
      <sd>A second pod moves into the centre of the area with <name type="PERSON">DARSANA</name>, the 
AMBASSADOR OF GLEE ANSELM.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>AMBASSADOR <name type="PERSON">DARSANA</name>
         </speaker>
			Why weren't <name type="FAC">the Jedi</name> able to stop
			this assassination? We are no
			longer safe, under their protection.</sp>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">Senator</name>
         <name type="PERSON">ORN</name> FREE <name type="PERSON">TAA</name> swings forward in his pod.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">ORN</name> FREE <name type="PERSON">TAA</name>
         </speaker>
			The Republic needs more security
			now! Before it comes to war.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">PALPATINE</name>
         </speaker>
			Must I remind the <name type="PERSON">Senator</name> from
			<name type="PERSON">Malastare</name> that negotiations are
			continuing with the separatists.
			Peace is our objective here... not
			war.</sp>
      <sd>The <name type="PERSON">SENATOR</name>S yell pro and con. <name type="ORG">MAS</name> AMEDDA tries to calm things down. <name type="PERSON">SENATOR</name> PADME PADME, with CAPTAIN <name type="ORG">TYPHO</name>, <name type="ORG">JAR</name>
         <name type="ORG">JAR</name>, and DORME, manoeuvre her pod into the centre of the vast arena.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>PADME</speaker>
			My noble colleagues, I concur with
			the <name type="ORG">Supreme</name> Chancellor. At all
			costs, we do not want war!</sp>
      <sd>The <name type="LOC">Senate</name> goes quiet, then there is an outburst of cheering and 
applause.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">PALPATINE</name>
         </speaker>
			It is with great surprise and
			joy the chair recognises the
			<name type="PERSON">Senator</name> from <name type="LOC">Naboo</name>, Padm� <name type="PERSON">Amidala</name>.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>PADME</speaker>
			Less than an hour ago, an
			assassination attempt was made
			against my life. One of my
			bodyguards and six  others were
			ruthlessly and senselessly
			murdered. I was the target but,
			more importantly, I believe this
			security measure before you, was
			the target. I have led the
			opposition to build an army... but
			there is someone in this body who
			will stop at nothing to assure it's
			passage...</sp>
      <sd>Many of the <name type="PERSON">SENATOR</name>S boo and yell at <name type="PERSON">SENATOR</name> PADME.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>PADME</speaker>
			 	(continuing)
			I warn you, if you vote to create
			this army, war will follow. I
			have experienced the misery of war 
			first-hand; I do not wish to do it
			again.</sp>
      <sd>There is sporadic yelling for and against her statements.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>PADME</speaker>
			Wake up, <name type="PERSON">Senator</name>s... you must wake
			up! If you offer the separatists
			violence, they can only show us
			violence in return! Many will
			lose their lives. All will lose
			their freedom. This decision
			could very well destroy the very
			foundation of our great Republic.
			I pray you do not let fear push
			you into a disastrous decision.
			Vote down this security measure,
			which is nothing less than a
			declaration of war! Does anyone
			here want that? I cannot believe
			they do.</sp>
      <sd>There is an undercurrent of booing... and groaning. <name type="PERSON">SENATOR</name>
         <name type="PERSON">ORN</name> FREE <name type="PERSON">TAA</name> moves his pod next to PADME.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">ORN</name> FREE <name type="PERSON">TAA</name>
         </speaker>
			My motion to defer the vote must
			be dealt with first. That is the
			rule of law.</sp>
      <sd>PADME looks angry and frustrated. <name type="PERSON">PALPATINE</name> gives her a sympathetic look.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">PALPATINE</name>
         </speaker>
			Due to the lateness of the hour
			and the seriousness of this
			motion, we will take up these
			matters tomorrow. Until then, the
			<name type="LOC">Senate</name> stands adjourned.</sp>
      <setting>EXT. EXECUTIVE QUARTERS BUILDING - DAY </setting>
      <sd>The giant towers of the Republic Executive Building seem to reach the heavens. Traffic clogs the smoggy sky.</sd>
      <setting>INT. CHANCELLOR'S OFFICE - DAY </setting>
      <sd>CHANCELLOR <name type="PERSON">PALPATINE</name> sits behind his desk with TWO RED-CLAD ROYAL GUARDS on either side of the door. YODA, <name type="ORG">PLO</name>T KOON, <name type="GPE">KI</name>-AD-MUNDI, and <name type="PERSON">MACE</name> WINDU sit acress from him.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">PALPATINE</name>
         </speaker>
			I don't know how much longer I can
			hold off the vote, my friends.
			More and more star systems are
			joining the separatists.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">MACE</name> WINDU</speaker>
			If they do break away -</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">PALPATINE</name>
         </speaker>
			No! I will not let that happen!</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">MACE</name> WINDU</speaker>
			But if they do, you must realise
			there aren't enough Jedi to
			protect the Republic. We are
			keepers of the peace, not soldiers.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">PALPATINE</name>
         </speaker>
			Master <name type="PERSON">Yoda</name>, do you think it will
			really come to war?</sp>
      <sd>YODA closes his eyes.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>YODA</speaker>
			Worse than war, I fear... Much
			worse. </sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">PALPATINE</name>
         </speaker>
			What?</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">MACE</name> WINDU</speaker>
			What do you sense, Master?</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>YODA</speaker>
			Impossible to see ... The Dark Side
			clouds everything. But this I am
			sure of -
				(opens his eyes)
			Do their duty <name type="FAC">the Jedi</name> will.</sp>
      <sd>A muted BUZZER SOUNDS. A hologram of an AIDE, <name type="ORG">DAR WAC</name>, appears on the Chancellor's desk.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="ORG">DAR WAC</name>
         </speaker>
			The loyalist committee has arrived,
			my Lord. </sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">PALPATINE</name>
         </speaker>
			Send them in.</sp>
      <sd>They all stand as <name type="PERSON">SENATOR</name> PADME, CAPTAIN <name type="ORG">TYPHO</name>, <name type="ORG">JAR</name>
         <name type="ORG">JAR</name>, <name type="ORG">MAS</name> AMEDDA, DORME, and <name type="PERSON">SENATOR</name>S <name type="ORG">BAIL</name>
         <name type="PERSON">ORGANA</name>, <name type="ORG">HOROX RYYDER</name> and <name type="PERSON">ORN</name> FREE <name type="PERSON">TAA</name> enter the office. YODA and <name type="PERSON">MACE</name> WINDU move to greet the <name type="PERSON">SENATOR</name>, YODA taps PADME with his cane.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>YODA</speaker>
			With you the force is strong...
			young <name type="PERSON">Senator</name>. To see you alive
			brings warm feeling to my heart.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>PADME</speaker>
			Thank you, Master <name type="PERSON">Yoda</name>. Do you
			have any idea who was behind
			the attack?</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">MACE</name> WINDU</speaker>
			Our intelligence points to
			disgruntled spice miners, on
			the <name type="LOC">moon</name>s of <name type="LOC">Naboo</name>.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>PADME</speaker>
			I don't wish to disagree but I
			think that <name type="ORG">Count</name>
         <name type="PERSON">Dooku</name> was behind
			it.</sp>
      <sd>There is a stir of surprise.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">MACE</name> WINDU</speaker>
			You know, M'Lady, <name type="ORG">Count</name>
         <name type="PERSON">Dooku</name>
			was once a Jedi. He wouldn't
			assassinate anyone, it is not in
			his character.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="GPE">KI</name>-ADI-MUNDI</speaker>
			He is a political idealist, not
			a murderer.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>YODA</speaker>
			In dark times nothing is what it
			appears to be, but the fact remains
			<name type="PERSON">Senator</name>, in grave danger you are.</sp>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">PALPATINE</name> gets up, walks to the window, and looks out at the vast city.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">PALPATINE</name>
         </speaker>
         <name type="ORG">Count</name>
         <name type="PERSON">Dooku</name> has always avoided
			any kind of conflict. It appears
			he has no desire to start a war.
			Why would he kill you? To what end?</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>PADME </speaker>
			I don't know, but everything in my
			being tells me he was behind it... </sp>
      <sd>After gazing out of the window for several moments <name type="PERSON">Palpatine</name> turns to 
<name type="PERSON">Mace</name>.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">PALPATINE</name>
         </speaker>
			Master Jedi, may I suggest that
			the <name type="PERSON">Senator</name> be placed under the
			protection of your graces.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="ORG">BAIL</name>
            <name type="PERSON">ORGANA</name>
         </speaker>
			Do you think that is a wise use
			of manpower during these stressful
			times?</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>PADME</speaker>
			Chancellor, if I may comment, I
			do not believe the...</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">PALPATINE</name>
         </speaker>
			..."situation is that serious."
			No, but I do, <name type="PERSON">Senator</name>.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>PADME</speaker>
			Chancellor, please! I don't want
			any more guards!</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">PALPATINE</name>
         </speaker>
			I realise all too well that
			additional security might be
			disruptive for you, but perhaps
			someone you are familiar with... an
			old friend like... Master <name type="PERSON">Kenobi</name>...</sp>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">PALPATINE</name> nods to <name type="PERSON">MACE</name> WINDU, who nods back.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">MACE</name> WINDU</speaker>
			That's possible. He has just
			returned from a Border dispute on
			Ansion.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">PALPATINE</name>
         </speaker>
			You must remember him, M'Lady...
			he watched over you during the
			blockade conflict.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>PADME</speaker>
			This is not necessary, Chancellor.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">PALPATINE</name>
         </speaker>
			Do it for me, M'Lady, please. I
			will rest easier. We had a big
			scare today. The thought of
			losing you is unbearable.</sp>
      <sd>PADME sighs as the <name type="FAC">JEDI</name> get up to leave.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">MACE</name> WINDU</speaker>
			I will have Obi-Wan report to you
			immediately, M'Lady.</sp>
      <sd>YODA leans into her ear.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>YODA</speaker>
			Too little about yourself you
			worry, <name type="PERSON">Senator</name>, and too much about
			politics. Be mindful of your
			danger, Padm�. Accept our help.</sp>
      <sd>As the <name type="FAC">JEDI</name> leave the office, <name type="PERSON">PALPATINE</name> continues to pace behind his desk.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">PALPATINE</name>
         </speaker>
			I will not like this Republiv, that
			has stood for over a thousand
			years, be split in two</sp>
      <setting>EXT. SENATE APARTMENTS - TWILIGHT</setting>
      <sd>A graceful skyscraper twinkles in the evening light of <name type="LOC">Coruscant</name>.</sd>
      <setting>INT. SENATE BUILDING, APARTMENT CORRIDOR - EVENING</setting>
      <sd>The door to the apartment slides open. <name type="ORG">JAR</name>
         <name type="ORG">JAR</name> walks into the corridor, where TWO <name type="FAC">JEDI</name> are exiting the elevator. He recognises OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name> and becomes extremely excited, jumping around, shaking his hand.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="ORG">JAR</name>
            <name type="ORG">JAR</name>
         </speaker>
			Obi! Obi! Obi! Mesa sooo smilen
			to see'en yousa. Wahoooooo!</sp>
      <sd>OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name> smiles.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name>
         </speaker>
			It's Good to see you, too, <name type="PERSON">Jar Jar</name>.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="ORG">JAR</name>
            <name type="ORG">JAR</name>
         </speaker>
			Oops! Wheresa <name type="ORG">mesa</name> manners?
			Excuse me, Master Obi-Wan. I
			completely forgot myself for
			a moment there. I have had to learn
			Diplodiaclect... speak it like a
			native now. Don't really see the
			point, actually, but members of
			the <name type="LOC">Senate</name> seem to prefer it...</sp>
      <sd>
         <name type="ORG">JAR</name>
         <name type="ORG">JAR</name> notices OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name>'S APPRENTICE.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="ORG">JAR</name>
            <name type="ORG">JAR</name>
         </speaker>
				(continuing)
			...and this, I take it, is your
			apprentice... Nooooooooo! Annie?
			Noooooooo! Little Bitty Annie?
				(Looks at <name type="PERSON">Anakin</name>)
			Nooooooo! Yousa so biggen!
			Yiyiyiyyi! Annie!! Mesa no
			believen.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name>
         </speaker>
			Hi, <name type="PERSON">Jar Jar</name>.</sp>
      <sd>
         <name type="ORG">JAR</name>
         <name type="ORG">JAR</name> grabs hold of <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name> and envelops him in a big hug.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="ORG">JAR</name>
            <name type="ORG">JAR</name>
         </speaker>
			Annie! Annie! Yiyiyiyiyiyiiii!</sp>
      <setting>INT. SENATE BUILDING, APARTMENT - EVENING</setting>
      <sd>PADME is in a conference with CAPTAIN <name type="ORG">TYPHO</name> and DORME. <name type="ORG">JAR</name>
         <name type="ORG">JAR</name> enters the room, followed by the TWO <name type="FAC">JEDI</name>.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="ORG">JAR</name>
            <name type="ORG">JAR</name>
         </speaker>
			Lookie... lookie... Oops!... Oh,
			dear, I'm afraid I've forgotten
			myself again.</sp>
      <sd>PADME and <name type="ORG">TYPHO</name> rise as OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name> and <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name> stop before the <name type="PERSON">SENATOR</name>. OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name> steps forward. <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name> stares at PADME. She glances at him.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name>
         </speaker>
			It's a great pleasure to see you again,
			M'Lady.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>PADME</speaker>
			It has been far too long Master
			<name type="PERSON">Kenobi</name>. I'm so glad our paths
			have crossed again... but I must
			warn you that I think your
			presence here is unnecessary.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name>
         </speaker>
			I'm sure <name type="FAC">the Jedi</name>
         <name type="ORG">Council</name> have
			their reasons.</sp>
      <sd>She moves in front of <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name>
      </sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>PADME</speaker>
			Annie??
				(stares)
			My goodness you've grown.</sp>
      <sd>They look at each other for a long moment.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name>
         </speaker>
				(trying to be smooth)
			So have you... grown more
			beautiful, I mean... and much
			shorter... for a <name type="PERSON">Senator</name>, I mean.</sp>
      <sd>OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name> looks disapprovingly at his apprentice. PADME laughs and shakes her head.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>PADME</speaker>
			Oh Annie, you'll always be that
			little boy I knew on <name type="LOC">Tatooine</name>.</sp>
      <sd>This embarrasses <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name>, and he looks down. OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name> and CAPTAIN <name type="ORG">TYPHO</name> smile.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name>
         </speaker>
			Our presence will be invisible,
			M'Lady.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>CAPTAIN <name type="ORG">TYPHO</name>
         </speaker>
			I am very grateful you are here,
			Master <name type="PERSON">Kenobi</name>. The situation is
			more dangerous than the <name type="PERSON">Senator</name>
			will admit.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>PADME</speaker>
			I don't need more security, I need
			answers. I want to know who is
			trying to kill me.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name>
         </speaker>
				(frowning)
			We're here to protect you
			<name type="PERSON">Senator</name>, not to start an
			investigation.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name>
         </speaker>
			We will find out who is trying to
			kill you Padm�, I promise you.</sp>
      <sd>He's done it again. He bites his lip in frustration and shame. OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name> gives <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name> a dirty look.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name>
         </speaker>
			We are not going to exceed our
			mandate, my young Padawan learner.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name>
         </speaker>
			I meant in the interest of
			protecting her, Master, of course.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name>
         </speaker>
			We are not going through this
			exercise again, <name type="PERSON">Anakin</name>. You will
			pay attention to my lead.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name>
         </speaker>
			Why?</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name>
         </speaker>
			What??!!</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name>
         </speaker>
			Why else do you think we were
			assigned to her, if not to find
			the killer? Protection is a job
			for local security... not Jedi.
			It's overkill, Master.
			Investigation is implied in our
			mandate.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name>
         </speaker>
			We will do as the <name type="ORG">Council</name> has
			instructed, and you will learn
			your place, young one.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>PADME</speaker>
			Perhaps with merely your presence,
			the mysteries surrounding this
			threat will be revealed.  Now if
			you will excuse me I will retire.</sp>
      <sd>Everyone gives PADME a slight bow as she and DORME leave the room.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>CAPTAIN <name type="ORG">TYPHO</name>
         </speaker>
			Well, I know I feel a lot better
			having you here.
			I'll have an officer on every
			floor and I'll be at the command
			centre downstairs.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="ORG">JAR</name>
            <name type="ORG">JAR</name>
         </speaker>
			Mesa busten wit happiness seein
			Yousa again, Annie. Deesa bad
			times, bombad times.</sp>
      <sd>Captain <name type="PERSON">Typho</name> leaves.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name>
         </speaker>
			She didn't even recognise me, Jar
			Jar. I thought about her every
			day since we parted... and she's
			forgotten me completely.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="ORG">JAR</name>
            <name type="ORG">JAR</name>
         </speaker>
			Shesa happy. Happier den <name type="ORG">mesa</name>
			see-en her in longo time.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name>
         </speaker>
         <name type="PERSON">Anakin</name>, you're focusing on the
			Negative again. Be mindful of your
			thoughts. She was glad to see us.
			Now lets check the security here.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name>
         </speaker>
			Yes, my master.</sp>
      <setting>EXT. <name type="FAC">JEDI</name> TEMPLE - EVENING</setting>
      <sd>The vast Jedi <name type="LOC">Temple</name> sits on an endless flat plain, silhouetted by a against the traffic-filled sky.</sd>
      <setting>INT. <name type="FAC">JEDI</name> TEMPLE, CORRIDOR - EVENING</setting>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">MACE</name> WINDU and YODA walk down the long hallways, silhouetted by a lit room at the end.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">MACE</name> WINDU</speaker>
			Why couldn't we see this attack on
			the <name type="PERSON">Senator</name>?</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>YODA</speaker>
			Masking the future, is this
			disturbance in the <name type="ORG">Force</name>.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">MACE</name> WINDU</speaker>
			The propecy is coming true, the
			Dark Side is growing.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>YODA</speaker>
			And only those who have turned to
			the Dark Side can sense the
			possibilities of the future. Only
			going through the Dark Side can we
			see.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">MACE</name> WINDU</speaker>
			It's been ten years, and the Sith
			still have no shown themselves.
			Do you think they are behind this?</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>YODA</speaker>
			...Out there, they are. A
			certainty that is.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">MACE</name> WINDU</speaker>
			Do you think Obi-Wan's apprentice
			will be able to bring balance to
			the <name type="ORG">Force</name>?</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>YODA</speaker>
			Only if he chooses to follow his
			destiny.</sp>
      <sd>There is a long silence as they walk away. Only footsteps are heard.</sd>
      <setting>INT. SENATE BUILDING, PADME'S APARTMENT, BEDROOM - NIGHT</setting>
      <sd>PADME is asleep in her bed, lit only by the light of the city outside her window coming through the blinds. <name type="PERSON">ARTOO</name> stands in the corner of the bedroom. His power is off.</sd>
      <setting>INT. SENATE BUILDING, PADME'S APARTMENT, MAIN R0OM - NIGHT</setting>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name> is standing in the living room. He is in a meditative state. It is quiet. We hear DISTANT <name type="ORG">FOOTSTEPS</name> in the corridor outside the apartment. Suddenly <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name>'S eyes pop open. His eyes dart around the room. He reaches for his lightsaber, then smiles and puts it back in his belt.</sd>
      <sd>The door to the apartment slides open, and OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name> enters.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name>
         </speaker>
			Captain <name type="PERSON">Typho</name> has more than enough
			men downstairs. No assassin will
			try that way. Any activity up
			here?</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name>
         </speaker>
			Quiet as a tomb. I don't like
			just waiting here for something to
			happen to her.</sp>
      <sd>OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name> checks a palm-sized view scanner he has pulled out of his utility belt. It shows a shot of <name type="PERSON">ARTOO</name> by the door, but no sign of PADME on the bed.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name>
         </speaker>
			What's going on?</sp>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name> shrugs.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name>
         </speaker>
			She covered that camera. I don't
			think she liked me watching her.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name>
         </speaker>
			What is she thinking?</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name>
         </speaker>
			She programmed <name type="PERSON">Artoo</name> to warn us if
			there's an intruder.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name>
         </speaker>
			It's not an intruder I'm worried
			about. There are many other ways
			to kill a <name type="PERSON">Senator</name>.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name>
         </speaker>
			I know, but we also want to catch
			this assassin. Don't we, Master?</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name>
         </speaker>
			You're using her as bait??</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name>
         </speaker>
			It was her idea... No harm will
			come to her. I can sense
			everything going on in that room.
			Trust me.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name>
         </speaker>
			It's too risky... and your senses
			aren't that attuned, young
			apprentice.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name>
         </speaker>
			And yours are?</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name>
         </speaker>
			Possibly.</sp>
      <setting>INT. SENATE BUILDING, PADME'S APARTMENT, BEDROOM - NIGHT</setting>
      <sd>As PADME sleeps, a PROBE DROID approaches outside her window. It sends out several small arms that attach to the window, creating sparks that shut down the security system. Then a large arm cuts a small hole in the glass. A FAINT SOUND is heard as the small section of glass is removed from the window.</sd>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">ARTOO</name> wakes up, and his lights go on. The PROBE DROID freezes. <name type="PERSON">ARTOO</name> looks around, makes a PLAINTIVE LITTLE SOUND, then shuts down again. The PROBE DROID attaches a little tube to the window. TWO DEADLY LOO<name type="GPE">KI</name>NG CENTIPEDE-LIKE <name type="ORG">KOUHUNS</name> exit the tube, crawl through the blinds and head toward the sleeping PADME.</sd>
      <setting>INT. SENATE BUILDING, PADME'S APARTMENT, MAIN ROOM - NIGHT</setting>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name> and OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name> continue their conversation in the main room of the apartment.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name>
         </speaker>
			You look tired.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name>
         </speaker>
			I don't sleep well, anymore.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name>
         </speaker>
			Because of your mother?</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name>
         </speaker>
			I don't know why I keep dreaming
			About her now. I haven't seen her
			since I was little.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name>
         </speaker>
			Dreams pass in time.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name>
         </speaker>
			I'd rather dream of Padm�. Just
			Being around her again is...
			intoxicating.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name>
         </speaker>
			Mind your thoughts, <name type="PERSON">Anakin</name>, they
			betray you. You've made a
			commitment to <name type="FAC">the Jedi</name> order... a
			commitment not easily broken...
			and don't forget she's a
			politician. They're not to be
			trusted.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name>
         </speaker>
			She's not like the others in the
			<name type="LOC">Senate</name>, Master.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name>
         </speaker>
			It's been my experience that
			<name type="PERSON">Senator</name>s are only focused on
			pleasing those who fund their
			campaigns... and they are more
			than willing to forget the
			niceties of democracy to get those
			funds.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name>
         </speaker>
			Not another lecture, Master. Not
			on the economics of politics....
			It's too early in the morning... and
			besides, you're generalising. The
			Chancellor doesn't appear to
			be corrupt.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name>
         </speaker>
         <name type="PERSON">Palpatine</name>'s a politician, I've
			observed that he is very clever at
			following the passions and
			prejudices of the <name type="PERSON">Senator</name>s.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name>
         </speaker>
			I think he is a good man. My
			instincts are very positive
			about...</sp>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name> looks stunned. He looks sharply at OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name>
      </sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name>
         </speaker>
			I sense it, too.</sp>
      <setting>INT. SENATE BUILDING, PADME'S APARTMENT, BEDROOM - NIGHT</setting>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">ARTOO</name> sounds an alarm and shines a light on the bed. THE <name type="ORG">KOUHUNS</name> are inches from PADME'S face. Their mouths are open, and wicked stinger tongues flick out.</sd>
      <sd>OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name> and <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name> burst into the room. The <name type="ORG">KOUHUNS</name> stand on their hind legs and hiss as PADME wakes up. <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name> throws himself in front of her, whacking in half the deadly creatures with his lightsaber.</sd>
      <sd>OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name> sees the DROID outside the window and raqces straight at it, crashing through the blinds as he goes through the window.</sd>
      <setting>EXT. WINDOW LEDGE, APARTMENT BUILDING - NIGHT</setting>
      <sd>OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name> flies through the glass window and flings himself at the PROBE DROID, grabbing onto the deadly machine before it can flee. The PROBE DROID sinks under the weight of OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name> but manages to stay afloat and fly away, with <name type="FAC">the Jedi</name> hanging on for dear life, a hundred stories above the city.</sd>
      <setting>INT. SENATE BUILDING, PADME'S APARTMENT - NIGHT</setting>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name> and PADME stare at the sight of OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name> being carried off by the DROID. <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name> turns to her. She pulls her nightdress around her shoulders.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name>
         </speaker>
			Stay here!</sp>
      <sd>CAPTAIN <name type="ORG">TYPHO</name>, with TWO GUARDS and DORME, enter the room as <name type="PERSON">Anakin</name> dashes out.</sd>
      <setting>EXT. CITYSCAPE, CORUSCANT - NIGHT</setting>
      <sd>The PROBE DROID sends several protective electrical shocks across its surface, causing OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name> to almost lose his grip. As they dart in and out of the speeder traffic, OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name> disconnects a wire on the back of the DROID. Its power shuts off! OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name> and the DROID drop like rocks. OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name> realises the error of his ways and quickly puts the wire back. The DROID'S systems light up again and it takes off. </sd>
      <setting>EXT. SENATE APARTMENTS - ENTRANCE - NIGHT</setting>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name> charges out of the building and runs to a line of parked speeders. He vaults into an open one and takes off, gunning it fast toward the lines of speeder traffic high above.</sd>
      <setting>EXT. CITYSCAPE, CORUSCANT - NIGHT</setting>
      <sd>The DROID bumps against a wall, hoping to knock <name type="FAC">the Jedi</name> loose. It moves behind a speeder afterburner to scorch him. It takesthe <name type="FAC">JEDI</name> wildly between buildings and finally skims across a rooftop as OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name> is forced to lift his legs, tenaciously hanging onto the DROID. The DROID heads for a dirty, beat-up speeder hidden in an alcove of a building about twenty stories up. When the pilot of the speeder, a scruffy bounty hunter called <name type="ORG">ZAM</name> WESELL, sees the DROID approach with OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name> hanging on, she pulls a long rifle out of the speeder and starts to fire at the <name type="FAC">JEDI</name>. <name type="ORG">EXPLOSION</name>S burst all around OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name>.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name>
         </speaker>
			I have a bad feeling about this.</sp>
      <sd>FINALLY, the DROID suffers a direct hit and blows up. OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name> falls fifty stories, until a speeder drops down next to him, and he manages to grab onto the back end of the speeder and haul himself toward the cockpit. The <name type="FAC">JEDI</name> struggles to climb into the passenger seat of the open speeder and sit down next to the driver, <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name>.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name>
         </speaker>
			That was wacky! I almost lost you
			in the traffic.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name>
         </speaker>
			What took you so long?</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name>
         </speaker>
			Oh, you know, Master, I couldn't
			find a speeder I really liked,
			with an open cockpit... and with
			the right speed capabilities...
			and then you know I had to get a
			really gonzo color...</sp>
      <sd>They zoom upward in hot pursuit of <name type="ORG">ZAM</name> asshe fires out the open window at them with her laser pistol.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name>
         </speaker>
			If you'd spend as much time
			working on your saber skills as
			you do on your wit, young Padawan,
			you would rival Master <name type="PERSON">Yoda</name> as a
			swordsman.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name>
         </speaker>
			I thought I already did.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name>
         </speaker>
			Only in your mind, my very young
			apprentice. Careful!! Hey, easy!!</sp>
      <sd>As this conversation is going on, <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name> deftly moves in and out of the oncoming traffic, across lanes, between buildings, and miraculously through a construction site. <name type="ORG">ZAM</name> WESELL continues firing at them.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name>
         </speaker>
			Sorry, I forgot you don't like
			flying, Master.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name>
         </speaker>
			I don't mind flying... but
			what you're doing is suicide!</sp>
      <sd>They barely miss a commuter train</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name>
         </speaker>
			Master, you know I've been flying
			since before I could walk. I'm very
			good at this.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name>
         </speaker>
			Just slow down!</sp>
      <sd>
         <name type="ORG">ZAM</name>
         <name type="ORG">WESSEL</name> and the <name type="FAC">JEDI</name> race through a line of cross-traffic made up of giant trucks. The speeders bank sideways as they slide around right-angle turns between buildings. <name type="ORG">ZAM</name> races into a tram tunnel.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name>
         </speaker>
				(continuing)
			Wait! Don't go in there!</sp>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name> zooms into the tunnel after <name type="ORG">ZAM</name>. They see a tram coming at them. They brake, turn around, and race out, barely ahead of the charging commuter transport.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name>
         </speaker>
				(continuing)
			You know I don't like it when you
			do that!</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name>
         </speaker>
			Sorry, Master. Don't worry, this
			guy's gonna kill himself any
			minute now!</sp>
      <sd>
         <name type="ORG">ZAM</name>
         <name type="ORG">WESSEL</name> turns into oncoming traffic, deliberately trying to throw the <name type="FAC">JEDI</name> off. Oncoming speeders swerve, trying to avoid <name type="ORG">ZAM</name> and the <name type="FAC">JEDI</name>. <name type="ORG">ZAM</name> does a quick, tight loop-over and ends up behind the <name type="FAC">JEDI</name>. She is now in a much better position to fire at them with her laser pistol. To avoid being hit by the laser bolts, <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name> slams on the brakes and moves alongside <name type="ORG">ZAM</name>. She now fires point-blank at OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name>.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name>
         </speaker>
			What are you doing? He's gonna
			blast me!</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name>
         </speaker>
			Right - this isn't working.</sp>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name> slides underneath <name type="PERSON">Zam</name>'s speeder. They race along in traffic, one speeder right on top of the other. The BOUNTY HUNTER skims over the rooftops, causing <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name> to drop behind. <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name> goes through his gears, zooming around traffic. They race at high speed across a wide, flat surface of the city planet. A large spacecraft almost collides with them as it attempts to land. They round a corner and clip a flag, which gets caught on one of the front air scoops.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name>
         </speaker>
			That was too close!</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name>
         </speaker>
			Clear that!</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name>
         </speaker>
			What??</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name>
         </speaker>
			Clear the flag! We're losing
			power! Hurry!</sp>
      <sd>OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name> leans out of the speeder, then crawls out onto the front engine, pulling the flag free of the scoop. The speeder lurches forward with a surge of power.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name>
         </speaker>
			Whooooaaa! Don't do that! I
			don't  like it when you do that!</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name>
         </speaker>
			So sorry, Master.</sp>
      <sd>They chase the BOUNTY HUNTER through a power refinery.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name>
         </speaker>
			It's dangerous near those power
			couplings! Slow down! Don't go
			through there!</sp>
      <sd>Huge electrical bolts shoot between the buildings as the speeders pass.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name>
         </speaker>
				(continuing)
			Yiiii, what are you doing?</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name>
         </speaker>
			Sorry, Master!</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name>
         </speaker>
				(sarcastically)
			Oh, that was good...</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name>
         </speaker>
			That was crazy!!!</sp>
      <sd>
         <name type="ORG">ZAM</name> slides around a corner sideways, blocking an alley, firing point-blank as <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name> approaches.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name>
         </speaker>
				(continuing)
			Ahh, damn.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name>
         </speaker>
			Stop!!</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name>
         </speaker>
			No, we can make it.</sp>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name> barely misses the BOUNTY HUNTER'S speeder as he dives under it, and through a small gap in the building hitting several pipes and going wildly out of control. <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name> struggles to regain control of the speeder, narrowly missing a crane, barely clipping a pair of giant struts. A giant <name type="ORG">gasball</name> shoots up, causing <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name> to spin and bump a building, stalling the speeder.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name>
         </speaker>
			I'm crazy... I'm crazy... I'm
			crazy.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name>
         </speaker>
			But it worked... we made it.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name>
         </speaker>
				(angrily)
			It didn't work... we've stalled!
			And you almost got us killed!</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name>
         </speaker>
			I think we're still alive.</sp>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name> works to get the speeder started. It quickly races to life.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name>
         </speaker>
				(very angrily)
			It was stupid!</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name>
         </speaker>
				(sheepishly)
			I could have made it...</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name>
         </speaker>
				(furious)
			But you didn't!!! And now we've
			lost him.</sp>
      <sd>Suddenly, there is an ambush. Laser bolts fire everywhere. <name type="ORG">EXPLOSION</name>S surround them. They look up to see <name type="ORG">ZAM</name>
         <name type="ORG">WESSEL</name> take off.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name>
         </speaker>
			No we didn�t...</sp>
      <sd>Out of a cloud of smoke and ball of flames the <name type="FAC">JEDI</name> tear after <name type="ORG">ZAM</name>. They are smoking. OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name> slaps out the small fire on the dashboard. <name type="ORG">ZAM</name> goes up and down, through cross-traffic. There is a near miss as a speeder almost hits them. <name type="ORG">ZAM</name> turns down and left between two buildings. <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name> pulls up and to the right</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name>
         </speaker>
			Where are you going?! He went
			down there, the other way.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name>
         </speaker>
			This is a shortcut... I think.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name>
         </speaker>
			What do you mean, �You think?�
			What kind of shortcut?! He went
			completely the other way! You�ve
			lost him!</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name>
         </speaker>
			Master, if we keep this chase
			going, that creep�s gonna end up
			deep fried. Personally, I�d very
			much like to find out who in the
			hell he is and who he�s working
			for...</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name>
         </speaker>
				(sarcastic)
			Oh, so that�s why we�re going in
			the wrong direction.</sp>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name> turns up a side street, zooming up several small passageways, then stops, hovering about fifty stories up.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name>
         </speaker>
				(continuing)
			Well, you lost him.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name>
         </speaker>
			I�m deeply sorry, Master.</sp>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name> looks around front and back. He spots something. He seems to 
start counting to himself as he watches something below approach.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name>
         </speaker>
				(continuing)
			Excuse me for a moment.</sp>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name> jumps out of the speeder. OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name> looks down and sees <name type="PERSON">Zam</name>�s speeder about five stories below them cruising past. <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name> miraculously lands on top of <name type="PERSON">the Bounty Hunter</name>�s speeder. The speeder wobbles under the impact. <name type="ORG">ZAM</name> looks up and realises what has happened.</sd>
      <sd>
         <name type="ORG">ZAM</name> takes off, and <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name> slides to the back strut and almost slips off, but manages to hang on. <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name> works his way back to the speeder�s cockpit, just as <name type="ORG">ZAM</name> stops suddenly, and <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name> flies forward to the left front fork. <name type="ORG">ZAM</name> shoots at him with a laser pistol. There is a BLAST near <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name>'S hand, which breaks off a piece of the speeder. <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name> slides to the right fork of the speeder, where <name type="ORG">ZAM</name> can�t reach him. He scrambles to the top, holding onto an air scoop.</sd>
      <sd>OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name> has jumped into the driver�s seat of his speeder and is deftly gaining on the rogue speeder. The two speeders dive through oncoming traffic and then through cross traffic. Finally, <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name> is able to get hold of his lightsaber and starts to cut his way through the roof of the speeder. <name type="ORG">ZAM</name> takes out her laser pistol and starts firing at the helpless <name type="FAC">JEDI</name>, knocking the sword out of his hand. OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name> races under the speeder and catches <name type="FAC">the Jedi</name> weapon in the passenger�s seat.</sd>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name> sticks his hand into the cockpit and, using the <name type="ORG">Force</name>, pulls the gun out of <name type="ORG">ZAM</name>�S hand. She grabs <name type="FAC">the Jedi</name>�s hand, and they struggle for the weapon. It goes off, blowing a hole in the floor of the speeder. The speeder careens wildly out of control. <name type="ORG">ZAM</name> struggles to pull the speeder out of it�s nose dive. OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name> gets slowed down by traffic and loses sight of <name type="PERSON">the Bounty Hunter</name>�s speeder.</sd>
      <sd>Just as the dragster is about to nose dive into the ground, <name type="ORG">ZAM</name> pulls it out, and it slides hard on the pavement in a shower of sparks. <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name> goes flying into the street.</sd>
      <setting>EXT. ENTERTAINMENT STREET - NIGHT</setting>
      <sd>
         <name type="ORG">ZAM</name> exits the crashed speeder and runs. <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name> picks himself up off the pavement and runs down the very crowded street.</sd>
      <sd>It's the seedy underbelly of the city. Broken sidewalks, garish lights reflected on the filthy puddles. It's pretty crowded with various ALIEN LOW-LIFES, <name type="ORG">PAN</name>HANDLING <name type="ORG">DROIDS</name>, and the occasional group of UPPERCLASS SLUMMERS.</sd>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name> barges into several of them as he chases after the fleeing <name type="ORG">ZAM</name>. He loses <name type="PERSON">the Bounty Hunter</name> in the crowd, them sees him again. The young Jedi is having a very difficult time getting through the crowd.</sd>
      <sd>Ahead, <name type="ORG">ZAM</name> turns in through a door and disappears.</sd>
      <sd>A nightclub sighs is flashing over the door. <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name> is just about to follow <name type="ORG">ZAM</name> when there is a sudden swirl of litter from downthrusters. <name type="PERSON">PEOPLE</name> start moving out of the way, and the open speeder lands in the street beside him. OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name> gets out and walks over, holding out <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name>'S lightsaber.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name>
         </speaker>
         <name type="PERSON">Anakin</name>!</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name>
         </speaker>
			She went into that club, Master.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name>
         </speaker>
			Patience.</sp>
      <sd>OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name> hands <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name> the lightsaber.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name>
         </speaker>
			 	(continuing)
			Here. Next time try not to lose it.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name>
         </speaker>
			Sorry, Master.</sp>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name> reaches for the lightsaber, but OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name> holds it back.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name>
         </speaker>
			A Jedi's saber is his most
			precious possession.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name>
         </speaker>
			Yes, Master.</sp>
      <sd>He reaches for the lightsaber, OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name> pulls it back.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name>
         </speaker>
			He must keep it with him at all
			times.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name>
         </speaker>
			I know, Master.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name>
         </speaker>
			This weapon is your life!</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name>
         </speaker>
			I've heard this lesson before...</sp>
      <sd>OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name> finally holds out the lightsaber and <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name> grabs it.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name>
         </speaker>
			But, you haven't learned anything,
			<name type="PERSON">Anakin</name>.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name>
         </speaker>
			I try, Master.</sp>
      <setting>INT. NIGHTCLUB - NIGHT</setting>
      <sd>OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name> and <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name> enter the nightclub bar, and everyone stares at them</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name>
         </speaker>
			Why do I think you are going to be
			the death of me?!</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name>
         </speaker>
			Don't say that Master... You're
			the closest thing I have to a
			father... I love you. I don't want
			to cause you pain.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name>
         </speaker>
			Then why don't you listen to me?!</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name>
         </speaker>
			I will. I'll do better, I promise.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name>
         </speaker>
			Do you see him him?</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name>
         </speaker>
			I think he's a she...</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name>
         </speaker>
			Then be extra careful...
				(nods to a room)
			Check it out.</sp>
      <sd>OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name> goes away.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name>
         </speaker>
			Where are you going, Master?</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name>
         </speaker>
			To get a drink.</sp>
      <sd>OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name> heads for the bar. <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name> blinks in surprise, then moves into the room, where ALIEN FACES look back at him with hostility, suspicion, and invitation as he moves among the tables. OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name> arrives at the bar. He signals the BARMAN.</sd>
      <sd>CLOSE - Somewhere in the room a HAND moves to a pistol in its holster and unsnaps the safety catch. At the bar, a glass is placed in from of OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name>. A drink is poured. He lifts the glass.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>ELAN SLEAZEBAGGANO</speaker>
			Wanna buy some death sticks?</sp>
      <sd>OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name> looks at him. He moves his fingers slightly.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name>
         </speaker>
			You don't want to sell me death-
			sticks.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>ELAN</speaker>
			I don't want to sell you death-
			sticks.</sp>
      <sd>OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name> moves his fingers.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name>
         </speaker>
			You want to go home and rethink 
			your life.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>ELAN</speaker>
			I want to go home and rethink my
			life.</sp>
      <sd>He leaves. OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name> lifts the drink and tosses it back.</sd>
      <sd>CLOSE. The gun is drawn from its holster and held down out of sight. The BOUNTY HUNTER starts to move toward the bar.</sd>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name> checks out ALIEN FACES. OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name> signals for another drink. The gun moves toward his unsuspecting back.</sd>
      <sd>The drink is poured. OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name> reaches for it. The gun is raised to aim directly at his back, and suddenly OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name> turns fast. His lightsaber flashes. There is a shrill SCREAM and <name type="ORG">ZAM</name>'S ARM hits the floor. The gun drops from its twitching fingers. Blood spreads.</sd>
      <sd>The room is silent. ALIENS rise menacingly from their seats, and <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name> is suddenly at OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name>'s side, his lightsaber glowing.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name>
         </speaker>
			Easy... Official business. Go
			back to your drinks.</sp>
      <sd>Slowly, the ALIENS sit. Conversation resumes. Onstage, THE PERFORMERS pick up their routine. OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name> and <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name> lift <name type="ORG">ZAM</name> and carry her out.</sd>
      <setting>EXT. ALLEY OUTSIDE NIGHTCLUB - NIGHT</setting>
      <sd>OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name> and <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name> carry <name type="ORG">ZAM</name> into the alley and lower her to the ground. OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name> attends to her wounded shoulder. She stares up hatefully at <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name>. She winces in pain, then nods.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name>
         </speaker>
			Do you know who it was you were
			trying to kill?</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="ORG">ZAM</name>
            <name type="ORG">WESSEL</name>
         </speaker>
			The <name type="PERSON">Senator</name> from <name type="LOC">Naboo</name>.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name>
         </speaker>
			Who hired you?</sp>
      <sd>
         <name type="ORG">ZAM</name> glares at OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name>.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="ORG">ZAM</name>
            <name type="ORG">WESSEL</name>
         </speaker>
			It was just a job.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name>
         </speaker>
			Tell us!</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="ORG">ZAM</name>
            <name type="ORG">WESSEL</name>
         </speaker>
			That <name type="PERSON">Senator</name>'s gonna die soon
			anyway, and the next one won't
			make the same mistake I did...</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name>
         </speaker>
			This wound's going to need
			treatment.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name>
         </speaker>
			Who hired you? Tell us... tell us
			now!</sp>
      <sd>
         <name type="ORG">ZAM</name> glares hatefully.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="ORG">ZAM</name>
         </speaker>
			It was a Bounty Hunter called...</sp>
      <sd>There is a sudden FTZZZ sound. <name type="ORG">ZAM</name> twitches. She blinks in surprise and dies.</sd>
      <sd>There is a WEOOSH from above. OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name> and <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name> look up yo see an ARMOURED ROCKET-MAN taking off from a roof high above. OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name> looks down at <name type="ORG">ZAM</name>. He touches her neck and pulls out a small, wicked-looking dart.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name>
         </speaker>
			Toxic Dart...</sp>
      <setting>INT. SENATE BUILDING, PADME'S APARTMENT - DAY</setting>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name> and <name type="ORG">JAR</name>
         <name type="ORG">JAR</name> stand near the door of the anteroom to PADME'S 
bedroom. PADME and DORME move about packing luggage.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>PADME</speaker>
			Representative Binks. I know I can
			count on you.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="ORG">JAR</name>
            <name type="ORG">JAR</name>
         </speaker>
			Yousa betchen <name type="ORG">mesa</name> bottums.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>PADME</speaker>
			What?!</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="ORG">JAR</name>
            <name type="ORG">JAR</name>
         </speaker>
				(coughs, recovers)
			Oh, pardone-ay, <name type="PERSON">Senator</name>. I mean,
			I am honoured to accept this heavy
			burden. I take on this
			responsibility with deep humility
			tinged with an overwhelming pride.
				(pompously)
			It is not every day that I am
			called upon to...</sp>
      <sd>PADME kisses him on the cheek and gives him a hug. <name type="ORG">JAR</name>
         <name type="ORG">JAR</name> turns red.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>PADME</speaker>
			You're a good friend, <name type="PERSON">Jar Jar</name>. I
			don't wish to hold you up. I'm
			sure you have a great deal to do.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="ORG">JAR</name>
            <name type="ORG">JAR</name>
         </speaker>
			Of course, M'lady.</sp>
      <sd>
         <name type="ORG">JAR</name>
         <name type="ORG">JAR</name> bows and goes out. As he passes <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name>, he flashes a dazzling smile... PADME is in a very bad mood.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>PADME</speaker>
			I do not like this idea of hiding.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name>
         </speaker>
			Don't worry. Now that the <name type="ORG">Council</name>
			has ordered an investigation, it
			won't take Master Obi-Wan long to
			find that bounty hunter.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>PADME</speaker>
				(frustrated)
			I haven't worked for a year to
			defeat the "Military Creation Act"
			not to be here when its fate is
			decided.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name>
         </speaker>
			Sometimes we have to let go of our
			pride and do what is requested of
			us.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>PADME</speaker>
			Pride?!? Annie, you're young, and
			you don't have a very firm grip on
			politics. I suggest you reserve
			your opinions for some other time.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name>
         </speaker>
			Sorry, M'lady. I was only trying
			to...</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>PADME</speaker>
			Annie! No!</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name>
         </speaker>
			Please don't call me that.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>PADME</speaker>
			What?</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name>
         </speaker>
			Annie...</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>PADME</speaker>
			I've always called you that... it
			is your name, isn't it?</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name>
         </speaker>
			It's <name type="PERSON">Anakin</name>. When you say Annie
			it's like I'm still a little
			boy... and I'm not.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>PADME</speaker>
			I'm sorry, <name type="PERSON">Anakin</name>. It's impossible
			to deny you've...
				(looks him over)
			...that you've grown up.</sp>
      <sd>PADME smiles at <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name>. He becomes a little shy.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name>
         </speaker>
			Master Obi-Wan manages not to see
			it...</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>PADME</speaker>
			Mentors have a way of seeing more
			of our faults than we would like.
			It's the only way we grow.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name>
         </speaker>
			Don't get me wrong... Obi-Wan is
			a great mentor. As wise as Master
			<name type="PERSON">Yoda</name> and as powerful as Master
			Windu. I am truly thankful to be
			his apprentice. Only... although
			I'm a Padawan learner, in some
			ways... a lot of ways... I'm ahead
			of him. I'm ready for the trials.
			I know I am! He knows it too. He
			believes I'm too unpredictable...
			Other Jedi my age have gone
			through the trials and made it...
			I know I started my training
			late... but he won't let me move
			on.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>PADME</speaker>
			That must be frustrating.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name>
         </speaker>
			It's worse... he's overly
			critical. He never listens! He
			just doesn't understand! It's not
			fair!</sp>
      <sd>PADME cannot surpress a laugh. She shakes her head.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>PADME</speaker>
			I'm sorry... You sounded exactly
			like that little boy I once knew,
			when he didn't get his way.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name>
         </speaker>
			I'm not whining! I'm not.</sp>
      <sd>PADME just smiles at him. DORME laughs in the background.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>PADME</speaker>
			I didn't say it to hurt you.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name>
         </speaker>
			I know...</sp>
      <sd>There is a brief silence. PADME comes over to <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name>.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>PADME</speaker>
         <name type="PERSON">Anakin</name>...</sp>
      <sd>They look into each other's eyes for the first time.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>PADME</speaker>
				(continuing)
			Don't try to grow up too fast.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name>
         </speaker>
			I am grown up. You said it
			yourself.</sp>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name> looks deep into PADME'S eyes.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>PADME</speaker>
			Please don't look at me like that.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name>
         </speaker>
			Why not?</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>PADME</speaker>
			Because I can see what you're
			thinking.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name>
         </speaker>
				(laughing)
			Ahh... so, you have Jedi powers
			too?</sp>
      <sd>DORME is watching with concern.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>PADME</speaker>
			It makes me feel uncomfortable.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name>
         </speaker>
			Sorry, M'lady.</sp>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name> backs away as PADME turns and goes back to her packing.</sd>
      <setting>EXT. CORUSCANT, <name type="LOC">SPACE</name>PORT FREIGHTER DOCKS, TRANSPORT BUS - DAY </setting>
      <sd>A small bus speeds toward the massive freighter docks of <name type="LOC">Coruscant</name>'s In<name type="GPE">dus</name>trial area. The spaceport is bustling with activity. Transports of various sizes moves supplies and passengers as giant floating cranes lift cargo out of starships. The bus stops before a huge intergalactic freighter starship. It parks in the shadows of an overhang.</sd>
      <setting>INT. CORUSCANT, <name type="LOC">SPACE</name>PORT FREIGHTER DOCKS, TRANSPORT BUS - DAY</setting>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name> and PADME, dressed in <name type="GPE">Outland</name> peasant outfits, get up and head for the door where CAPTAIN <name type="ORG">TYPHO</name>, DORME and OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name> are waiting to hand them their luggage. DORME is dressed to look like <name type="PERSON">Senator</name>
         <name type="PERSON">Amidala</name>.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>CAPTAIN <name type="ORG">TYPHO</name>
         </speaker>
			Be safe, m'lady.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>PADME</speaker>
			Thank you, Captain. Take good
			care of Dorme... the threat's on
			you two now.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>DORME</speaker>
			He'll be safe with me.</sp>
      <sd>They laugh, and PADME embraces her faithful handmaiden. DORME start to weep.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>PADME</speaker>
			You'll be fine.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>DORME</speaker>
			It's not me, M'Lady. I worry
			about you. What if they realise
			I'm not you?</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>PADME</speaker>
				(looks to <name type="PERSON">Anakin</name>)
			Then my Jedi protector will have
			to prove how grown up he is.</sp>
      <sd>DORME and PADME smile. <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name> frowns as OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name> pulls him aside.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name>
         </speaker>
         <name type="PERSON">Anakin</name>, you stay put on <name type="LOC">Naboo</name>.
			Do not attract any attention. Do
			absolutely nothing without
			checking in with me or the <name type="ORG">Council</name>.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name>
         </speaker>
			Yes, Master.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name>
         </speaker>
				(to <name type="PERSON">Padme</name>)
			I will get to the bottom of this
			plot quickly, M'Lady. You'll be
			back here in no time.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>PADME</speaker>
			I will be most grateful for your
			speed, Master Jedi.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name>
         </speaker>
			Time to go.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>PADME</speaker>
			I know. </sp>
      <sd>PADME gives DORME a last hug. <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name> picks up the luggage, and the TWO PEASANTS exit the speeder bus, where <name type="PERSON">ARTOO</name> is waiting for them.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name>
         </speaker>
			May the <name type="ORG">Force</name> be with you.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name>
         </speaker>
			May the <name type="ORG">Force</name> be with you, Master.</sp>
      <sd>They head off toward the giant <name type="ORG">Starfreighter</name>.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>PADME</speaker>
			Suddenly, I'm afraid...</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name>
         </speaker>
			I'm kinda scared too. This is my
			first assignment on my own.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>PADME</speaker>
			There's nothing to worry about...
			we have <name type="PERSON">Artoo</name> with us.</sp>
      <sd>The two laugh.</sd>
      <sd>OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name> and CAPTAIN <name type="ORG">TYPHO</name> watch <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name> and PADME disappear into the 
vastness of the spaceport with <name type="PERSON">ARTOO</name> trundling along behind them.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name>
         </speaker>
			I hope he doesn't try anything
			foolish.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>CAPTAIN <name type="ORG">TYPHO</name>
         </speaker>
			I'd be more concerned about her
			doing something, than him.</sp>
      <setting>EXT. FREIGHTER DOCKS - CORUSCANT - DAY</setting>
      <sd>The freighter slowly takes off from the huge docks area of <name type="LOC">Coruscant</name>. It soon moves into the crowded skies.</sd>
      <setting>INT. <name type="FAC">JEDI</name> TEMPLE, MAIN HALLWAY - LATE DAY</setting>
      <sd>From high above, light streams down from the lofty ceilings. OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name> crosses the floor of the great hallway, heaading for the Analysis Rooms.</sd>
      <setting>INT. <name type="FAC">JEDI</name> TEMPLE, ANALYSIS CUBICLES - LATE DAY</setting>
      <sd>OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name> walks past several glass cubicles where work is going on. He comes to an empty one and sits down in front of a console. A PK-4 ANALYSIS DROID comes to life. A tray slides out of the console.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>PK-4</speaker>
			Place the subject for analysis on
			the sensot tray, please.</sp>
      <sd>OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name> puts the dart onto the <name type="ORG">traym</name> which retracts into the console. The DROID activates the system, and a screen lights up in from of OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name>.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name>
         </speaker>
			It's a toxic dart. I need to know
			where it came from and who made it.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>PK-4</speaker>
			One moment, please.</sp>
      <sd>Diagrams and .... appear on the screem, scrolling past at great speed. OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name> watches as the screen goes blank. They tray slides out.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>PK-4</speaker>
				(continuing)
			As you can see on your screen,
			subject weapon does not exist in
			any known culture. Markings
			cannot be identified. Probablt
			self-made by a warrior not
			associated with any known society.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name>
         </speaker>
			Excuse me? Could you try again
			please?</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>PK-4</speaker>
			Master Jedi, our records are very
			thorough. they cover eight
			percent of the galaxy. If I can't
			tell you where it came from,
			nobody can.</sp>
      <sd>OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name> picks up the dart and looks at it, then looks to the DROID.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name>
         </speaker>
			Thanks for your assistance! You
			may not be able to figure this
			out, but I think I know someone
			who might.</sp>
      <setting>EXT. <name type="LOC">SPACE</name>, STARSHIP FREIGHTER</setting>
      <sd>The massive, slow-moving Freighter suddenly zooms away into lightspeed.</sd>
      <setting>INT. STARFREIGHTER, STORAGE HOLD - DAY</setting>
      <sd>The great, gloomy hold is crowded with EMIGRANTS and their belongings. To one side <name type="PERSON">ARTOO</name> is coming to the head of a food line, where SERVERS are ladling out bowls of mush. <name type="PERSON">ARTOO</name> holds two bowls.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>SERVER</speaker>
			Keep moving! Keep moving!</sp>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">ARTOO</name> slips tube into a tub of mush and sucks up a large quantity. With one of his little claw-arms, he grabs several chunks of something that looks like brown bread. A SERVER sees him.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>FOOD SERVER</speaker>
				(continuing)
			Hey! No <name type="ORG">Droid</name>s!</sp>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">ARTOO</name> takes one last big suck and heads away from the food line. The SERVER shouts after him angrily. The little droid moves past groups of eating or sleeping EMIGRANTS and comes to where <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name> is sound asleep. The young Jedi seems to be having a nightmare. He is very restless.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name>
         </speaker>
			No, no, Mom, no...</sp>
      <sd>He is sweating. PADME leans over to wipe some of the sweat from his forehead. He wakes up with a start, then realises where he is. PADME simply looks at him. He stares back, somewhat confused. <name type="PERSON">ARTOO</name> fills up two bowls with mush.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name>
         </speaker>
				(continuing)
			What?</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>PADME</speaker>
			You seemed to be having a
			nightmare.</sp>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name> looks at PADME a little more closely, trying to see if he has revealed any of his secrets. She hands him a bowl of mush and bread.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>PADME</speaker>
				(continuing)
			Are you hungry?</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name>
         </speaker>
			Thank you.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>PADME</speaker>
			We went into lightspeed a while
			ago.</sp>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name> looks into PADME'S eyes.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name>
         </speaker>
			I look forward to seeing <name type="LOC">Naboo</name>
			again. I've thought about it every
			day since I left. It's by far the
			most beautiful place I've ever
			seen...</sp>
      <sd>PADME is a little unnerved by his intense stare. </sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>PADME</speaker>
			You were just a little boy then.
			It may not be as you remember it;
			time changes your perception.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name>
         </speaker>
			I think time has given me much
			more mature feelings to enhance my
			perception.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>PADME</speaker>
			It must be difficult having sworn
			your life to <name type="FAC">the Jedi</name>... not being
			able to visit the places you
			like... or do the things you
			like...</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name>
         </speaker>
			Or be with the people I love.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>PADME</speaker>
			Are you allowed to love? I
			thought that was forbidden for a
			Jedi.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name>
         </speaker>
			Attachment is forbidden.
			Possession is forbidden.
			Compassion, which I would define
			as unconditional love, is central
			to a Jedi's life, so you might say
			we're encouraged to love.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>PADME</speaker>
			You have changed so much</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name>
         </speaker>
			You haven't changed a bit. You're
			exactly the way I remember you in
			my dreams. I doubt if <name type="LOC">Naboo</name> has
			changed much either.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>PADME</speaker>
			It hasn't...</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name>
         </speaker>
			I can't wait to breathe the sweet
			breeze that comes off the rolling
			hills. Whenever I try to
			visualise the <name type="ORG">Force</name>, those hills
			are what I see.</sp>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name> looks at PADME when he says this.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name>
         </speaker>
				(continuing)
			I love <name type="LOC">Naboo</name>.</sp>
      <sd>There is an awkward moment.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>PADME</speaker>
				(changing the subject)
			Were you dreaming about you
			mother earlier, weren't you?</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name>
         </speaker>
			Yes... I left <name type="LOC">Tatooine</name> so long
			ago, my memory of her is fading.
			I don't want to lose it. Recently
			I've been seeing her in my
			dreams... vivid dreams... scary
			dreams. I worry about her.</sp>
      <sd>PADME gives <name type="PERSON">ANAKIN</name> a sympathetic look.</sd>
      <setting>EXT. CORUSCANT, DOWNTOWN, BACK STREET - M<name type="PERSON">ORN</name>ING</setting>
      <sd>OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name> walks down the street. It is a pretty tough part of town. Old buildings, warehouses, beat up speeders and transporter rigs occasional "shiny freighters" hissing through.</sd>
      <sd>OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name> comes to a kind of alien diner. On the steamed-up windowa it says "DEX'S <name type="LOC">DINER</name>" in alien lettering. He goes inside.</sd>
      <setting>INT. CORUSCANT, DEX'S <name type="LOC">DINER</name> - M<name type="PERSON">ORN</name>ING</setting>
      <sd>A young waitress, <name type="PERSON">HERMIONE</name> BAGWA, is wiping off a booth tabletop. There is a counter with stools and a line of booths along the wall by the window. A number of CUSTOMERS are eating - TOUGH-LOO<name type="GPE">KI</name>NG WORKERS, FREIGHTER DRIVERS etc. <name type="PERSON">HERMIONE</name> looks up as OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name> comes in.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">HERMIONE</name>
         </speaker>
			Can I help ya?</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name>
         </speaker>
			I'm looking for Dexter.</sp>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">HERMIONE</name>'S eyes narrow.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">HERMIONE</name> BAGWA</speaker>
			Waddya want him for?</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name>
         </speaker>
			He's not in trouble. It's
			personal.</sp>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">HERMIONE</name> stares at OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name>. There is a brief pause. Then she goes to the open serving hatch behind the counter.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">HERMIONE</name> BAGWA</speaker>
			Someone to see ya, honey
				(lowering her voice)
			A Jedi, by the looks of him.</sp>
      <sd>Steam billows out from the kitchen hatch behind the counter as a huge head pokes through.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="ORG">DEXTER</name> JETTSTER</speaker>
      </sp>

			Obi-Wan!

<sp>
         <speaker>OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name>
         </speaker>
			Hey, Dex.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="ORG">DEXTER</name> JETTSTER</speaker>
      </sp>

			Take a seat! Be right with ya!

<sd>OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name> sits in a booth.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="PERSON">HERMIONE</name> BAGWA</speaker>
			You want a cup of ardees?</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name>
         </speaker>
			Thank you.</sp>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">HERMIONE</name> moves off as the door to the counter opens and <name type="ORG">DEXTER</name> JETTSTER appears. He is big - bald and sweaty, old and alien. Not someone to tangle with. He arrives, beaming hugely.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="ORG">DEXTER</name> JETTSTER</speaker>
      </sp>

			Hey, ol' buddy!

<sp>
         <speaker>OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name>
         </speaker>
			Hey, Dex.</sp>
      <sd>
         <name type="ORG">DEXTER</name> eases himself into the seat opposite OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name>. He can just make it. <name type="PERSON">HERMIONE</name> sets two mugs of <name type="PERSON">steaming ardees</name> in from of them.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="ORG">DEXTER</name> JETTSTER</speaker>
      </sp>

			So, my friend. What can I do for
			ya?

<sp>
         <speaker>OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name>
         </speaker>
			You can tell me what this is.</sp>
      <sd>OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name> places the dart on the table between them. DEX'S eyes widen. He puts down his mug.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="ORG">DEXTER</name> JETTSTER</speaker>
      </sp>

			Well, whattaya know...

<sd>
         <name type="ORG">DEXTER</name> picks up the dart delicately between his puffy fingers and peers at it.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="ORG">DEXTER</name> JETTSTER</speaker>
      </sp>

				(continuing)
			I ain't seen one of these since I
			was prospecting on Subterrel
			beyond the Outer Rim!

<sp>
         <speaker>OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name>
         </speaker>
			Do you know where it came from?</sp>
      <sd>
         <name type="ORG">DEXTER</name> grins. He puts the dart down between them.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="ORG">DEXTER</name> JETTSTER</speaker>
      </sp>

			This baby belongs to them cloners.
			What you got here is a <name type="LOC">Kamino</name>
			Kyberdart.

<sp>
         <speaker>OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name>
         </speaker>
         <name type="LOC">Kamino</name> Kyberdart... I wonder why
			it didn't show up in any analysis
			archive.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="ORG">DEXTER</name> JETTSTER</speaker>
      </sp>

			It's these funny little cuts on
			the side give it away...
			Those analysis <name type="ORG">droids</name> you've got
			over there only focus on symbols,
			you know. I should think you Jedi
			would have more respect for the
			difference between knowledge and
			wisdom.

<sp>
         <speaker>OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name>
         </speaker>
			Well, Dex, if <name type="ORG">droids</name> could think, we
			wouldn't be here, would we?
				(laughing)
			<name type="LOC">Kamino</name>... doesn't sound familiar.
			Is it part of the Republic?</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="ORG">DEXTER</name> JETTSTER</speaker>
      </sp>

			No, it's beyond the Outer Rim.
			I'd say about twelve parsecs
			outside the Rishi Maze, toward the
			south. It should be easy to find,
			even for those <name type="ORG">droids</name> in your
			archive to find. Those <name type="LOC">Kamino</name>ans
			keep to themselves. They're
			cloners. Damned good ones, too.

<sd>OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name> then picks up the dart, holding it midway between them.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name>
         </speaker>
			Cloners? Are they friendly?</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="ORG">DEXTER</name> JETTSTER</speaker>
      </sp>

			It depends.

<sp>
         <speaker>OBI-<name type="ORG">WAN</name>
         </speaker>
			On what, Dex?</sp>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">Dexter grins</name>. </sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="ORG">DEXTER</name> JETTSTER</speaker>
      </sp>

			On how good your manners are...
			and how big your pocketbook is...
