<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="sw_schema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<root>
   <title>Star Wars: Episode V - The <name type="ORG">Empire</name> Strikes Back (1980)</title>
by <writer>Lawrence Kasdan &amp; Leigh Brackett</writer>
   <script>
      <subTitle epNum="5">EPISODE 5 THE EMPIRE S<name type="ORG">TRI</name>KES BACK</subTitle>
      <crawl>It is a dark time for the Rebellion. Although the <name type="ORG">Death Star</name> has been destroyed, <name type="ORG">Imperial</name> troops have driven the Rebel forces from their hidden base and pursued them across the galaxy.Evading the dreaded <name type="ORG">Imperial</name> Starfleet, a group of freedom fighters led by <name type="PERSON">Luke</name>
         <name type="PERSON">Skywalker</name> have established a new secret base on the remote ice world of <name type="GPE">Hoth</name>.The evil lord Darth <name type="PERSON">Vader</name>, obsessed with finding young <name type="PERSON">Skywalker</name>, has dispatched thousands of remote probes into the far reaches of space....</crawl>
      <setting>EXT. GALAXY - PLANET HOTH</setting>
      <sd>A Star <name type="ORG">Destroyer</name> moves through space, releasing <name type="ORG">Imperial</name> probe robots 
from its underside.  </sd>
      <sd>One of these probes zooms toward the planet <name type="GPE">Hoth</name> and lands on its ice-
covered surface.  An explosion marks the point of
impact.  </sd>
      <setting>EXT. HOTH - METEORITE CRATER - SNOW PLAIN - DAY</setting>
      <sd>A weird mechanical sound rises above the whining of the wind.  A 
strange probe robot, with several extended sensors, emerges from the 
smoke-shrouded crater.  The ominous mechanical probe floats across the 
snow plain and disappears into the distance.</sd>
      <setting>EXT. PLAIN OF HOTH - DAY</setting>
      <sd>A small figure gallops across the windswept ice slope.  The bundled 
rider is mounted on a large gray snow lizard, a <name type="PERSON">Taun</name>taun.  Curving 
plumes of snow rise from beneath the speeding paws of the two-legged 
beast.</sd>
      <sd>The rider gallops up a slope and reins his lizard to a stop.  Pulling 
off his protective goggles, <name type="PERSON">Luke</name>
         <name type="PERSON">Skywalker</name> notices something in the 
sky.  He takes a pair of electrobinoculars from his utility belt and 
through them sees smoke rising from where the probe robot has crashed.</sd>
      <sd>The wind whips at <name type="PERSON">Luke</name>'s fur-lined cap and he activates a comlink 
transmitter.  His <name type="PERSON">Taun</name>taun shifts and moans nervously beneath him.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
			(into comlink)
		Echo Three to Echo Seven.  <name type="PERSON">Han</name>, 
		old buddy, do you read me?</sp>
      <sd>After a little static a familiar voice is heard.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>HAN</speaker>
			(over comlink)
		Loud and clear, kid.  What's up?</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
			(into comlink)
		Well, I finished my circle.  I 
		don't pick up any life readings.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>HAN</speaker>
			(over comlink)
		There isn't enough life on this 
		ice cube to fill a space cruiser.  
		The sensors are placed, I'm going 
		back.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
			(into comlink)
		Right.  I'll see you shortly.  
		There's a meteorite that hit the 
		ground near here.  I want to check 
		it out.  It won't take long.</sp>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">Luke</name> clicks off his transmitter and reins back on his nervous lizard.  
He pats the beast on the head to calm it.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
		Hey, steady girl.  What's the 
		matter?  You smell something?</sp>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">Luke</name> takes a small device from his belt and starts to adjust it when 
suddenly a large shadow falls over him from behind.  He hears a 
monstrous howl and turns to see an eleven-foot-tall shape towering over 
him.  It is a <name type="ORG">Wampa</name> Ice Creature, lunging at him ferociously.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
		Aaargh!</sp>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">Luke</name> grabs for his pistol, but is hit flat in the face by a huge white 
claw.  He falls unconscious into the snow and in a moment the terrified 
screams of the <name type="PERSON">Taun</name>taun are cut short by the horrible snap of a neck 
being broken.</sd>
      <sd>
         <name type="ORG">The Wampa Ice Creature</name> grabs <name type="PERSON">Luke</name> by one ankle and drags him away 
across the frozen plain.</sd>
      <setting>EXT. HOTH - REBEL BASE ENTRANCE - DAY</setting>
      <sd>A stalwart figure rides his <name type="PERSON">Taun</name>taun up to the entrance of an enormous 
ice cave.</sd>
      <setting>INT. HOTH - REBEL BASE - MAIN HANGAR DECK</setting>
      <sd>Rebel troopers rush about unloading supplies and otherwise securing 
their new base.  The rider, <name type="PERSON">Han</name>
         <name type="PERSON">Solo</name>, swings off his lizard and pulls 
off his goggles.</sd>
      <sd>He walks into the main hangar deck toward the Millennium <name type="ORG">Falcon</name>, which 
is parked among several fighters.  Mechanics, R2 units, and various 
other <name type="ORG">droids</name> hurry about.  <name type="PERSON">Han</name> stops at the Millennium <name type="ORG">Falcon</name> where his 
<name type="NORP">Wookiee</name> copilot, <name type="PERSON">Chewbacca</name>, is welding on a central lifter.  <name type="PERSON">Chewie</name> 
stops his work and lifts his face shield, growling an irritated 
greeting to his boss.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>HAN</speaker>
         <name type="PERSON">Chewie</name>!</sp>
      <sd>The <name type="NORP">Wookiee</name> grumbles a reply.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>HAN</speaker>
		All right, don't lose your temper.
		I'll come right back and give you 
		a hand.</sp>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">Chewbacca</name> puts his mask back on and returns to his welding as <name type="PERSON">Han</name> 
leaves.</sd>
      <setting>INT. HOTH - REBEL BASE - COMMAND CENTER</setting>
      <sd>A makeshift command center has been set up in a blasted area of thick 
ice.  The low-ceilinged room is a beehive of activity. Controllers, 
troops, and <name type="ORG">droids</name> move about setting up electronic eq<name type="ORG">uip</name>ment and 
monitoring radar signals.</sd>
      <sd>
         <name type="ORG">General Rieekan</name> straightens up from a console at <name type="PERSON">Han</name>'s approach.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>RIEEKAN</speaker>
         <name type="PERSON">Solo</name>?</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>HAN</speaker>
No sign of life out there, General.
The sensors are in place.  You'll 
know if anything comes around.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>RIEEKAN</speaker>
		Commander <name type="PERSON">Skywalker</name> reported in yet?</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>HAN</speaker>
		No.  He's checking out a meteorite 
		that hit near him.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>RIEEKAN</speaker>
			(indicates radar 
			 screen)
		With all the meteor activity in this
		system, it's going to be difficult 
		to spot approaching ships.</sp>
      <sd>Taking a deep breath, <name type="PERSON">Han</name> blurts out what is on his mind.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>HAN</speaker>
		General, I've got to leave.  I 
		can't stay anymore.</sp>
      <sd>Princess <name type="PERSON">Leia</name>, standing at a console nearby, is dressed in a short 
white combat jacket and pants.  Her hair is braided across her head in 
a <name type="NORP">Nordic</name> fashion.  She overhears their  conversation and seems somewhat 
distressed.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>RIEEKAN</speaker>
		I'm sorry to hear that.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>HAN</speaker>
		Well, there's a price on my head.
		If I don't pay off <name type="PERSON">Jabba</name> the <name type="ORG">Hut</name>, 
		I'm a dead man.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>RIEEKAN</speaker>
		A death mark's not an easy thing 
		to live with.  You're a good
		fighter, <name type="PERSON">Solo</name>.  I hate to lose you.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>HAN</speaker>
		Thank you, General.</sp>
      <sd>He turns to <name type="PERSON">Leia</name> as <name type="NORP">Rieekan</name> moves away.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>HAN</speaker>
			(with feeling)
		Well, Your Highness, I guess this 
		is it.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
		That's right.</sp>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">Leia</name> is angry.  <name type="PERSON">Han</name> sees she has no warmth to offer him.  He shakes his 
head and adopts a sarcastic tone.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>HAN</speaker>
			(cooly)
		Well, don't get all mushy on me.
		So long, Princess.</sp>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">Han</name> walks away into the quiet corridor adjoining the command center.  
<name type="PERSON">Leia</name> stews a moment, then hurries after him.</sd>
      <setting>INT. HOTH - REBEL BASE - ICE CORRIDOR</setting>
      <sp>
         <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
         <name type="PERSON">Han</name>!</sp>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">Han</name> stops in the corridor and turns to face <name type="PERSON">Leia</name>.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>HAN</speaker>
		Yes, Your Highnessness?</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
		I thought you decided to stay.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>HAN</speaker>
		Well, the bounty hunter we ran 
		into on Ord Mantell changed my
		mind.  </sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
         <name type="PERSON">Han</name>, we need you!</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>HAN</speaker>
		We?</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
		Yes.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>HAN</speaker>
		Oh, what about you need?</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
			(mystified)
		I need?  I don't know what you're 
		talking about.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>HAN</speaker>
			(shakes his head, 
			 fed up) 
		You probably don't.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
		And what precisely am I supposed 
		to know?</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>HAN</speaker>
		Come on!  You want me to stay 
		because of the way you feel about
		me.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
		Yes.  You're a great help to us.
		You're a natural leader...</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>HAN</speaker>
		No!  That's not it.  Come on.  
		Aahhh - uh huh!  Come on.</sp>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">Leia</name> stares at him, understanding, then laughs.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
You're imagining things.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>HAN</speaker>
		Am I?  Then why are you following 
		me?  Afraid I was going to leave
		without giving you a goodbye kiss?</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
		I'd just as soon kiss a <name type="NORP">Wookiee</name>.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>HAN</speaker>
		I can arrange that.  You could use 
		a good kiss!</sp>
      <sd>Angrily, <name type="PERSON">Han</name> strides down the corridor as <name type="PERSON">Leia</name> stares after him.</sd>
      <setting>INT. HOTH - REBEL BASE - <name type="ORG">ANOTHER</name> ICE CORRIDOR</setting>
      <sd>A familiar stream of beeps and whistles herald the approach of <name type="PERSON">Artoo</name>-
Detoo and See-<name type="PERSON">Threepio</name>, who appear around a corner and move along an 
ice wall toward the main hangar.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="ORG">THREEPIO</name>
         </speaker>
		Don't try to blame me.  I didn't 
		ask you to turn on the thermal 
		heater.  I merely commented that it 
		was freezing in the princess' 
		chamber.  But it's supposed to be 
		freezing.  How are we going to dry 
		out all her clothes?  I really don't 
		know.</sp>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">Artoo</name> beeps a stream of protesting whistles.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="ORG">THREEPIO</name>
         </speaker>
		Oh, switch off.</sp>
      <setting>INT. HOTH - REBEL BASE - MAIN HANGAR DECK</setting>
      <sd>The two robots stop at <name type="PERSON">Han</name>
         <name type="PERSON">Solo</name>'s space freighter.  <name type="PERSON">Han</name> and <name type="PERSON">Chewie</name> are 
struggling with their central lifters.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>HAN</speaker>
			(to <name type="PERSON">Chewie</name>)
		Why do you take this apart now? 
		I'm trying to get us out of here 
		and you pull both of these.</sp>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">Chewie</name> grumbles in irritation.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="ORG">THREEPIO</name>
         </speaker>
		Excuse me, sir.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>HAN</speaker>
			(to <name type="PERSON">Chewie</name>)
		Put them back together right now.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="ORG">THREEPIO</name>
         </speaker>
		Might I have a word with you, 
		please?</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>HAN</speaker>
		What do you want?</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="ORG">THREEPIO</name>
         </speaker>
		Well, it's Princess <name type="PERSON">Leia</name>, sir.
		She's been trying to get you on 
		the communicator.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>HAN</speaker>
		I turned it off.  I don't want to 
		talk to her.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="ORG">THREEPIO</name>
         </speaker>
		Oh.  Well, Princess <name type="PERSON">Leia</name> is wondering 
		about Master <name type="PERSON">Luke</name>.  He hasn't come 
		back yet.  She doesn't know where he 
		is.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>HAN</speaker>
		I don't know where he is.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="ORG">THREEPIO</name>
         </speaker>
		Nobody knows where he is.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>HAN</speaker>
		What do you mean, "nobody knows"?</sp>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">Han</name> glances at the fading light at the entrance of the ice cave as 
night slowly begins to fall on the planet.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="ORG">THREEPIO</name>
         </speaker>
		Well, uh, you see...</sp>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">Han</name> jumps down off the lift, as <name type="PERSON">Threepio</name> follows him.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>HAN</speaker>
		Deck Officer.  Deck Officer!</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="ORG">THREEPIO</name>
         </speaker>
		Excuse me, sir.  Might I inqu...</sp>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">Han</name> abruptly puts his hand over <name type="PERSON">Threepio</name>'s mouth as the deck officer 
approaches.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>DECK OFFICER</speaker>
		Yes, sir?</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>HAN</speaker>
		Do you know where Commander 
		<name type="PERSON">Skywalker</name> is?</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>DECK OFFICER</speaker>
		I haven't seen him.  It's possible 
		he came in through the south entrance.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>HAN</speaker>
		It's possible?  Why don't you go 
		find out?  It's getting dark out there.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>DECK OFFICER</speaker>
		Yes, sir.</sp>
      <sd>The deck officer leaves hurriedly, as <name type="PERSON">Han</name> takes his hand off <name type="PERSON">Threepio</name>'s 
mouth.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="ORG">THREEPIO</name>
         </speaker>
		Excuse me, sir.  Might I inquire 
		what's going on?</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>HAN</speaker>
		Why not?</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="ORG">THREEPIO</name>
         </speaker>
		Impossible man.  Come along, <name type="PERSON">Artoo</name>, 
		let's find Princess <name type="PERSON">Leia</name>.  Between 
		ourselves, I think Master <name type="PERSON">Luke</name> is 
		in considerable danger.</sp>
      <setting>INT. HOTH - REBEL BASE - MAIN ICE TUNNEL</setting>
      <sd>The deck officer and his assistant hurry toward <name type="PERSON">Han</name> as he enters the 
tunnel.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>DECK OFFICER</speaker>
		Sir, Commander <name type="PERSON">Skywalker</name> hasn't 
		come in through the south entrance.
		He might have forgotten to check in.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>HAN</speaker>
		Not likely.  Are the speeders ready?</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>DECK OFFICER</speaker>
		Not yet.  We're having some trouble 
		adapting them to the cold.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>HAN</speaker>
		Then we'll have to go out on 
		<name type="PERSON">Taun</name>tauns.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>DECK OFFICER</speaker>
		Sir, the temperature's dropping too 
		rapidly.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>HAN</speaker>
		That's right.  And my friends out 
		in it.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>ASSISTANT OFFICER</speaker>
		I'll cover sector twelve.  Have 
		com-control set screen alpha.</sp>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">Han</name> pushes through the troops and mounts a <name type="PERSON">Taun</name>taun.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>DECK OFFICER</speaker>
		Your <name type="PERSON">Taun</name>taun'll freeze before you 
		reach the first marker.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>HAN</speaker>
		Then I'll see you in hell!</sp>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">Han</name> maneuvers his mount out of the cave and races into the dark bitter 
night.</sd>
      <setting>EXT. HOTH - ICE GORGE - DUSK</setting>
      <sd>The jagged face of a huge ice wall sits gloomily in the dim twilight of 
a <name type="GPE">Hoth</name> day.  <name type="PERSON">Luke</name> hangs upside down, ankles frozen into icy 
stalactites, his extended arms within a foot of the snow floor.  One 
side of his face is covered in a dried mask of frozen blood.  He opens 
his eyes as a chilling moan of the hideous ice creature echoes off the 
gorge walls.  <name type="PERSON">Luke</name> pulls himself up, grabs hold of his ankles, and 
futilely tries to unfasten the throngs.</sd>
      <sd>Exhausted, he drops back into his hanging position.  As he hangs there, 
he spies his lightsaber lying near a pile of his discarded gear, about 
three feet out of reach.</sd>
      <sd>He focuses on the saber and, as his hand strains toward the weapon, he 
squeezes his eyes tight in concentration.</sd>
      <sd>Just as the ice creature looms over <name type="PERSON">Luke</name>, the lightsaber jumps into 
<name type="PERSON">Luke</name>'s hand.</sd>
      <sd>The young warrior instantly ignites his sword, swinging up, and cuts 
himself loose from the ice.  He flops to the snow in a heap.  The 
startled creature moves back, his giant yellow eyes blinking.  <name type="PERSON">Luke</name> 
scrambles to his feet.  He swings his lightsaber and the beast screams 
in pain.</sd>
      <setting>EXT. HOTH - ENTRANCE TO ICE GORGE - DUSK</setting>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">Luke</name> staggers out of the gorge into the dark and snowy twilight.  Weak 
and exhausted, he stumbles down a snow bank.</sd>
      <setting>EXT. HOTH - SNOW PLAIN - DUSK</setting>
      <sd>A small, lone figure riding a <name type="PERSON">Taun</name>taun races through the hostile 
vastness of snow and cold.  As it runs, the <name type="PERSON">Taun</name>taun's legs kick up 
large clouds of snow and ice into the snowy air.</sd>
      <setting>EXT. HOTH - OUTSIDE ICE				 HANGAR - DUSK</setting>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">Artoo</name> stands in the falling snow, beeping worriedly.  <name type="PERSON">Threepio</name> moves 
stiffly over to him.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="ORG">THREEPIO</name>
         </speaker>
		You must come along now, <name type="PERSON">Artoo</name>.  
		There's really nothing more we can 
		do.  And my joints are freezing up.</sp>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">Artoo</name> beeps, long and low.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="ORG">THREEPIO</name>
         </speaker>
		Don't say thing like that!  Of 
		course we'll see Master <name type="PERSON">Luke</name> again.
		He'll be quite all right, you'll see.
			(to himself)
		Stupid little short-circuit.  He'll 
		be quite all right.</sp>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">Threepio</name> turns to go back inside the main hangar as <name type="PERSON">Artoo</name> mournfully 
keeps his vigil.</sd>
      <setting>EXT. HOTH - SNOW DRIFT - DUSK</setting>
      <sd>The wind is blowing quite strong now.  <name type="PERSON">Luke</name> struggles to stay upright, 
but a blast of freezing snow knocks him over.  He struggles to get up, 
but he can't.  The young warrior from <name type="LOC">Tatooine</name> drags himself a couple 
of feet and then collapses.</sd>
      <setting>INT. REBEL BASE - MAIN HANGAR DECK - ENTRANCE - NIGHT</setting>
      <sd>Princess <name type="PERSON">Leia</name> stands inside the dark entrance to the Rebel base, 
waiting for a sign of the two Rebel heroes.  She shivers in the cold 
wind as, nearby, <name type="PERSON">Chewie</name> sits with his head in his hands.  In the 
background, <name type="PERSON">Artoo</name> and <name type="PERSON">Threepio</name> move through the doors.  </sd>
      <sd>A Rebel lieutenant moves to Major <name type="PERSON">Derlin</name>, an officer keeping watch with 
the princess.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>LIEU<name type="ORG">TEN</name>ANT</speaker>
		Sir, all the patrols are in.
		There's still no contact from 
		<name type="PERSON">Skywalker</name> or <name type="PERSON">Solo</name>.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="ORG">THREEPIO</name>
         </speaker>
		Mistress <name type="PERSON">Leia</name>, <name type="PERSON">Artoo</name> says he's been 
		quite unable to pick up any signals, 
		although he does admit that his own 
		range is far too weak to abandon 
		all hope.</sp>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">Leia</name> nods an acknowledgment, but she is lost in thought.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>DERLIN</speaker>
		Your Highness, there's nothing 
		more we can do tonight.  The shield 
		doors must be closed.</sp>
      <sd>He turns to the lieutenant.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>DERLIN</speaker>
		Close the doors.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>LIEU<name type="ORG">TEN</name>ANT</speaker>
		Yes, sir.</sp>
      <sd>The lieutenant walks away.  <name type="PERSON">Chewie</name> lets out a long, mournful howl, 
somewhat like a coyote.  At the same moment, <name type="PERSON">Artoo</name> begins a complex 
series of efficient beeps.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="ORG">THREEPIO</name>
         </speaker>
         <name type="PERSON">Artoo</name> says the chances of survival 
		are seven hundred seventy-five...
		to one.</sp>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">Leia</name> stands praying to herself as the huge metal doors slam across the 
entrance of the ice cave.  The loud booms echo throughout the huge 
cavern.  <name type="PERSON">Chewie</name> lets out another suffering howl.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="ORG">THREEPIO</name>
         </speaker>
		Actually, <name type="PERSON">Artoo</name> has been known to 
		make mistakes... from time to time.
		Oh, dear, oh, dear.  Don't worry 
		about Master <name type="PERSON">Luke</name>.  I'm sure he'll 
		be all right.  He's quite clever, 
		you know... for a human being.</sp>
      <setting>EXT. HOTH - SNOW DRIFT - DUSK</setting>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">Luke</name> lies face down in the snow, nearly unconscious.  Slowly he looks 
up and sees <name type="PERSON">Ben</name>
         <name type="PERSON">Kenobi</name>, barely visible through the blowing snow.  It is 
hard to tell if <name type="PERSON">Kenobi</name> is real or a hallucination.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>BEN</speaker>
         <name type="PERSON">Luke</name>... <name type="PERSON">Luke</name>.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
			(weakly)
		<name type="PERSON">Ben</name>?</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>BEN</speaker>
		You will go to the <name type="FAC">Dagobah</name> system.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
         <name type="FAC">Dagobah</name> system?</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>BEN</speaker>
		There you will learn from <name type="PERSON">Yoda</name>, 
		<name type="FAC">the Jedi</name> Master who instructed me.</sp>
      <sd>The image of <name type="PERSON">Ben</name> fades, revealing a lone <name type="PERSON">Taun</name>taun rider approaching 
from the windswept horizon.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
			(groaning faintly)
		<name type="PERSON">Ben</name>... <name type="PERSON">Ben</name>.</sp>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">Luke</name> drops into unconsciousness.</sd>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">Han</name> pulls up and leaps off his mount.  He hurries to his snow-covered 
friend, cradling him in his arms.  <name type="PERSON">Han</name>'s <name type="PERSON">Taun</name>taun lets out a low, 
pitiful bellow.  But <name type="PERSON">Han</name>'s concern is with <name type="PERSON">Luke</name>, and he shakes him 
urgently.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>HAN</speaker>
         <name type="PERSON">Luke</name>!  <name type="PERSON">Luke</name>!  Don't do this, <name type="PERSON">Luke</name>.  
		Come on, give me a sign here.</sp>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">Luke</name> doesn't respond.  <name type="PERSON">Han</name> begins frantically rubbing and slapping 
<name type="PERSON">Luke</name>'s unconscious face.  As he starts to lift the youth, <name type="PERSON">Han</name> hears a 
rasping sound behind him.  He turns, just in time to see his <name type="PERSON">Taun</name>taun 
stagger and then fall over into the snow.</sd>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">Han</name> carries <name type="PERSON">Luke</name> to the moaning beast.  Then, with a final groan, the 
<name type="PERSON">Taun</name>taun expires.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>HAN </speaker>
		Not much time.</sp>
      <sd>He pushes <name type="PERSON">Luke</name>'s inert form against the belly of the dead beast.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
			(moaning)
		<name type="PERSON">Ben</name>... <name type="PERSON">Ben</name>...</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>HAN</speaker>
         <name type="PERSON">Han</name>g on, kid.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
         <name type="FAC">Dagobah</name> system...</sp>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">Han</name> ignites <name type="PERSON">Luke</name>'s saber and cuts the beast from head to toe.  He 
quickly tosses it's steaming innards into the snow, then lifts <name type="PERSON">Luke</name>'s 
inert form and stuffs him inside the carcass.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>HAN</speaker>
			(reeling from the 
			 odor) 
		Whew...</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
         <name type="FAC">Dagobah</name>...</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>HAN</speaker>
		This may smell bad, kid...</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
			(moaning)
		<name type="PERSON">Yoda</name>...</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>HAN</speaker>
		...but it will keep you warm... 
		til I get the shelter built.
			(struggling to get 
			 <name type="PERSON">Luke</name> inside the 
			 carcass) 
		Ooh... I thought they smelled bad 
		on the outside!</sp>
      <sd>The wind has picked up considerably, making it difficult to move.  <name type="PERSON">Han</name> 
removes a pack from the dead creature's back, taking out a shelter 
container.  He begins to set up what can only be a pitiful protection 
against a bitter <name type="GPE">Hoth</name> night.</sd>
      <setting>EXT. HOTH - SNOWDRIFT - DAWN</setting>
      <sd>Four snub-nosed armored snowspeeders race across the white landscape.</sd>
      <setting>INT. SNOWSPEEDER COCKPIT</setting>
      <sd>There is only one pilot, <name type="PERSON">Zev</name>, in the enclosed two-man craft.  He 
concentrates on the scopes which ring his cockpit.  He hears a low beep 
from one of his monitors.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>ZEV</speaker>
			(into transmitter) 
		Echo Base... I've got something!  Not 
		much, but it could be a life form.</sp>
      <setting>EXT. HOTH - SNOWDRIFT</setting>
      <sd>The small craft banks and makes a slow arc, then races off in a new 
direction.</sd>
      <setting>INT. SNOWSPEEDER - COCKPIT</setting>
      <sd>The pilot switches over to a new transmitter.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>ZEV</speaker>
			(into transmitter)
		This is <name type="PERSON">Rogue Two</name>.  this is Rogue 
		Two.  Captain <name type="PERSON">Solo</name>, so you copy?  
		Commander <name type="PERSON">Skywalker</name>, do you copy? 
		This is <name type="PERSON">Rogue Two</name>.</sp>
      <sd>There is a sharp crackle of static, then a faint voice.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>HAN</speaker>
			(filtered over 
			 <name type="PERSON">Zev</name>'s receiver)
		Good morning.  Nice of you guys 
		to drop by.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>ZEV</speaker>
			(switching transmitters) 
		Echo Base... this is <name type="PERSON">Rogue Two</name>.  I 
		found them.  Repeat, I found them.</sp>
      <setting>EXT. HOTH - SNOWDRIFT - DAY</setting>
      <sd>The small shelter <name type="PERSON">Han</name> set up is covered with snow on the windward side.  
A makeshift antenna rests gingerly on top the snowdrift.  <name type="PERSON">Han</name> spots 
<name type="PERSON">Zev</name>'s snowspeeder approaching in the distance, and begins waving his 
arms frantically at the tiny craft.</sd>
      <setting>INT. REBEL BASE - MEDICAL CENTER</setting>
      <sd>Strange robot surgeons adjust a mass of electronic eq<name type="ORG">uip</name>ment.  A switch 
is thrown and a sudden blinding flash obscures <name type="PERSON">Luke</name> in a bacta tank 
filled with a thick, gelatinous slime.  He begins to thrash about, 
raving in delirium.</sd>
      <setting>INT. REBEL BASE - MEDICAL CENTER - RECOVERY ROOM</setting>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">Luke</name> sits up in a recovery-room bed, weak but smiling.  His face shows 
terrible wounds from the <name type="ORG">Wampa</name>'s attack.  <name type="PERSON">Threepio</name> and <name type="PERSON">Artoo</name> enter the 
room.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="ORG">THREEPIO</name>
         </speaker>
		Master <name type="PERSON">Luke</name>, sir, it's so good 
		to see you fully functional again.</sp>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">Artoo</name> beeps his good wishes.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="ORG">THREEPIO</name>
         </speaker>
         <name type="PERSON">Artoo</name> expresses his relief, also.</sp>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">Han</name> and <name type="PERSON">Chewie</name> make their entrance.  The <name type="NORP">Wookiee</name> growls a greeting.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>HAN</speaker>
		How are you feeling, kid?  You 
		don't look so bad to me.  In 
		fact, you look strong enough to 
		pull the ears off a Gundark.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
		Thanks to you.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>HAN</speaker>
		That's two you owe me, junior.</sp>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">Han</name> turns as <name type="PERSON">Leia</name> enters the room.  He looks at her with a big, 
devilish grin.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>HAN</speaker>
		Well your Worship, looks like 
		you managed to keep me around for
		a little while longer.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
			(haughtily)
		I had nothing to do with it.  General 
		<name type="NORP">Rieekan</name> thinks it's dangerous for 
		any ships to leave the system until 
		we've activated the energy shield.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>HAN</speaker>
		That's a good story.  I think you 
		just can't bear to let a gorgeous 
		guy like me out of your sight.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
		I don't know where you get your 
		delusions, laser brain.</sp>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">Chewie</name> is amused; he laughs in his manner.  <name type="PERSON">Han</name>, enjoying himself, 
regards <name type="PERSON">Chewie</name> good-humoredly.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>HAN</speaker>
		Laugh it up, fuzzball.  But you 
		didn't see us alone in the south 
		passage.</sp>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">Luke</name> sparks to this; he looks at <name type="PERSON">Leia</name>.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>HAN</speaker>
		She expressed her true feelings 
		for me.</sp>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">Leia</name> is flushed, eyes darting between <name type="PERSON">Luke</name> and <name type="PERSON">Han</name>.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
		My...!  Why, you stuck up,... half-
		witted... scruffy-looking ...nerf-
		herder!</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>HAN</speaker>
		Who's scruffy-looking? 
			(to <name type="PERSON">Luke</name>) 
		I must have hit pretty close to 
		the mark to get her all riled up 
		like that, huh, kid?</sp>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">Leia</name> looks vulnerable for a moment, then the mask falls again, and she 
focuses on <name type="PERSON">Luke</name>.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
		Why, I guess you don't know 
		everything about women yet?</sp>
      <sd>With that she leans over and kisses <name type="PERSON">Luke</name> on the lips.  Then she turns 
on her heel and walks out, leaving everyone in the room slightly 
dumbstruck.  With some smugness, <name type="PERSON">Luke</name> puts his hands behind his head 
and grins.</sd>
      <sd>Suddenly, in the distance, the muffled sound of an alarm is heard.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>ANNOUNCER</speaker>
			(over loudspeaker)
		Headquarters personnel, report to 
		command center.</sp>
      <sd>The voice repeats the order and <name type="PERSON">Han</name>, <name type="PERSON">Chewie</name>, <name type="PERSON">Artoo</name>, and <name type="PERSON">Threepio</name> hurry 
out of the room, bidding farewell to <name type="PERSON">Luke</name>.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>HAN</speaker>
		Take it easy.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="ORG">THREEPIO</name>
         </speaker>
		Excuse us, please.</sp>
      <setting>INT. HOTH - REBEL BASE - COMMAND CENTER</setting>
      <sd>
         <name type="NORP">Rieekan</name> looks up grimly from a console screen.  He calls over to <name type="PERSON">Leia</name> 
and <name type="PERSON">Han</name>.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>RIEEKAN</speaker>
		Princess... we have a visitor.</sp>
      <sd>The group hurries over to <name type="NORP">Rieekan</name>.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>RIEEKAN</speaker>
		We've picked up something outside 
		the base in zone twelve, moving 
		east.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>SENIOR CONTROLLER</speaker>
		It's metal.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
		Then it couldn't be one of those 
		creatures that attacked <name type="PERSON">Luke</name>.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>HAN</speaker>
		It could be a speeder, one of ours.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>SENIOR CONTROLLER</speaker>
		No.  Wait - there's something very 
		weak coming through.</sp>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">Threepio</name> steps up to the control panel and listens intently to the 
strange signal.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="ORG">THREEPIO</name>
         </speaker>
		Sir, I am fluent in six million 
		forms of communication.  This signal 
		is not used by the Alliance.  It 
		could be an <name type="ORG">Imperial</name> code.</sp>
      <sd>The transmission ends in static.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>HAN</speaker>
		It isn't friendly, whatever it is.  
		Come on, <name type="PERSON">Chewie</name>, let's check it out.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>RIEEKAN</speaker>
		Send Rogues Ten and Eleven to 
		station three-eight.</sp>
      <setting>EXT. HOTH - SNOW PLAIN - DAY</setting>
      <sd>The dark probe robot moves past the smoldering ruins of station three-
eight and down a ridge toward the Rebel base.  It raises a large 
antenna from the top of its head and begins to send out a piercing 
signal.</sd>
      <sd>The probe droid has spotted <name type="PERSON">Chewbacca</name> who, not thirty feet away, has 
popped his head over a snow bank.  Instantly, the probe robot swings 
around, its deadly ray ready to fire.  But before it can get a shot 
off, it is hit from behind by a laser bolt, and explodes in a million 
pieces.</sd>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">Han</name>
         <name type="PERSON">Solo</name> replaces his blaster in its holster and peers intently at the 
smoldering remains of the <name type="ORG">Imperial</name> probe.</sd>
      <setting>INT. HOTH - REBEL BASE - COMMAND CENTER</setting>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">Leia</name> and <name type="NORP">Rieekan</name> listen to <name type="PERSON">Han</name> on the comlink.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>HAN</speaker>
			(over comlink)
		Afraid there's not much left.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
			(into comlink)
		What was it?</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>HAN</speaker>
			(over comlink)
		<name type="ORG">Droid</name> of some kind.  I didn't hit 
		it that hard.  It must have had a 
		self-destruct.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
			(into comlink)
		An <name type="ORG">Imperial</name> probe droid.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>HAN</speaker>
			(over comlink)
		It's a good bet the <name type="ORG">Empire</name> knows 
		we're here.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>RIEEKAN</speaker>
		We'd better start the evacuation.</sp>
      <setting>EXT. <name type="LOC">SPACE</name> - <name type="ORG">IMPERIAL</name> FLEET</setting>
      <sd>Darth <name type="PERSON">Vader</name>'s Star <name type="ORG">Destroyer</name>, larger and more awesome than the five 
<name type="ORG">Imperial</name> Star <name type="ORG">Destroyer</name>s that surround it, sits in the vastness of 
space.  The six huge ships are surrounded by a convoy of smaller 
spacecraft.  <name type="ORG">TIE</name> fighters dart to and fro.</sd>
      <setting>INT. <name type="PERSON">DARTH VADER</name>'S STAR DESTROYER - BRIDGE - MAIN CONTROL DECK</setting>
      <sd>Controllers working the vast complex of electronic controls hear 
ominous approaching footsteps and look up from their controls.  The 
squat, evil-looking Admiral <name type="PERSON">Ozzel</name> and the young, powerfully built 
<name type="PERSON">General Veers</name>, who have been conferring near the front, also feel the 
approaching presence and turn toward it.  Darth <name type="PERSON">Vader</name>, Lord of the 
Sith, enters like a chill wind.  As <name type="PERSON">Vader</name> moves across the wide bridge, 
Captain <name type="PERSON">Piett</name> hurries up to <name type="PERSON">Ozzel</name>.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>PIETT</speaker>
		Admiral.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>OZZEL</speaker>
		Yes, Captain</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>PIETT</speaker>
		I think we've got something, sir.  
		The report is only a fragment from 
		a probe droid in the <name type="GPE">Hoth</name> system, 
		but it's the best lead we've had.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>OZZEL</speaker>
			(irritated) 
		We have thousands of probe <name type="ORG">droids</name> 
		searching the galaxy.  I want proof, 
		not leads!</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>PIETT</speaker>
		The visuals indicate life readings.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>OZZEL</speaker>
		It could mean anything.  If we 
		followed every lead...</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>PIETT</speaker>
		But, sir, the <name type="GPE">Hoth</name> system is supposed 
		to be devoid of human forms.</sp>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">Vader</name> moves to a large screen showing an image of the Rebel snow base.  
Rebel speeders can be seen approaching the base in the distance.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>VADER</speaker>
		You found something?</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>PIETT</speaker>
		Yes, my lord.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>VADER</speaker>
			(studying the image 
			 on the console screen) 
		That's it.  The <name type="ORG">Rebels</name> are there.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>OZZEL</speaker>
		My lord, there are so many uncharted 
		settlements.  It could be smugglers, 
		it could be...</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>VADER</speaker>
		That is the system.  And I'm sure 
		<name type="PERSON">Skywalker</name> is with them.  Set your 
		course for the <name type="GPE">Hoth</name> system.  General 
		<name type="ORG">Veers</name>, prepare you men.</sp>
      <setting>INT. HOTH - REBEL BASE - TRANSPORT BAY</setting>
      <sd>A captain issues instructions to two of his men at the entrance to the 
main transport bay.  Several Rebel transports behind them are being 
loaded by men carrying heavy boxes and moving quickly, but not in 
panic.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>REBEL CAPTAIN</speaker>
		Groups seven and ten will stay 
		behind to fly the speeders.  As 
		soon as each transport is loaded, 
		evacuation control will give 
		clearance for immediate launch.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>REBEL FIGHTER</speaker>
		Right, sir.</sp>
      <setting>INT. HOTH - REBEL BASE - MAIN HANGAR DECK</setting>
      <sd>Alarms sound.  Troops, ground crews, and <name type="ORG">droids</name> rush to their alert 
stations.  Armored snowspeeders are lined up in attack formation near 
the main entrance.</sd>
      <sd>In the midst of all this activity, <name type="PERSON">Han</name> does some frantic welding on the 
lifters of the Millennium <name type="ORG">Falcon</name>.</sd>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">Han</name> finishes his work and hops down to the hangar floor.  He pulls out 
his comlink, all the while eyeing problematic lifters.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>HAN</speaker>
			(into comlink, to 
			 <name type="PERSON">Chewie</name>)
		Okay, that's it.  Try it... Off! 
		Turn it off!  Turn it off!  Off!</sp>
      <sd>Smoke rises from a minor explosion on the lifter.  Exasperated, <name type="PERSON">Han</name> 
surveys the new damage.</sd>
      <setting>INT. REBEL BASE - MEDICAL CENTER</setting>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">Luke</name> dresses in readiness for the evacuation as his attending medical 
droid stands by.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>MEDICAL DROID</speaker>
		Sir, it will take quite a while 
		to evacuate the T-forty- sevens.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
		Well, forget the heavy eq<name type="ORG">uip</name>ment.
		There's plenty of time to get the 
		smaller modules on the transports.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>MEDICAL DROID</speaker>
		Take care, sir.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
		Thanks.</sp>
      <setting>INT. REBEL BASE - MAIN HANGAR DECK</setting>
      <sd>Pilots, gunners, and R2 units scurry about.  <name type="PERSON">Luke</name>, pulling on his 
heavy-weather jacket, is headed toward a row of armored speeders.  He 
stops at the rear of the Millennium <name type="ORG">Falcon</name>, where <name type="PERSON">Han</name> and <name type="PERSON">Chewie</name> are 
trying to repair the right lifter with even more haste than before.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
         <name type="PERSON">Chewie</name>, take care of yourself, 
		okay?</sp>
      <sd>As <name type="PERSON">Luke</name> pats <name type="PERSON">Chewie</name> on the arm, <name type="PERSON">Chewie</name> puts his arms around <name type="PERSON">Luke</name> and 
gives him a tight hug.  <name type="PERSON">Han</name> is discussing the lifter with a repair 
droid when he sees <name type="PERSON">Luke</name>.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>HAN</speaker>
		Hi, kid.
			(to droid)
		There's got to be a reason for 
		it.  Check it at the other end.
		Wait a second.
			(to <name type="PERSON">Luke</name>)
		You all right?</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
		Yeah.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>HAN</speaker>
		Be careful.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
		You, too.</sp>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">Luke</name> smiles, then waves at his friend and walks on.  After a few steps, 
he stops and looks back.  <name type="PERSON">Han</name> glances up and the two exchange a silent 
communication, each wishing the other safety, happiness - many things, 
all difficult to verbalize.</sd>
      <setting>INT. REBEL BASE - CONTROL ROOM.</setting>
      <sd>Alarms sound throughout the hidden Rebel base.  In the control room, a 
controller urgently gestures for <name type="ORG">General Rieekan</name> to check a computer 
scan.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>CONTROLLER</speaker>
		General, there's a fleet of Star 
		<name type="ORG">Destroyer</name>s coming out of hyperspace 
		in sector four.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>RIEEKAN</speaker>
		Reroute all power to the energy 
		shield.  We've got to hold them till 
		all transports are away.  Prepare 
		for ground assault.</sp>
      <sd>
         <name type="NORP">Rieekan</name> exits hurriedly.</sd>
      <setting>INT. VADER'S STAR DESTROYER - VADER'S CHAMBER - MEDITATION CUBICLE</setting>
      <sd>The dark cubicle is illuminated by a single shaft of light which falls 
on the brooding <name type="PERSON">Dark Lord</name> as he sits on a raised meditation cube.  
<name type="PERSON">General Veers</name> enters the room and approaches the silent, unmoving 
<name type="PERSON">Vader</name>.  Although seemingly very sure of himself, <name type="ORG">Veers</name> is still not 
bold enough to interrupt the meditating lord.  The younger general 
stands quietly at attention until the evil presence speaks.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>VADER</speaker>
		What is it, General?</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>VEERS</speaker>
		My lord, the fleet has moves out 
		of light-speed.  Com-Scan has 
		detected an energy field protecting 
		an area around the sixth planet of 
		the <name type="GPE">Hoth</name> system.  The field is 
		strong enough to deflect any 
		bombardment.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>VADER</speaker>
			(angrily)
		The <name type="ORG">Rebels</name> are alerted to our 
		presence.  Admiral <name type="PERSON">Ozzel</name> came out 
		of light-speed too close to the 
		system.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>VEERS</speaker>
		He felt surprise was wiser...</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>VADER</speaker>
		He is as clumsy as he is stupid.
		General, prepare your troops for a 
		surface attack.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>VEERS</speaker>
		Yes, my lord.</sp>
      <sd>
         <name type="ORG">Veers</name> turns smartly and leaves as <name type="PERSON">Vader</name> activates a large viewscreen 
showing the bridge of his mighty ship.  Admiral <name type="PERSON">Ozzel</name> appears on the 
viewscreen, standing slightly in front of Captain <name type="PERSON">Piett</name>.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>OZZEL</speaker>
         <name type="PERSON">Lord Vader</name>, the fleet has moved 
		out of light-speed, and we're 
		preparing to... Aaagh!</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>VADER</speaker>
		You have failed me for the last 
		time, Admiral.  Captain <name type="PERSON">Piett</name>.</sp>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">Piett</name> steps forward, as the admiral moves away, slightly confused, 
touching his throat as it begins to constrict painfully.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>PIETT</speaker>
		Yes, my lord.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>VADER</speaker>
Make ready to land out troops beyond 
the energy shield and deploy the 
fleet so that nothing gets off that 
system.  You are in command now, 
Admiral <name type="PERSON">Piett</name>.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>PIETT</speaker>
		Thank you, <name type="PERSON">Lord Vader</name>.</sp>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">Piett</name>'s pleasure about his unexpected promotion is not an unmixed 
emotion.  He glances warily at the struggling Admiral <name type="PERSON">Ozzel</name> who, with a 
final choke, stumbles and falls in a lifeless heap before him.</sd>
      <setting>INT. REBEL BASE - MAIN HANGAR DECK</setting>
      <sd>With a sense of urgency, <name type="PERSON">Leia</name> quickly briefs a group of pilots gathered 
in the center of the hangar.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
		All troop carriers will assemble 
		at the north entrance.  The heavy 
		transport ships will leave as 
		soon as they're loaded.  Only two 
		fighter escorts per ship.  The 
		energy shield can only be opened 
		for a short time, so you'll have 
		to stay very close to your transports.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>HOBBIE</speaker>
		Two fighters against a Star <name type="ORG">Destroyer</name>?</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
		The ion cannon will fire several 
		shots to make sure that any enemy 
		ships will be out of your flight 
		path.  When you've gotten past the 
		energy shield, proceed directly to 
		the rendezvous point.  Understood?</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>PILOTS</speaker>
			(in unison)
		Right.  Okay.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
		Good luck.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>DERLIN</speaker>
		Okay.  Everyone to your stations.  
		Let's go!</sp>
      <sd>The pilots hurry away.</sd>
      <setting>EXT. HOTH - ICE PLAIN - SNOW TRENCH - DAY</setting>
      <sd>Rebel troops carry heavy bazooka-type weapons and position them along 
the snow trench.  Men hurriedly respond to their officers' yelled 
orders and brace themselves against the rhythmic gusts of bitter-cold 
wind.</sd>
      <sd>Other troops load power packs into a gun turret and swing its guns into 
position.</sd>
      <setting>EXT. HOTH - ICE PLAIN - POWER GENERATORS</setting>
      <sd>Near the base power generators, troops rush to set up their heavy 
battle eq<name type="ORG">uip</name>ment.  Buzzing loudly, the generators send along, sparking 
fingers of energy into the bitter <name type="GPE">Hoth</name> wind.</sd>
      <setting>INT. REBEL BASE - COMMAND CENTER</setting>
      <sd>The long line of Rebel controllers is tense, as are Princess <name type="PERSON">Leia</name> and 
<name type="ORG">General Rieekan</name>, who are trying very hard not to show any fear.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>RIEEKAN</speaker>
		Their primary target will be the 
		power generators.  Prepare to 
		open the shield.</sp>
      <setting>EXT. ICE PLAIN</setting>
      <sd>The Rebel transport and two escort fighters begin their departure from 
the ice planet.</sd>
      <setting>EXT. <name type="LOC">SPACE</name> - <name type="ORG">IMPERIAL</name> STAR DESTROYER</setting>
      <sd>A huge <name type="ORG">Imperial</name> Star <name type="ORG">Destroyer</name> rest against a sea of stars, far above 
the white surface of the planet <name type="GPE">Hoth</name>.</sd>
      <setting>INT. <name type="ORG">IMPERIAL</name> STAR DESTROYER - BRIDGE</setting>
      <sd>An <name type="ORG">Imperial</name> controller approaches his commander.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>CONTROLLER</speaker>
		Sir, Rebel ships are coming into 
		our sector.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
		Good.  Our first catch of the day.</sp>
      <setting>INT. REBEL BASE - COMMAND CENTER</setting>
      <sp>
         <speaker>WOMAN CONTROLLER</speaker>
		Stand by, ion control... Fire!</sp>
      <setting>EXT. REBEL BASE ICE CAVE - ION CANNON</setting>
      <sd>The giant ball-shaped ion cannon rotates into position and blasts two 
red energy beams skyward.</sd>
      <setting>EXT. <name type="LOC">SPACE</name> - HOTH - REBEL TRANSPORT</setting>
      <sd>The Rebel transport and its escort race away from the white planet, 
closely followed by the two red energy beams.</sd>
      <sd>As the Rebel transport races toward the waiting <name type="ORG">Imperial</name> Star 
<name type="ORG">Destroyer</name>, it is overtaken by the two scarlet energy bolts.  The 
<name type="ORG">Imperial</name> Star <name type="ORG">Destroyer</name> is hit in the conning tower by the powerful 
bolts, which set up fiery explosions on its metal hull.</sd>
      <sd>The big Star <name type="ORG">Destroyer</name> veers, then spins wildly out of control.  As the 
<name type="ORG">Imperial</name> ship careers into deep space, the Rebel transport races away 
to safety.</sd>
      <setting>INT. REBEL BASE - MAIN HANGAR DECK</setting>
      <sd>Pilots, gunners, and troopers hurry to their stations and their 
vehicles.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>ANNOUNCER</speaker>
			(over loudspeaker)
		The first transport is away.</sp>
      <sd>Everyone cheers at the announcement, which echoes through the hangar.  
<name type="PERSON">Luke</name> turns and walks on, heading toward his snowspeeder.  His gunner, 
<name type="PERSON">Dack</name>, a fresh-faced, eager kid, is glad to see him.  They climb in.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>DACK</speaker>
		Feeling all right, sir?</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
		Just like new, <name type="PERSON">Dack</name>.  How about 
		you?</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>DACK</speaker>
		Right now I feel like I could take 
		on the whole <name type="ORG">Empire</name> myself.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
			(quietly, strapping 
			 in)
		I know what you mean.</sp>
      <setting>EXT. HOTH - ICE PLAIN</setting>
      <sd>A thin horizon line cuts across the bleak landscape.  Small dot-size 
objects begin to appear on the horizon, moving in the direction of the 
Rebel base.</sd>
      <setting>EXT. HOTH - ICE PLAIN - SNOW TRENCH</setting>
      <sd>A Rebel officer lifts a pair of electrobinoculars to his eyes.  Through 
the lens he sees a very close view of a giant <name type="ORG">Imperial</name> snow walker.  He 
adjusts the view which then zooms back to reveal three more of the 
ominous battle machines.  Small flashes of yellow fire billow from the 
guns of the lumbering snow walkers.</sd>
      <sd>The officer lowers his binoculars as the regular rhythmic pounding 
begins to make the ground vibrate.  The pounding grows louder and is 
accompanied by a high-pitched, metallic rattling.  The officer speaks 
into his comlink.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>TRENCH OFFICER</speaker>
		Echo Station Three-T-Eight.</sp>
      <setting>INT. REBEL BASE - CORRIDOR</setting>
      <sd>Pilots and gunners race to their waiting snowspeeders.  Ice and snow 
begin falling from the walls of the corridor, shaken by the pounding 
<name type="ORG">Imperial</name> snow walker as they draw ever nearer.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>TRENCH OFFICER</speaker>
			(over comlink) 
		We have spotted <name type="ORG">Imperial</name> walkers!</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>CONTROLLER</speaker>
         <name type="ORG">Imperial</name> walkers on the north 
ridge.</sp>
      <setting>EXT. HOTH - ICE PLAIN - SNOW TRENCH</setting>
      <sd>The Rebel troops aim their weapons at the horizon as explosions erupt 
all around them.  They are nervous and their grip on their weapons 
tightens from the cold and from fear.</sd>
      <sd>Behind the troops a dozen snowspeeders race through the sky.</sd>
      <setting>INT. LUKE'S SNOWSPEEDER, ROGUE LEADER - COCKPIT</setting>
      <sp>
         <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
			(into comlink) 
		Echo station Five-Seven.  We're 
		on our way.</sp>
      <setting>EXT. HOTH - ICE PLAIN - <name type="ORG">BATTLE</name>FIELD</setting>
      <sd>The fleet of snowspeeders races above the ice field at full throttle.  
They accelerate away from the base and head toward the distant walkers.</sd>
      <setting>INT. LUKE'S SNOWSPEEDER, ROGUE LEADER - COCKPIT</setting>
      <sp>
         <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
			(into comlink) 
		All right, boys, keep tight now.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>DACK</speaker>
         <name type="PERSON">Luke</name>, I have no approach vector.  
		I'm not set.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
		Steady, <name type="PERSON">Dack</name>.  Attack pattern 
		delta.  Go now!</sp>
      <setting>EXT. HOTH - ICE PLAIN - <name type="ORG">BATTLE</name>FIELD</setting>
      <sd>The cannons mounted on the walker head fire at the speeders.  Other 
walkers loom in the background.  Two speeders race away past two of the 
enormous walkers and bank to the right.</sd>
      <setting>INT.  LUKE'S SNOWSPEEDER, ROGUE LEADER - COCKPIT</setting>
      <sp>
         <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
		All right, I'm coming in.</sp>
      <sd>He turns his speeder and heads directly at one of the walkers, flying 
toward its towering legs.  The horizon twists as the speeder banks 
between the legs.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
			(into comlink)
		Hobbie, you still with me?</sp>
      <setting>EXT. HOTH - ICE PLAIN - <name type="ORG">BATTLE</name>FIELD</setting>
      <sd>Two speeders race directly at the head of a walker, then split and fly 
past it.</sd>
      <sd>Three other walkers march onward, firing all cannons.</sd>
      <setting>EXT. HOTH - ICE PLAIN - SNOWTRENCH</setting>
      <sd>Rebel troops fire on the approaching walkers, as the snow and ice 
explode all around them.</sd>
      <setting>EXT. HOTH - ICE PLAIN - <name type="ORG">BATTLE</name>FIELD</setting>
      <sd>A speeder banks through and away from the legs of a walker.  Two other 
speeders pass the first speeder from the opposite direction.  Other 
Rebel craft race just above the icy plain.</sd>
      <sd>A giant walker head swivels and fires, striking a snowspeeder and 
sending it crashing in a ball of flames.</sd>
      <setting>INT. <name type="ORG">IMPERIAL</name> SNOW WALKER - COCKPIT</setting>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">General Veers</name> and two walker pilots keep a careful eye on the racing 
<name type="PERSON">Rebel snowspeeders</name> as they maneuver their lumbering war machine 
forward.</sd>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">Luke</name>'s speeder banks in from the side of <name type="ORG">Veers</name>'s walker and heads 
straight for its viewport, blasting away.  An explosion hits the walker 
window, but dissipates, doing no harm.  The speeder roars up and over 
the impregnable war machine.</sd>
      <setting>INT.  LUKE'S SNOWSPEEDER, ROGUE LEADER - COCKPIT</setting>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">Luke</name> looks back at the walker as it grows smaller in the distance.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
		That armor's too strong for 
		blasters.</sp>
      <sd>On the horizon, another walker moves up past <name type="PERSON">Luke</name>'s cockpit window, 
twisting out of sight as <name type="PERSON">Luke</name> banks and starts another run.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
			(into comlink)
		Rogue Group, use your harpoons 
		and tow cables.  Go for the legs.
		It might be our only chance of 
		stopping them.
			(to <name type="PERSON">Dack</name>)
		All right, stand by, <name type="PERSON">Dack</name>.</sp>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">Dack</name> is at the gunner's controls.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>DACK</speaker>
         <name type="PERSON">Luke</name>, we've got a malfunction in 
		fire control.  I'll have to cut in 
		the auxiliary.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
		Just hang on.  <name type="PERSON">Han</name>g on, <name type="PERSON">Dack</name>.  Get 
		ready to fire that tow cable.</sp>
      <sd>Barely keeping his seat in the tumbling ship, <name type="PERSON">Dack</name> struggles to set up 
his harpoon gun.</sd>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">Luke</name> swings his speeder around and heads toward an oncoming walker.  
Laser bolts and flak fill the air, creating a deadly obstacle course 
for the tiny craft.</sd>
      <setting>EXT. HOTH - ICE PLAIN - <name type="ORG">BATTLE</name>FIELD</setting>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">Rogue Leader</name> and another snowspeeder fly in tight formation toward the 
walker as explosions burst all around them.</sd>
      <setting>INT.  LUKE'S SNOWSPEEDER, ROGUE LEADER - COCKPIT</setting>
      <sd>After sustaining a heavy volley of fire, <name type="PERSON">Luke</name> turns around to see if 
<name type="PERSON">Dack</name> is all right.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
         <name type="PERSON">Dack</name>?  <name type="PERSON">Dack</name>!</sp>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">Dack</name> is lost.  Blood streams down his forehead, which rests on his 
smoldering controls.  Out the back window, an <name type="ORG">Imperial</name> walker recedes 
in the distance.</sd>
      <setting>EXT. HOTH - ICE PLAIN - SNOW TRENCH AREA</setting>
      <sd>Rebel troops fire the dishlike ray gun while explosions erupt around 
them.</sd>
      <setting>EXT. HOTH - ICE PLAIN - <name type="ORG">BATTLE</name>FIELD</setting>
      <sd>Two walkers lumber toward the Rebel base as a speeder between them 
explodes in a ball of flames.</sd>
      <setting>EXT. HOTH - ICE PLAIN - SNOW TRENCH</setting>
      <sd>The dislike ray gun is hit by a laser bolt and instantly explodes.</sd>
      <setting>INT. <name type="ORG">IMPERIAL</name> SNOW WALKER - COCKPIT</setting>
      <sd>Through the cockpit window, <name type="ORG">Veers</name> and his pilot can see the Rebel power 
generators in the distance.</sd>
      <sd>A hologram of Darth <name type="PERSON">Vader</name> appears on a control panel screen.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>VEERS</speaker>
		Yes, <name type="PERSON">Lord Vader</name>.  I've reached the 
		main power generator.  The shield 
		will be down in moments.  You may 
		start your landing.</sp>
      <setting>INT.  LUKE'S SNOWSPEEDER, ROGUE LEADER - COCKPIT</setting>
      <sp>
         <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
			(into comlink) 
		<name type="ORG">Rogue Three</name>.</sp>
      <setting>INT. WEDGE'S SNOWSPEEDER, ROGUE THREE - COCKPIT</setting>
      <sp>
         <speaker>WEDGE</speaker>
			(into comlink) 
		Copy, <name type="PERSON">Rogue Leader</name>
      </sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>LUKE </speaker>
			(over comlink) 
		<name type="ORG">Wedge</name>, I've lost my gunner.  You'll 
		have to make this shot.  I'll cover 
		for you.  Set your harpoon.  Follow 
		me on the next pass.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>WEDGE</speaker>
			(into comlink) 
		Coming around, <name type="PERSON">Rogue Leader</name>.</sp>
      <setting>INT.  LUKE'S SNOWSPEEDER, ROGUE LEADER - COCKPIT</setting>
      <sp>
         <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
			(into comlink) 
		Steady, <name type="PERSON">Rogue Two</name>
      </sp>
      <setting>EXT. HOTH - <name type="ORG">BATTLE</name>FIELD</setting>
      <sd>
         <name type="ORG">Wedge</name>'s speeder races through the legs of one of the monstrous walkers.</sd>
      <setting>INT. WEDGE'S SNOWSPEEDER, ROGUE THREE - COCKPIT</setting>
      <sp>
         <speaker>WEDGE</speaker>
			(to gunner) 
		Activate harpoon.</sp>
      <sd>
         <name type="ORG">Wedge</name>'s gunner reaches for a firing switch to activate the harpoon.  
The harpoon flashes out, and speeds toward the receding legs of the 
walker.</sd>
      <setting>EXT. HOTH - <name type="ORG">BATTLE</name>FIELD</setting>
      <sd>The harpoon hurtles toward the walker, In an instant it is embedded in 
one of the walker's legs.</sd>
      <setting>INT. WEDGE'S SNOWSPEEDER, ROGUE THREE - COCKPIT</setting>
      <sp>
         <speaker>WEDGE </speaker>
			(to gunner) 
		Good shot, Janson.</sp>
      <setting>EXT. HOTH - <name type="ORG">BATTLE</name>FIELD</setting>
      <sd>The speeder <name type="ORG">Rogue Three</name> races around one of the giant walker's feet, 
trailing the cable behind it.  Continuing around the back foot, Rogue 
Three then circles the walker around the tail end.</sd>
      <setting>INT. WEDGE'S SNOWSPEEDER, ROGUE THREE - COCKPIT</setting>
      <sd>
         <name type="ORG">Wedge</name> checks his controls and banks around the front of the walker.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>WEDGE</speaker>
		One more pass.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>JANSON </speaker>
		Coming around.  Once more.</sp>
      <setting>EXT. HOTH - <name type="ORG">BATTLE</name>FIELD</setting>
      <sd>The speeder sweeps left to right in front of the giant legs, towing the 
cable behind it.</sd>
      <setting>INT. WEDGE'S SNOWSPEEDER, ROGUE THREE - COCKPIT</setting>
      <sp>
         <speaker>JANSON</speaker>
		Once more.</sp>
      <sd>
         <name type="ORG">Wedge</name> swings the speeder between the legs of the giant walker.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>JANSON</speaker>
		Cable out!  Let her go!</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>WEDGE</speaker>
		Detach cable.</sp>
      <setting>EXT. WEDGE'S SNOWSPEEDER, ROGUE THREE</setting>
      <sd>The cable release on the back of the speeder snaps loose and the cable 
drops away.</sd>
      <setting>INT. WEDGE'S SNOWSPEEDER, ROGUE THREE - COCKPIT</setting>
      <sp>
         <speaker>JANSON</speaker>
		Cable detached.</sp>
      <setting>EXT. HOTH - <name type="ORG">BATTLE</name>FIELD</setting>
      <sd>The speeder zooms away into the distance.  The tangled legs of the 
enormous war machine attempt a step, but as they do the giant <name type="ORG">Imperial</name> 
walker begins to topple.  It teeters for a moment, and then crashes 
onto the icy ground, sending snow and metal pieces flying.</sd>
      <setting>EXT. HOTH - ICE PLAIN - SNOW TRENCH</setting>
      <sd>The troops in the trenches cheer at the sight of the crashing walker.</sd>
      <sd>An officer gives a signal to his men and Rebel troops charge the fallen 
war machine.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>TRENCH OFFICER</speaker>
		Come on!</sp>
      <sd>The troops run toward the downed walker, followed by two Rebel speeders 
flying overhead.  Just as they reach the walker, it explodes, the 
impact throwing some of the men onto the frozen ground.</sd>
      <setting>INT. WEDGE'S SNOWSPEEDER, ROGUE THREE - COCKPIT</setting>
      <sd>
         <name type="ORG">Wedge</name> lets out a triumphant yell, banking his speeder away from the 
fallen walker.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>WEDGE</speaker>
			(into comlink) 
		Whooha!  That got him!</sp>
      <setting>INT.  LUKE'S SNOWSPEEDER, ROGUE LEADER - COCKPIT</setting>
      <sp>
         <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
			(into comlink) 
		I see it, <name type="ORG">Wedge</name>.  Good work.</sp>
      <setting>INT. REBEL BASE - COMMAND CENTER</setting>
      <sd>Large chunks of ice tumble into the command center as <name type="PERSON">Leia</name> and General 
<name type="NORP">Rieekan</name> monitor computer screens.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>RIEEKAN</speaker>
		I don't think we can protect two 
		transports at a time.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>LEIA </speaker>
		It's risky, but we can't hold out 
		much longer.  We have no choice.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>RIEEKAN</speaker>
			(into comlink) 
		Launch patrols.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
			(to an aide) 
		Evacuate remaining ground staff.</sp>
      <setting>INT. REBEL BASE - MAIN HANGAR</setting>
      <sd>Muffled distant explosions create widening cracks in the ice roof of 
the hangar.  Trying to ignore the noise and falling bits of snow, <name type="PERSON">Han</name> 
works on one of the <name type="ORG">Falcon</name>'s lifters while <name type="PERSON">Chewie</name> works on one of the 
wings.  Noticing <name type="PERSON">Chewie</name> attach a wrong part, <name type="PERSON">Han</name> grows impatient.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>HAN</speaker>
		No, no!  No!  This one goes there, 
		that one goes there.  Right?</sp>
      <sd>In another area of the hangar, <name type="PERSON">Threepio</name> watches as <name type="PERSON">Artoo</name> is raised up 
into <name type="PERSON">Luke</name>'s X-wing fighter.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="ORG">THREEPIO</name>
         </speaker>
         <name type="PERSON">Artoo</name>, you take good care of 
		Master <name type="PERSON">Luke</name> now, understand?  And
		... do take good care of yourself.  
		Oh, dear, oh, dear.</sp>
      <setting>EXT. HOTH - <name type="ORG">BATTLE</name>FIELD</setting>
      <sd>The fierce battle on the vast snow plains of <name type="GPE">Hoth</name> rages on.  The 
<name type="ORG">Imperial</name> walkers continue their slow, steady assault on the Rebel base, 
firing lasers as they lumber ever onward.  In the snow trench, Rebel 
troops fire large bazookalike guns and dishlike ray guns as explosions 
erupt around them.  A gun tower is hit by a laser bolt and instantly 
explodes.  Another blast destroys a ray gun.</sd>
      <setting>INT. <name type="ORG">IMPERIAL</name> SNOW WALKER - COCKPIT</setting>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">General Veers</name> studies various readouts on his control panel.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>VEERS</speaker>
		All troops will debark for ground 
		assault.  Prepare to target the 
		main generator.</sp>
      <setting>EXT. HOTH - <name type="ORG">BATTLE</name>FIELD</setting>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">Luke</name>'s speeder and <name type="PERSON">Rogue Two</name> fly in formation, banking from right to 
left and flying above the erupting battlefield.  Flak bursts all around 
them.</sd>
      <setting>INT.  LUKE'S SNOWSPEEDER, ROGUE LEADER - COCKPIT</setting>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">Luke</name>, glancing over, sees <name type="PERSON">Rogue Two</name> on his left.  His ship shudders as 
flak bursts nearby.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
			(into comlink) 
		<name type="PERSON">Rogue Two</name>, are you all right?</sp>
      <setting>INT. ZEV'S SNOWSPEEDER, ROGUE TWO - COCKPIT</setting>
      <sp>
         <speaker>ZEV</speaker>
			(into comlink) 
		Yeah.  I'm with you, <name type="PERSON">Rogue Leader</name>.</sp>
      <setting>INT.  LUKE'S SNOWSPEEDER, ROGUE LEADER - COCKPIT</setting>
      <sp>
         <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
			(into comlink) 
		We'll set harpoon.  I'll cover for you.</sp>
      <setting>EXT. HOTH - <name type="ORG">BATTLE</name>FIELD</setting>
      <sd>The two speeders race across the horizon toward the giant walkers.</sd>
      <setting>INT. ZEV'S SNOWSPEEDER, ROGUE TWO - COCKPIT</setting>
      <sp>
         <speaker>ZEV</speaker>
			(into comlink) 
		Coming around.</sp>
      <setting>INT.  LUKE'S SNOWSPEEDER, ROGUE LEADER - COCKPIT</setting>
      <sp>
         <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
			(into comlink) 
		Watch that cross fire, boys.</sp>
      <setting>INT. ZEV'S SNOWSPEEDER, ROGUE TWO - COCKPIT</setting>
      <sp>
         <speaker>ZEV</speaker>
			(into comlink) 
		Set for position three.
			(to gunner) 
		Steady.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
			(over comlink) 
		Stay tight and low.</sp>
      <setting>EXT. ZEV'S SNOWSPEEDER, ROGUE TWO</setting>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">Luke</name>'s speeder moves in formation with <name type="PERSON">Rogue Two</name>, when suddenly <name type="PERSON">Zev</name>'s 
speeder is hit by a laser bolt.  His ship bucks violently under the 
impact and the cockpit explodes in a ball of flame.</sd>
      <sd>Spewing smoke, the speeder hurtles toward a looming walker.  Before 
they collide.  <name type="PERSON">Rogue Two</name> explodes in a million flaming pieces.</sd>
      <setting>INT. LUKE'S SNOWSPEEDER, ROGUE LEADER - COCKPIT</setting>
      <sd>Desperately, <name type="PERSON">Luke</name> works the controls of his flak-buffeted ship.  
Suddenly, the speeder is rocked by a huge explosion.  <name type="PERSON">Luke</name> struggles 
with the controls with a look of terror on his face.  The speeder fills 
with smoke, and electrical sparks jump about the cockpit.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
			(into comlink) 
		Hobbie, I've been hit!</sp>
      <setting>INT. REBEL BASE - COMMAND CENTER</setting>
      <sd>Apart from the distant thunder of laser blasts, the corridor is 
strangely quiet and empty.  Running footsteps echo through the freezing 
hallway, then <name type="PERSON">Han</name> appears.  Cracks have appeared in some of the walls 
and some pipes have broken, sending hot steam billowing into the 
underground hallways.  <name type="PERSON">Han</name> hurries into the command center.  It is a 
shambles, but some people are still at their posts.  As he enters, a 
gigantic cave-in almost obliterates the room.  He finds <name type="PERSON">Leia</name> and 
<name type="PERSON">Threepio</name> near one of the control boards.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>HAN</speaker>
		You all right?</sp>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">Leia</name> nods.  She is surprised to see him.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
		Why are you still here?</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>HAN</speaker>
		I heard the command center had 
		been hit.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
		You got your clearance to leave.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>HAN</speaker>
		Don't worry.  I'll leave.  First 
		I'm going to get you to your ship.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="ORG">THREEPIO</name>
         </speaker>
		Your Highness, we must take this 
		last transport.  It's our only hope.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
			(to controller) 
		Send all troops in sector twelve 
		to the south slope to protect the 
		fighters.</sp>
      <sd>A blast rocks the command center, throwing <name type="PERSON">Threepio</name> backward into <name type="PERSON">Han</name>'s 
arms.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>ANNOUNCER</speaker>
			(over loudspeaker) 
		<name type="ORG">Imperial</name> troops have entered the 
		base.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>HAN</speaker>
		Come on... that's it.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
			(to head controller) 
		Give the evacuation code signal.  
		And get to your transports!</sp>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">Leia</name> looks exhausted.  <name type="PERSON">Han</name> grabs her and starts to lead her out.</sd>
      <sd>As <name type="PERSON">Han</name>, <name type="PERSON">Leia</name>, and <name type="PERSON">Threepio</name> run out of the command center, the code 
signal can be heard echoing off the corridor walls.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>HEAD CONTROLLER</speaker>
		K-one-zero... all troops disengage.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="ORG">THREEPIO</name>
         </speaker>
			(to <name type="PERSON">Han</name> and <name type="PERSON">Leia</name>) 
		Oh!  Wait for me!</sp>
      <setting>EXT. <name type="ORG">BATTLE</name>FIELD - SNOW TRENCH</setting>
      <sd>Rebel troops retreat under the awesome <name type="ORG">Imperial</name> onslaught.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>OFFICER</speaker>
		Begin retreat!</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>SECOND OFFICER</speaker>
		Fall back!</sp>
      <sd>Troops flee from the battle, the ground exploding around them.</sd>
      <setting>EXT. HOTH - <name type="ORG">BATTLE</name>FIELD</setting>
      <sd>Three of the giant walkers, firing lasers, advance toward the Rebel 
headquarters.</sd>
      <setting>EXT. HOTH - SNOW TRENCH</setting>
      <sd>Continuing their retreat, the <name type="ORG">Rebels</name> see the walkers looming ever 
nearer.</sd>
      <setting>EXT. HOTH - <name type="ORG">BATTLE</name>FIELD - ICE PLAIN</setting>
      <sd>On the battlefield, <name type="PERSON">Luke</name> watches as a walker foot rises and moves over 
him.  He looks up at the underbelly of the huge walker, passing 
overhead.</sd>
      <sd>Running beneath the monstrous machine, <name type="PERSON">Luke</name> fires his harpoon gun at 
the walker's underside.  A thin cable follows the projectile from the 
gun.  The magnetic head and cable attach firmly to the metal hull.</sd>
      <sd>Still running under the walker, <name type="PERSON">Luke</name> attaches the cable drum to his 
belt buckle.  Soon he is pulled up the cable and hangs dangling 
underneath the walker.</sd>
      <sd>The walker's giant feet continue to pound onward across the frozen 
snow.  Stray laser bolts whistle by <name type="PERSON">Luke</name> as he climbs up the cable to 
the walker's hull, reaching a small hatch.  <name type="PERSON">Han</name>ging precariously, <name type="PERSON">Luke</name> 
cuts the solid metal hatch with his laser sword.</sd>
      <sd>He takes a landmine from around his neck and throws it inside the 
<name type="ORG">Imperial</name> machine.  Quickly, <name type="PERSON">Luke</name> starts down the cable and crashes onto 
the icy ground far below.  He lies unconscious as a giant rear leg 
passes by - and just misses him.</sd>
      <sd>The giant walker stops in mid-step.  A muffled explosion comes from 
within - and then the walker's mechanical insides  are spewed out every 
conceivable opening.  The machine sits dead in its tracks, smoking like 
a locomotive on stilts.</sd>
      <setting>EXT. HOTH - <name type="ORG">BATTLE</name>FIELD</setting>
      <sd>
         <name type="ORG">Veers</name>'s walker continues to advance toward the Rebel base.  The 
smoldering walker that <name type="PERSON">Luke</name> exploded stands smoking just to the right 
of <name type="ORG">Veers</name>'s path.</sd>
      <setting>INT. <name type="ORG">IMPERIAL</name> SNOW WALKER - COCKPIT</setting>
      <sd>Inside his walker, <name type="PERSON">General Veers</name> prepares to fire on the Rebel power 
generators.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>VEERS</speaker>
		Distance to power generators?</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>PILOT</speaker>
		One-seven, decimal two-eight.</sp>
      <sd>
         <name type="ORG">Veers</name> reaches for the electrorangefinder and lines up the main 
generator.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>VEERS</speaker>
		Target.  Maximum fire power.</sp>
      <setting>EXT. HOTH - <name type="ORG">BATTLE</name>FIELD</setting>
      <sd>The Rebel troops continue their desperate retreat, pushed back by the 
relentless <name type="ORG">Imperial</name> assault.</sd>
      <setting>INT. HOTH - REBEL BASE - ICE CORRIDORS</setting>
      <sd>With <name type="PERSON">Threepio</name> lagging behind, <name type="PERSON">Han</name> and <name type="PERSON">Leia</name> race through the crumbling 
ice corridors.  Suddenly, there is an explosion.  <name type="PERSON">Han</name> turns, grabs the 
princess, and pulls her to the wall as a tremendous cave-in blacks 
their path.</sd>
      <sd>He takes the comlink from his pocket.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>HAN </speaker>
			(into comlink) 
		Transport, this is <name type="PERSON">Solo</name>.  Better 
		take off - I can't get to you.  
		I'll get the princess out on the 
		<name type="ORG">Falcon</name>.</sp>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">Han</name> and <name type="PERSON">Leia</name> turn and race down the corridor.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="ORG">THREEPIO</name>
         </speaker>
		But... but... but... where are 
		you going?  Uh... come back!!</sp>
      <setting>INT. HOTH - REBEL BASE - COMMAND CENTER</setting>
      <sd>
         <name type="ORG">Imperial</name> troops have reached the base.  As they push through the 
blocked passageway, Darth <name type="PERSON">Vader</name> strides behind them.</sd>
      <setting>INT. HOTH - REBEL BASE - ICE CORRIDOR</setting>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">Han</name> and <name type="PERSON">Leia</name> run toward the entrance of the main hangar where the 
Millennium <name type="ORG">Falcon</name> is docked.  <name type="PERSON">Threepio</name> still lags behind.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="ORG">THREEPIO</name>
         </speaker>
		Wait!  Wait for me!  Wait!  Stop!</sp>
      <sd>The door to the hangar closes in his face.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="ORG">THREEPIO</name>
         </speaker>
			(exasperated) 
		How typical.</sp>
      <sd>Quickly, the door reopens as <name type="PERSON">Han</name> reaches out and pulls <name type="FAC">the golden droid</name> 
through.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>HAN</speaker>
		Come on.</sp>
      <setting>INT. HOTH - REBEL BASE - MAIN HANGAR</setting>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">Chewie</name> paces under the shelter of the Millennium <name type="ORG">Falcon</name>'s landing gear.  
The giant <name type="NORP">Wookiee</name> pats the underbelly of his beloved ship and barks a 
few reassuring words.  As he searches worriedly for his captain, 
something at last catches his eye.</sd>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">Chewie</name> lets out a relieved shriek at seeing <name type="PERSON">Han</name> and <name type="PERSON">Leia</name> running toward 
the ship.  The <name type="NORP">Wookiee</name> runs out into the falling ice, lets out a howl, 
then runs up the ship's ramp.  <name type="PERSON">Han</name> and <name type="PERSON">Leia</name> run up the ramp after him, 
closely followed by <name type="PERSON">Threepio</name>.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>HAN</speaker>
		Hurry up, goldenrod, or you're 
		going to be a permanent resident!</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="ORG">THREEPIO</name>
         </speaker>
		Wait!  Wait!</sp>
      <setting>INT. HOTH - REBEL BASE - ICE CORRIDOR</setting>
      <sd>
         <name type="ORG">Imperial</name> troops run through the base corridors.  <name type="PERSON">Vader</name> surveys the 
place.  A huge chunk falls, almost hitting him, but  he calmly, 
purposefully, continues around it.</sd>
      <setting>INT. REBEL BASE - MAIN HANGER - <name type="ORG">MILLENNIUM</name>
         <name type="ORG">FALCON</name>
      </setting>
      <sd>A distant, huge, explosion rocks the hangar deck.  Ice cakes come 
crashing down on the Millennium <name type="ORG">Falcon</name>.</sd>
      <setting>INT. MAIN HANGAR - <name type="ORG">MILLENNIUM</name>
         <name type="ORG">FALCON</name> - MAIN HOLD</setting>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">Han</name>, standing before a control panel, is busy flipping switches as 
<name type="PERSON">Chewie</name> watches a troublesome gauge.  A worried <name type="PERSON">Leia</name> observes their 
efforts.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>HAN</speaker>
			(to <name type="PERSON">Chewie</name>)
		How's this?</sp>
      <sd>The <name type="NORP">Wookiee</name> barks a negative reply.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
		Would it helped if I got out and 
		pushed?</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>HAN</speaker>
		It might.</sp>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">Threepio</name> clanks into the hold.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="ORG">THREEPIO</name>
         </speaker>
		Captain <name type="PERSON">Solo</name>, Captain <name type="PERSON">Solo</name>... sir, 
		might I suggest that you...</sp>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">Han</name> gives the gold robot a devastating look.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="ORG">THREEPIO</name>
         </speaker>
		It can wait.</sp>
      <setting>INT. MAIN HANGAR - <name type="ORG">MILLENNIUM</name>
         <name type="ORG">FALCON</name> - COCKPIT</setting>
      <sd>They move to the cockpit where <name type="PERSON">Han</name> flips some more switches.  <name type="PERSON">Leia</name> 
watches him, impatient, disbelieving.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
		This bucket of bolts is never going 
		to get us past that blockade.</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>HAN</speaker>
		This baby's got a few surprises 
		left in her, sweetheart.</sp>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">Han</name> and <name type="PERSON">Leia</name> look out the cockpit window and see a squad of 
stormtroopers rushing into the far side of the hangar.</sd>
      <sd>Quickly, <name type="PERSON">Han</name> straps himself into the pilot's seat and <name type="PERSON">Leia</name> into the 
navigator's chair.</sd>
      <setting>INT. HOTH - REBEL BASE - MAIN HANGAR</setting>
      <sd>
         <name type="ORG">Stormtroopers</name> hurriedly set up a large bazookalike weapon.  Behind them 
the giant hangar doors open slowly.</sd>
      <setting>EXT. MAIN HANGAR - <name type="ORG">MILLENNIUM</name>
         <name type="ORG">FALCON</name>
      </setting>
      <sd>A laser gun appears on the <name type="ORG">Falcon</name> and swings around to aim at the 
<name type="ORG">Imperial</name> troops.</sd>
      <sd>The stormtroopers, preparing to fire their bazooka cannon, are hit by 
the <name type="ORG">Falcon</name>'s fire and are thrown about in all directions.</sd>
      <setting>INT. MAIN HANGAR - <name type="ORG">MILLENNIUM</name>
         <name type="ORG">FALCON</name> - COCKPIT</setting>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">Chewie</name> rushes into the cockpit.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>HAN</speaker>
		Come on!  Come on!  Switch over.
		Let's hope we don't have a burnout.</sp>
      <sd>A laser hits the window near <name type="PERSON">Chewie</name> as he is settling into his chair.  
Letting out a loud whelp, <name type="PERSON">Chewie</name> quickly pulls back on the controls and 
the first stage of engine fire can be heard.  <name type="PERSON">Han</name> flashes a big grin at 
<name type="PERSON">Leia</name>.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>HAN</speaker>
		See?</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
		Someday you're going to be wrong, 
		and I hope I'm there to see it.</sp>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">Han</name> looks at <name type="PERSON">Chewie</name>.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>HAN</speaker>
		Punch it!</sp>
      <sd>The roar of the <name type="ORG">Falcon</name>'s main engines blasts out everything as the ice-
cave wall rushes by outside the cockpit window.</sd>
      <setting>INT. REBEL BASE - MAIN HANGAR</setting>
      <sd>More stormtroopers run into the hangar, closely followed by <name type="PERSON">Vader</name>.  
Hearing the loud roar of the Millennium <name type="ORG">Falcon</name>'s engines, <name type="PERSON">Vader</name> looks 
toward the main hangar doors just in time to see the <name type="ORG">Falcon</name> lift up and 
disappear outside the cave.</sd>
      <setting>EXT. HOTH - ICE SLOPE - DAY</setting>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">Luke</name> and two other pilots look up as the Millennium <name type="ORG">Falcon</name> races above 
them, flying very close to the ground.</sd>
      <sd>The three pilots turn then, and trudge onward toward their X-wing 
fighters, each going to his own ship.  <name type="PERSON">Luke</name> waves farewell, then heads 
toward his own fighter.  </sd>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">Artoo</name>, seated on his cubbyhole, chirps an excited greeting as <name type="PERSON">Luke</name> 
climbs aboard the spacecraft.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
         <name type="PERSON">Artoo</name>!  Get her ready for takeoff.</sp>
      <sd>From his ship, <name type="PERSON">Luke</name> sees <name type="ORG">Wedge</name> in his own X-wing, preparing for 
takeoff.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>WEDGE</speaker>
		Good luck, <name type="PERSON">Luke</name>.  See you at 
		the rendezvous.</sp>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">Luke</name> smiles and nods at <name type="ORG">Wedge</name>, then lowers himself into the cockpit of 
his X-wing while <name type="PERSON">Artoo</name> waits in the cubbyhole, beeping impatiently.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
		Don't worry, <name type="PERSON">Artoo</name>.  We're going, 
		we're going.</sp>
      <sd>The canopy over the X-wing lowers and snaps shut.</sd>
      <setting>EXT. <name type="LOC">SPACE</name> -  LUKE'S X-WING</setting>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">Luke</name>'s fighter, its wings closed, speeds away from the icy planet.  
Soon it disappears into the stars.</sd>
      <setting>INT.  LUKE'S X-WING - COCKPIT</setting>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">Luke</name>, looking thoughtful, suddenly makes a decision.  He flips several 
switches.  The stars shift as he takes his fighter into a steep turn.  
The X-wing banks sharply and flies away in a new direction.</sd>
      <sd>The monitor screen on <name type="PERSON">Luke</name>'s control panel prints out a question from 
the concerned <name type="PERSON">Artoo</name>.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
			(into comlink)
		There's nothing wrong, <name type="PERSON">Artoo</name>.
		I'm just setting a new course.</sp>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">Artoo</name> beeps once again.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
			(into comlink)
		We're not going to regroup with 
		the others.</sp>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">Artoo</name> begins a protest, whistling an unbelieving, "What?!"</sd>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">Luke</name> reads <name type="PERSON">Artoo</name>'s exclamation on his control panel.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
			(into comlink)
		We're going to the <name type="FAC">Dagobah</name> system.</sp>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">Luke</name> checks his readouts and makes a few adjustments.  He rides along 
with only the soft hum of the instruments to break the silence.  
Finally, <name type="PERSON">Artoo</name> chirps up.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
			(into comlink)
		Yes, <name type="PERSON">Artoo</name>?</sp>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">Artoo</name> utters a soft, carefully phrased steam of whistles.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
			(into comlink, chuckling)
		That's all right.  I'd like to 
		keep it on manual control for a 
		while.</sp>
      <sd>The little droid lets out a defeated whimper.  <name type="PERSON">Luke</name> smiles, and 
continues on his course.</sd>
      <setting>EXT. <name type="LOC">SPACE</name> - <name type="ORG">MILLENNIUM</name>
         <name type="ORG">FALCON</name>
      </setting>
      <sd>The Millennium <name type="ORG">Falcon</name> speeds away from <name type="GPE">Hoth</name>, closely followed by one 
huge Star <name type="ORG">Destroyer</name> and four tiny <name type="ORG">TIE</name> fighters.</sd>
      <sd>As it is pursued, the <name type="ORG">Falcon</name> races toward two very bright star-sized 
objects.</sd>
      <setting>INT. <name type="ORG">MILLENNIUM</name>
         <name type="ORG">FALCON</name> - COCKPIT</setting>
      <sd>Inside the cockpit, <name type="PERSON">Chewie</name> lets out a loud howl.  <name type="PERSON">Han</name> checks as the 
ship is buffeted by exploding flak.  He appears to be doing six things 
at once.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>HAN</speaker>
			(harried)
		I saw them!  I saw them!</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
		Saw what?</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>HAN</speaker>
		Star <name type="ORG">Destroyer</name>s, two of them, 
		coming right at us.</sp>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">Threepio</name> bumps and bangs his way into the cockpit.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>
            <name type="ORG">THREEPIO</name>
         </speaker>
		Sir, sir!  Might I suggest...</sp>
      <sp>
         <speaker>HAN</speaker>
			(to <name type="PERSON">Leia</name>)
		Shut him up or shut him down!
			(to <name type="PERSON">Chewie</name>)
		Check the deflector shield!</sp>
      <sd>
         <name type="PERSON">Chewie</name> barks a reply as he readjusts an overhead switch.</sd>
      <sp>
         <speaker>HAN</speaker>
		Oh, great.  Well, we can still 
		outmaneuver them.</sp>
      <setting>EXT. <name type="LOC">SPACE</name> - <name type="ORG">MILLENNIUM</name>
         <name type="ORG">FALCON</name> - STAR DESTROYERS</setting>
      <sd>The Millennium <name type="ORG">Falcon</name> races toward one of the huge oncoming Star 
<name type="ORG">Destroyer</name>s.  Suddenly, the <name type="ORG">Falcon</name> starts into a deep dive straight 
down, closely followed by four <name type="ORG">TIE</name> fighters.  The underside of the Star 
<name type="ORG">Destroyer</name> continues on a collision course with two oncoming Star 
<name type="ORG">Destroyer</name>s.  Slowly, it starts to veer to the left.</sd>
      <setting>INT. STAR DESTROYER - BRIDGE</setting>
Out the front window, the two approaching Star <name type="ORG">Destroyer</name>s can be seen 
veering to the left.
