<?xml-model href="sw_schema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<root>

<title>Star Wars: Episode IV - A New Hope (1977)</title>
by <writer>George Lucas.</writer>
 

<script>

<sd> A vast sea of stars serves as the backdrop for the main title. 
War drums echo through the heavens as a rollup slowly crawls 
into infinity.</sd>
 <subTitle epNum="4">EPISODE 4 A NEW HOPE</subTitle>

 <crawl> A long time ago, in a galaxy far, far, away...

  It is a period of civil war. Rebel spaceships, 
  striking from a hidden base, have won their first 
  victory against the evil <name type="NORP">Galactic</name> <name type="ORG">Empire</name>.

  During the battle, Rebel spies managed to steal 
  secret plans to the <name type="ORG">Empire</name>'s ultimate weapon, the 
  <name type="ORG">Death Star</name>, an armored space station with enough 
  power to destroy an entire planet.

  Pursued by the <name type="ORG">Empire</name>'s sinister agents, Princess 
  <name type="PERSON">Leia</name> races home aboard her starship, custodian of 
  the stolen plans that can save her people and 
  restore freedom to the galaxy...</crawl>

<sd>The awesome yellow planet of <name type="LOC">Tatooine</name> emerges from a total 
eclipse, her two <name type="LOC">moon</name>s glowing against the darkness. A tiny 
silver spacecraft, a Rebel Blockade Runner firing lasers 
from the back of the ship, races through space. It is pursed 
by a giant <name type="ORG">Imperial</name> Stardestroyer. Hundreds of deadly 
<name type="PERSON">laserbolt</name>s streak from the <name type="ORG">Imperial</name> Stardestroyer, causing 
the main solar fin of the Rebel craft to disintegrate.</sd>

<setting>INT. REBEL BLOCKADE RUNNER - MAIN PASSAGEWAY</setting>

<sd>An explosion rocks the ship as two robots, <name type="PERSON">Artoo</name>-Detoo (R2-
D2) and See-<name type="PERSON">Threepio</name> (C-3PO) struggle to make their way 
through the shaking, bouncing passageway. Both robots are 
old and battered. <name type="PERSON">Artoo</name> is a short, claw-armed tripod. His 
face is a mass of computer lights surrounding a radar eye. 
<name type="PERSON">Threepio</name>, on the other hand, is a tall, slender robot of 
human proportions. He has a gleaming bronze-like metallic 
surface of an <name type="ORG">Art Deco</name> design.</sd>

<sd>Another blast shakes them as they struggle along their way.</sd>

<sp><speaker><name type="ORG">THREEPIO</name></speaker>
Did you hear that? They've shut down 
the main reactor. We'll be destroyed 
for sure. This is madness!</sp>

<sd>Rebel troopers rush past the robots and take up positions in 
the main passageway. They aim their weapons toward the door.</sd>

<sp><speaker><name type="ORG">THREEPIO</name></speaker>
We're doomed!</sp>

<sd>The little R2 unit makes a series of electronic sounds that 
only another robot could understand.</sd>

<sp><speaker><name type="ORG">THREEPIO</name></speaker>
There'll be no escape for the Princess 
this time.</sp>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Artoo</name> continues making beeping sounds. Tension mounts as 
loud metallic latches clank and the scream of heavy eq<name type="ORG">uip</name>ment 
are heard moving around the outside hull of the ship.</sd>

<sp><speaker><name type="ORG">THREEPIO</name></speaker>
What's that?</sp>

<setting>EXT. <name type="LOC">SPACE</name>CRAFT IN <name type="LOC">SPACE</name></setting>

<sd>The <name type="ORG">Imperial</name> craft has easily overtaken the Rebel Blockade 
Runner. The smaller Rebel ship is being drawn into the 
underside dock of the giant <name type="ORG">Imperial</name> starship.</sd>

<setting>INT. REBEL BLOCKADE RUNNER</setting>

<sd>The nervous Rebel troopers aim their weapons. Suddenly a 
tremendous blast opens up a hole in the main passageway and 
a score of fearsome armored spacesuited stormtroopers make 
their way into the smoke-filled corridor.</sd>

<sd>In a few minutes the entire passageway is ablaze with 
laserfire. The deadly bolts ricochet in wild random patterns 
creating huge explosions. <name type="ORG">Stormtroopers</name> scatter and duck 
behind storage lockers. Laserbolts hit several Rebel soldiers 
who scream and stagger through the smoke, holding shattered 
arms and faces.</sd>

<sd>An explosion hits near the robots.</sd>

<sp><speaker><name type="ORG">THREEPIO</name></speaker>
I should have known better than to 
trust the logic of a half-sized 
thermocapsulary dehousing assister...</sp>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Artoo</name> counters with an angry rebuttal as the battle rages 
around the two hapless robots.</sd>

<setting>EXT. TATOOINE - DESERT WASTELAND - DAY</setting>

<sd>A death-white wasteland stretches from horizon to horizon. 
The tremendous heat of two huge twin suns settle on a lone 
figure, <name type="PERSON">Luke</name> <name type="PERSON">Skywalker</name>, a farm boy with heroic aspirations 
who looks much younger than his eighteen years. His shaggy 
hair and baggy tunic give him the air of a simple but lovable 
lad with a prize-winning smile.</sd>

<sd>A light wind whips at him as he adjusts several valves on a 
large battered moisture vaporator which sticks out of the 
desert floor much like an oil pipe with valves. He is aided 
by a <name type="PERSON">beatup</name> tread-robot with six claw arms. The little robot 
appears to be barely functioning and moves with jerky motions.  
A bright sparkle in the morning sky catches <name type="PERSON">Luke</name>'s eye and 
he instinctively grabs a pair of electrobinoculars from his 
utility belt. He stands transfixed for a few moments studying 
the heavens, then dashed toward his dented, crudely repaired 
<name type="PERSON">Landspeeder</name> (an auto-like transport that travels a few feet 
above the ground on a magnetic-field). He motions for the 
tiny robot to follow him.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
Hurry up! Come with me! What are you 
waiting for?! Get in gear!</sp>

<sd>The robot scoots around in a tight circle, stops short, and 
smoke begins to pour out of every joint. <name type="PERSON">Luke</name> throws his 
arms up in disgust. Exasperated, the young farm boy jumps 
into his <name type="PERSON">Landspeeder</name> leaving the smoldering robot to hum 
madly.</sd>

<setting>INT. REBEL BLOCKADE RUNNER - MAIN HALLWAY</setting>

<sd>The awesome, seven-foot-tall <name type="PERSON">Dark Lord</name> of the Sith makes his 
way into the blinding light of the main passageway. This is 
Darth <name type="PERSON">Vader</name>, right hand of <name type="FAC">the Emperor</name>. His face is obscured 
by his flowing black robes and grotesque breath mask, which 
stands out next to the fascist white armored suits of the 
<name type="ORG">Imperial</name> stormtroopers. Everyone instinctively backs away 
from the imposing warrior and a deathly quiet sweeps through 
the Rebel troops. Several of the Rebel troops break and run 
in a frenzied panic.</sd>

<setting>INT. REBEL BLOCKADE RUNNER</setting>

<sd>A woman's hand puts a card into an opening in <name type="PERSON">Artoo</name>'s dome.  
<name type="PERSON">Artoo</name> makes beeping sounds.</sd>

<setting>INT. REBEL BLOCKADE RUNNER</setting>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Threepio</name> stands in a hallway, somewhat bewildered. <name type="PERSON">Artoo</name> is 
nowhere in sight. The pitiful screams of the doomed Rebel 
soldiers can be heard in the distance.</sd>

<sp><speaker><name type="ORG">THREEPIO</name></speaker>
<name type="PERSON">Artoo</name>! <name type="PERSON">Artoo</name>-Detoo, where are you?</sp>

<sd>A familiar clanking sound attacks <name type="PERSON">Threepio</name>'s attention and 
he spots little <name type="PERSON">Artoo</name> at the end of the hallway in a smoke-
filled alcove. A beautiful young girl (about sixteen years 
old) stands in front of <name type="PERSON">Artoo</name>. Surreal and out of place, 
dreamlike and half hidden in the smoke, she finishes adjusting 
something on <name type="PERSON">Artoo</name>'s computer face, then watches as the little 
robot joins his companion.</sd>

<sp><speaker><name type="ORG">THREEPIO</name></speaker>
At last! Where have you been?</sp>

<sd><name type="ORG">Stormtroopers</name> can be heard battling in the distance.</sd>

<sp><speaker><name type="ORG">THREEPIO</name></speaker>
They're heading in this direction. 
What are we going to do? We'll be 
sent to the spice mine of Kessel or 
smashed into who knows what!</sp>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Artoo</name> scoots past his bronze friend and races down the 
<name type="GPE">subhallway</name>. <name type="PERSON">Threepio</name> chases after him.</sd>

<sp><speaker><name type="ORG">THREEPIO</name></speaker>
Wait a minute, where are you going?</sp>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Artoo</name> responds with electronic beeps.</sd>

<setting>INT. REBEL BLOCKADE RUNNER - CORRIDOR</setting>

<sd>The evil Darth <name type="PERSON">Vader</name> stands amid the broken and twisted bodies 
of his foes. He grabs a wounded Rebel Officer by the neck as 
an <name type="ORG">Imperial</name> Officer rushes up to the <name type="PERSON">Dark Lord</name>.</sd>

<sp><speaker><name type="ORG">IMPERIAL</name> OFFICER</speaker>
The <name type="ORG">Death Star</name> plans are not in the 
main computer.</sp>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Vader</name> squeezes the neck of the Rebel Officer, who struggles 
in vain.</sd>

<sp><speaker>VADER</speaker>
Where are those transmissions you 
intercepted?</sp>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Vader</name> lifts the Rebel off his feet by his throat.</sd>

<sp><speaker>VADER</speaker>
What have you done with those plans?</sp>

<sp><speaker>REBEL OFFICER</speaker>
We intercepted no transmissions. 
Aaah... This is a consular ship. 
Were on a diplomatic mission.</sp>

<sp><speaker>VADER</speaker>
If this is a consular ship... were 
is the Ambassador?</sp>

<sd>The Rebel refuses to speak but eventually cries out as the 
<name type="PERSON">Dark Lord</name> begins to squeeze the officer's throat, creating a 
gruesome snapping and choking, until the soldier goes limp. 
<name type="PERSON">Vader</name> tosses the dead soldier against the wall and turns to 
his troops.</sd>

<sp><speaker>VADER</speaker>
Commander, tear this ship apart until 
you've found those plans and bring 
me the Ambassador. I want her alive!</sp>

<sd>The stormtroopers scurry into the <name type="GPE">subhallway</name>s.</sd>

<setting>INT. REBEL BLOCKADE RUNNER - SUBHALLWAY</setting>

<sd>The lovely young girl huddles in a small alcove as the 
stormtroopers search through the ship. She is Princess <name type="PERSON">Leia</name> 
<name type="PERSON">Organa</name>, a member of the <name type="LOC">Alderaan</name> <name type="LOC">Senate</name>. The fear in her 
eyes slowly gives way to anger as the muted crushing sounds 
of the approaching stormtroopers grow louder. One of the 
troopers spots her.</sd>

<sp><speaker>TROOPER</speaker>
There she is! Set for stun!</sp>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Leia</name> steps from her hiding place and blasts a trooper with 
her laser pistol. She starts to run but is felled by a 
paralyzing ray. The troopers inspect her inert body.</sd>

<sp><speaker>TROOPER</speaker>
She'll be all right. Inform Lord 
<name type="PERSON">Vader</name> we have a prisoner.</sp>

<setting>INT. REBEL BLOCKADE RUNNER - SUBHALLWAY</setting>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Artoo</name> stops before the small hatch of an emergency <name type="PERSON">lifepod</name>. 
He snaps the seal on the main latch and a red warning light 
begins to flash. The stubby astro-robot works his way into 
the cramped four-man pod.</sd>

<sp><speaker><name type="ORG">THREEPIO</name></speaker>
Hey, you're not permitted in there. 
It's restricted. You'll be deactivated 
for sure..</sp>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Artoo</name> beeps something to him.</sd>

<sp><speaker><name type="ORG">THREEPIO</name></speaker>
Don't call me a mindless philosopher, 
you overweight glob of grease! Now 
come out before somebody sees you.</sp>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Artoo</name> whistles something at his reluctant friend regarding 
the mission he is about to perform.</sd>

<sp><speaker><name type="ORG">THREEPIO</name></speaker>
Secret mission? What plans? What are 
you talking about? I'm not getting 
in there!</sp>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Artoo</name> isn't happy with <name type="PERSON">Threepio</name>'s stubbornness, and he beeps 
and twangs angrily.</sd>

<sd>A new explosion, this time very close, sends <name type="GPE">dus</name>t and debris 
through the narrow <name type="GPE">subhallway</name>. Flames lick at <name type="PERSON">Threepio</name> and, 
after a flurry of electronic swearing from <name type="PERSON">Artoo</name>, the lanky 
robot jumps into the <name type="PERSON">lifepod</name>.</sd>

<sp><speaker><name type="ORG">THREEPIO</name></speaker>
I'm going to regret this.</sp>

<setting>INT. <name type="ORG">IMPERIAL</name> STARDESTROYER</setting>

<sd>On the main viewscreen, the <name type="PERSON">lifepod</name> carrying the two terrified 
robots speeds away from the stricken Rebel spacecraft.</sd>

<sp><speaker>CHIEF PILOT</speaker>
There goes another one.</sp>

<sp><speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
Hold your fire. There are no life 
forms. It must have been short-
circuited.</sp>

<setting>INT. LIFEPOD</setting>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Artoo</name> and <name type="PERSON">Threepio</name> look out at the receding <name type="ORG">Imperial</name> starship.  
Stars circle as the pod rotates through the galaxy.</sd>

<sp><speaker><name type="ORG">THREEPIO</name></speaker>
That's funny, the damage doesn't 
look as bad from out here.</sp>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Artoo</name> beeps an assuring response.</sd>

<sp><speaker><name type="ORG">THREEPIO</name></speaker>
Are you sure this things safe?</sp>

<setting>EXT. TATOOINE - ANCHORHEAD SETTLEMENT - POWER STATION - DAY</setting>

<sd>Heat waves radiate from the dozen or so bleached white 
buildings. <name type="PERSON">Luke</name> pilots his <name type="PERSON">Landspeeder</name> through the <name type="GPE">dus</name>ty 
empty street of the tiny settlement. An old woman runs to 
get out of the way of the speeding vehicle, shaking her fist 
at <name type="PERSON">Luke</name> as he flies past.</sd>

<sp><speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
I've told you kids to slow down!</sp>

<setting>INT. POWER STATION - DAY</setting>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Luke</name> bursts into the power station, waking The Fixer, a rugged 
mechanic and <name type="PERSON">Camie</name>, a sexy, disheveled girl who has been 
asleep in his lap. They grumbled as he races through the 
office, yelling wildly.</sd>

<sp><speaker>FIXER</speaker>
Did I hear a young noise blast through 
here?</sp>

<sp><speaker>CAMIE</speaker>
It was just wormie on another rampage.</sp>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Luke</name> bounces into a small room behind the office where <name type="PERSON">Deak</name> 
and <name type="PERSON">Windy</name>, two tough boys about the same age as <name type="PERSON">Luke</name>, are 
playing a computer pool-like game with <name type="PERSON">Biggs</name>, a burly, 
handsome boy a few years older than the rest. His flashy 
city attire is a sharp contrast to the loose-fitting tunics 
of the farm boys. A robot repairs some eq<name type="ORG">uip</name>ment in the 
background.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
Shape it up you guys!... <name type="PERSON">Biggs</name>?</sp>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Luke</name>'s surprise at the appearance of <name type="PERSON">Biggs</name> gives way to great 
joy and emotion. They give each other a great bear hug.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
I didn't know you were back! When 
did you get in?</sp>

<sp><speaker>BIGGS</speaker>
Just now. I wanted to surprise you, 
hot shot. I thought you'd be here... 
certainly didn't expect you to be 
out working.
(he laughs)</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
The Academy didn't change you 
much...but you're back so soon? Hey, 
what happened, didn't you get your 
commission?</sp>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Biggs</name> has an air of cool that seems slightly phony.</sd>

<sp><speaker>BIGGS</speaker>
Of course I got it. Signed aboard 
The Rand Ecliptic last week. First 
mate <name type="PERSON">Biggs</name> Darklighter at your 
service...
(he salutes)
...I just came to say good-bye to 
all you unfortunate landlocked 
simpletons.</sp>

<sd>Everyone laughs. The dazzling spectacle of his dashing friend 
is almost too much for <name type="PERSON">Luke</name>, but suddenly he snaps out of 
it.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
I almost forgot. There's a battle 
going on! Right here in our system. 
Come and look!</sp>

<sp><speaker>DEAK</speaker>
Not again! Forget it.</sp>

<setting>EXT. TATOOINE - ANCHORHEAD - SETTLEMENT - POWER STATION - DAY</setting>


<sd>The group stumbles out into the stifling desert sun. <name type="PERSON">Camie</name> 
and The Fixer complain and are forced to shade their eyes. 
<name type="PERSON">Luke</name> has his binoculars out scanning the heavens.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
There they are!</sp>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Biggs</name> takes the binoculars from <name type="PERSON">Luke</name> as the others strain to 
see something with the naked eye. Through the binoculars 
<name type="PERSON">Biggs</name> sees two small silver specks.</sd>

<sp><speaker>BIGGS</speaker>
That's no battle, hot shot... they're 
just sitting there! Probably a 
freighter-tanker refueling.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
But there was a lot of firing 
earlier...</sp>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Camie</name> grabs the binoculars away banging them against the 
building in the process. <name type="PERSON">Luke</name> grabs them.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
Hey, easy with those...</sp>

<sp><speaker>CAMIE</speaker>
Don't worry about it, Wormie.</sp>

<sd>The Fixer gives <name type="PERSON">Luke</name> a hard look and the young farm boy shrugs 
his shoulders in resignation.</sd>

<sp><speaker>FIXER</speaker>
I keep telling you, the Rebellion is 
a long way from here. I doubt if the 
<name type="ORG">Empire</name> would even fight to keep this 
system. Believe me <name type="PERSON">Luke</name>, this planet 
is a big hunk of nothing...</sp>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Luke</name> agrees, although it's obvious he isn't sure why. The 
group stumbles back into the power station, grumbling about 
<name type="PERSON">Luke</name>'s ineptitude.</sd>

<setting>INT. REBEL BLOCKADE RUNNER - HALLWAY</setting>

<sd>Princess <name type="PERSON">Leia</name> is led down a low-ceilinged hallway by a squad 
of armored stormtroopers. Her hands are bound and she is 
brutally shoved when she is unable to keep up with the briskly 
marching troops. They stop in a smoky hallway as Darth <name type="PERSON">Vader</name> 
emerges from the shadows. The sinister <name type="PERSON">Dark Lord</name> stares hard 
at the frail young <name type="PERSON">senator</name>, but she doesn't move.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LEIA</speaker>
<name type="PERSON">Lord <name type="PERSON">Vader</name></name>, I should have known. 
Only you could be so bold. The 
<name type="ORG">Imperial</name> <name type="LOC">Senate</name> will not sit for 
this, when they hear you've attacked 
a diplomatic...</sp>

<sp><speaker>VADER</speaker>
Don't play games with me, Your 
Highness. You weren't on any mercy 
mission this time. You passed directly 
through a restricted system. Several 
transmissions were beamed to this 
ship by Rebel spies. I want to know 
what happened to the plans they sent 
you.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LEIA</speaker>
I don't know what you're talking 
about. I'm a member of the <name type="ORG">Imperial</name> 
<name type="LOC">Senate</name> on a diplomatic mission to 
<name type="LOC">Alderaan</name>...</sp>

<sp><speaker>VADER</speaker>
You're a part of the Rebel Alliance... 
and a traitor. Take her away!</sp>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Leia</name> is marched away down the hallway and into the smoldering 
hole blasted in the side of the ship. An <name type="ORG">Imperial</name> Commander 
turns to <name type="PERSON">Vader</name>.</sd>

<sp><speaker>COMMANDER</speaker>
Holding her is dangerous. If word of 
this gets out, it could generate 
sympathy for the Rebellion in the 
senate.</sp>

<sp><speaker>VADER</speaker>
I have traced the Rebel spies to 
her. Now she is my only link to find 
their secret base!</sp>

<sp><speaker>COMMANDER</speaker>
She'll die before she tells you 
anything.</sp>

<sp><speaker>VADER</speaker>
Leave that to me. Send a distress 
signal and then inform the senate 
that all aboard were killed!</sp>

<sd>Another <name type="ORG">Imperial</name> Officer approaches <name type="PERSON">Vader</name> and the Commander. 
They stop and snap to attention.</sd>

<sp><speaker>SECOND OFFICER</speaker>
<name type="PERSON">Lord <name type="PERSON">Vader</name></name>, the battle station plans 
are not aboard this ship! And no 
transmissions were made. An escape 
pod was jettisoned during the 
fighting, but no life forms were 
aboard.</sp>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Vader</name> turns to the Commander.</sd>

<sp><speaker>VADER</speaker>
She must have hidden the plans in 
the escape pod. Send a detachment 
down to retrieve them. See to it 
personally, Commander. There'll be 
no one to stop us this time.</sp>

<sp><speaker>COMMANDER</speaker>
Yes, sir.</sp>

<setting>EXT. <name type="LOC">SPACE</name></setting>

<sd>The <name type="ORG">Imperial</name> Stardestroyer comes over the surface of the 
planet <name type="LOC">Tatooine</name>.</sd>

<setting>EXT. TATOOINE - DESERT</setting>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Jundland</name>, or "No Man's Land", where the rugged desert <name type="ORG">mesa</name>s 
meet the foreboding dune sea. The two helpless astro-<name type="NORP">droids</name> 
kick up clouds of sand as they leave the <name type="PERSON">lifepod</name> and clumsily 
work their way across the desert wasteland. The <name type="PERSON">lifepod</name> in 
the distance rests half buried in the sand.</sd>

<sp><speaker><name type="ORG">THREEPIO</name></speaker>
How did I get into this mess? I really 
don't know how. We seem to be made 
to suffer. It's our lot in life.</sp>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Artoo</name> answers with beeping sounds.</sd>

<sp><speaker><name type="ORG">THREEPIO</name></speaker>
I've got to rest before I fall apart. 
My joints are almost frozen.</sp>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Artoo</name> continues to respond with beeping sounds.</sd>

<sp><speaker><name type="ORG">THREEPIO</name></speaker>
What a desolate place this is.</sp>

<sd>Suddenly <name type="PERSON">Artoo</name> whistles, makes a sharp right turn and starts 
off in the direction of the rocky desert <name type="ORG">mesa</name>s. <name type="PERSON">Threepio</name> 
stops and yells at him.</sd>

<sp><speaker><name type="ORG">THREEPIO</name></speaker>
Where are you going?</sp>

<sd>A stream of electronic noises pours forth from the small 
robot.</sd>

<sp><speaker><name type="ORG">THREEPIO</name></speaker>
Well, I'm not going that way. It's 
much too rocky. This way is much 
easier.</sp>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Artoo</name> counters with a long whistle.</sd>

<sp><speaker><name type="ORG">THREEPIO</name></speaker>
What makes you think there are 
settlements over there?</sp>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Artoo</name> continues to make beeping sounds.</sd>

<sp><speaker><name type="ORG">THREEPIO</name></speaker>
Don't get technical with me.</sp>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Artoo</name> continues to make beeping sounds.</sd>

<sp><speaker><name type="ORG">THREEPIO</name></speaker>
What mission? What are you talking 
about? I've had just about enough of 
you! Go that way! You'll be 
malfunctioning within a day, you 
nearsighted scrap pile!</sp>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Threepio</name> gives the little robot a kick and starts off in the 
direction of the vast dune sea.</sd>

<sp><speaker><name type="ORG">THREEPIO</name></speaker>
And don't let me catch you following 
me begging for help, because you 
won't get it.</sp>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Artoo</name>'s reply is a rather rude sound. He turns and trudges 
off in the direction of the towering <name type="ORG">mesa</name>s.</sd>

<sp><speaker><name type="ORG">THREEPIO</name></speaker>
No more adventures. I'm not going 
that way.</sp>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Artoo</name> beeps to himself as he makes his way toward the distant 
mountains.</sd>

<setting>EXT. TATOOINE - DUNE SEA</setting>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Threepio</name>, hot and tired, struggles up over the ridge of a 
dune; only to find more dunes, which seem to go on for endless 
miles.  He looks back in the direction of the now distant 
rock <name type="ORG">mesa</name>s.</sd>

<sp><speaker><name type="ORG">THREEPIO</name></speaker>
That malfunctioning little twerp. 
This is all his fault! He tricked me 
into going this way, but he'll do no 
better.</sp>

<sd>In a huff of anger and frustration, <name type="PERSON">Threepio</name> knocks the sand 
from his joints. His plight seems hopeless, when a glint of 
reflected light in the distance reveals an object moving 
towards him.</sd>

<sp><speaker><name type="ORG">THREEPIO</name></speaker>
Wait, what's that? A transport! I'm 
saved!</sp>

<sd>The bronze android waves frantically and yells at the 
approaching transport.</sd>

<sp><speaker><name type="ORG">THREEPIO</name></speaker>
Over here! Help! Please, help!</sp>

<setting>EXT. TATOOINE - ANCHORHEAD SETTLEMENT - POWER STATION - DAY</setting>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Luke</name> and <name type="PERSON">Biggs</name> are walking and drinking a malt brew. Fixer 
and the others can be heard working inside.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
(Very animated)
...so I cut off my power, shut down 
the afterburners and came in low on 
<name type="PERSON">Deak</name>'s trail. I was so close I thought 
I was going to fry my instruments. 
As it was I busted up the <name type="ORG">Skyhopper</name> 
pretty bad. Uncle <name type="PERSON">Owen</name> was pretty 
upset. He grounded me for the rest 
of the season. You should have been 
there... it was fantastic.</sp>

<sp><speaker>BIGGS</speaker>
You ought to take it easy <name type="PERSON">Luke</name>. You 
may be the hottest bushpilot this 
side of <name type="PERSON">Mos Eisley</name>, but those little 
<name type="ORG">Skyhopper</name>s are dangerous. Keep it 
up, and one day, whammo, you're going 
to be nothing more than a dark spot 
on the down side of a canyon wall.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
Look who's talking. Now that you've 
been around those giant starships 
you're beginning to sound like my 
uncle. You've gotten soft in the 
city...</sp>

<sp><speaker>BIGGS</speaker>
I've missed you kid.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
Well, things haven't been the same 
since you left, <name type="PERSON">Biggs</name>. It's been 
so... quiet.</sp>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Biggs</name> looks around then leans close to <name type="PERSON">Luke</name>.</sd>

<sp><speaker>BIGGS</speaker>
<name type="PERSON">Luke</name>, I didn't come back just to say 
good-bye... I shouldn't tell you 
this, but you're the only one I can 
trust... and if I don't come back, I 
want somebody to know.</sp>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Luke</name>'s eyes are wide with <name type="PERSON">Biggs</name>' seriousness and loyalty.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
What are you talking about?</sp>

<sp><speaker>BIGGS</speaker>
I made some friends at the Academy.
(he whispers)
...when our frigate goes to one of 
the central systems, we're going to 
jump ship and join the Alliance...</sp>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Luke</name>, amazed and stunned, is almost speechless.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
Join the Rebellion?! Are you kidding! 
How?</sp>

<sp><speaker>BIGGS</speaker>
Quiet down will ya! You got a mouth 
bigger than a meteor crater!</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
I'm sorry. I'm quiet.
(he whispers)
Listen how quiet I am. You can barely 
hear me...</sp>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Biggs</name> shakes his head angrily and then continues.</sd>

<sp><speaker>BIGGS</speaker>
My friend has a friend on Bestine 
who might help us make contact.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
You're crazy! You could wander around 
forever trying to find them.</sp>

<sp><speaker>BIGGS</speaker>
I know it's a long shot, but if I 
don't find them I'll do what I can 
on my own... It's what we always 
talked about. <name type="PERSON">Luke</name>, I'm not going to 
wait for the <name type="ORG">Empire</name> to draft me into 
service. The Rebellion is spreading 
and I want to be on the right side -- 
the side I believe in.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
And I'm stuck here...</sp>

<sp><speaker>BIGGS</speaker>
I thought you were going to the 
Academy next term. You'll get your 
chance to get off this rock.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
Not likely! I had to cancel my 
application. There has been a lot of 
unrest among the Sandpeople since 
you left... they've even raided the 
outskirts of Anchorhead.</sp>

<sp><speaker>BIGGS</speaker>
Your uncle could hold off a whole 
colony of Sandpeople with one blaster.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
I know, but he's got enough vaporators 
going to make the place pay off. He 
needs me for just one more season. I 
can't leave him now.</sp>

<sp><speaker>BIGGS</speaker>
I feel for you, <name type="PERSON">Luke</name>, you're going 
to have to learn what seems to be 
important or what really is important. 
What good is all your uncle's work 
if it's taken over by the <name type="ORG">Empire</name>?... 
You know they're starting to 
nationalize commerce in the central 
systems... it won't be long before 
your uncle is merely a tenant, slaving 
for the greater glory of the <name type="ORG">Empire</name>.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
It couldn't happen here. You said it 
yourself. The <name type="ORG">Empire</name> won't bother 
with this rock.</sp>

<sp><speaker>BIGGS</speaker>
Things always change.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
I wish I was going... Are you going 
to be around long?</sp>

<sp><speaker>BIGGS</speaker>
No, I'm leaving in the morning...</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
Then I guess I won't see you.</sp>

<sp><speaker>BIGGS</speaker>
Maybe someday... I'll keep a lookout.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
Well, I'll be at the Academy next 
season... after that who knows. I 
won't be drafted into the <name type="ORG">Imperial</name> 
Starfleet that's for sure... Take 
care of yourself, you'll always be 
the best friend I've got.</sp>

<sp><speaker>BIGGS</speaker>
So long, <name type="PERSON">Luke</name>.</sp>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Biggs</name> turns away from his old friend and heads towards the 
power station.</sd>

<setting>EXT. TATOOINE - ROCK CANYON - SUNSET</setting>

<sd><name type="ORG">The gargantuan rock formations</name> are shrouded in a strange 
foreboding mist and the onimous sounds of unearthly creatures 
fill the air. <name type="PERSON">Artoo</name> moves cautiously through the creepy rock 
canyon, inadvertently making a loud clicking noise as he 
goes. He hears a distant, hard, metallic sound and stops for 
a moment. Convinced he is alone, he continues on his way.</sd>

<sd>In the distance, a pebble tumbles down the steep canyon wall 
and a small dark figure darts into the shadows. A little 
further up the canyon a slight flicker of light reveals a 
pair of eyes in the dark recesses only a few feet from the 
narrow path.</sd>

<sd>The unsuspecting robot waddles along the rugged trail until 
suddenly, out of nowhere, a powerful magnetic ray shoots out 
of the rocks and engulfs him in an eerie glow. He manages 
one short electronic squeak before he topples over onto his 
back. His bright computer lights flicker off, then on, then 
off again. Out of the rocks scurry three <name type="PERSON">Jawa</name>s, no taller 
than <name type="PERSON">Artoo</name>. They holster strange and complex weapons as they 
cautiously approach the robot. They wear grubby cloaks and 
their faces are shrouded so only their glowing eyes can be 
seen. They hiss and make odd guttural sounds as they heave 
the heavy robot onto their shoulders and carry him off down 
the trail.</sd>

<setting>EXT. TATOOINE - ROCK CANYON - SANDCRAWLER - SUNSET</setting>

<sd>The eight <name type="PERSON">Jawa</name>s carry <name type="PERSON">Artoo</name> out of the canyon to a huge tank-
like vehicle the size of a four-story house. They weld a 
small disk on the side of <name type="PERSON">Artoo</name> and then put him under a 
large tube on the side of the vehicle and the little robot 
is sucked into the giant machine.</sd>

<sd>The filthy little <name type="PERSON">Jawa</name>s scurry like rats up small ladders 
and enter the main cabin of the behemoth transport.</sd>

<setting>INT. SANDCRAWLER - HOLD AREA</setting>

<sd>It is dim inside the hold area of the <name type="ORG">Sandcrawler</name>. <name type="PERSON">Artoo</name> 
switches on a small floodlight on his forehead and stumbles 
around the scrap heap. The narrow beam swings across rusty 
metal rocket parts and an array of grotesquely twisted and 
maimed astro-robots. He lets out a pathetic electronic whimper 
and stumbles off toward what appears to be a door at the end 
of the chamber.</sd>

<setting>INT. SANDCRAWLER - PRISON AREA</setting>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Artoo</name> enters a wide room with a four-foot ceiling. In the 
middle of the scrap heap sit a dozen or so robots of various 
shapes and sizes. Some are engaged in electronic conversation, 
while others simply mill about. A voice of recognition calls 
out from the gloom.</sd>

<sp><speaker><name type="ORG">THREEPIO</name></speaker>
<name type="PERSON">Artoo</name>-Detoo! It's you! It's you!</sp>

<sd>A battered <name type="PERSON">Threepio</name> scrambles up to <name type="PERSON">Artoo</name> and embraces him.</sd>

<setting>EXT. TATOOINE - ROCK CANYON - SANDCRAWLER - SUNSET</setting>

<sd>The enormous <name type="ORG">Sandcrawler</name> lumbers off toward the magnificent 
twin suns, which are slowly setting over a distant mountain 
ridge.</sd>

<setting>EXT. TATOOINE - DESERT - DAY</setting>

<sd>Four <name type="ORG">Imperial</name> stormtroopers mill about in front of the half-
buried <name type="PERSON">lifepod</name> that brought <name type="PERSON">Artoo</name> and <name type="PERSON">Threepio</name> to <name type="LOC">Tatooine</name>. 
A trooper yells to an officer some distance away.</sd>

<sp><speaker>FIRST TROOPER</speaker>
Someone was in the pod. The tracks 
go off in this direction.</sp>

<sd>A second trooper picks a small bit of metal out of the sand 
and gives it to the first trooper.</sd>

<sp><speaker>SECOND TROOPER</speaker>
Look, sir -- <name type="NORP">droids</name>.</sp>

<setting>EXT. TATOOINE - DUNES</setting>

<sd>The <name type="ORG">Sandcrawler</name> moves slowly down a great sand dune.</sd>

<setting>INT. SANDCRAWLER</setting>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Threepio</name> and <name type="PERSON">Artoo</name> noisily bounce along inside the cramped 
prison chamber. <name type="PERSON">Artoo</name> appears to be shut off.</sd>

<sp><speaker><name type="ORG">THREEPIO</name></speaker>
Wake up! Wake up!</sp>

<sd>Suddenly the shaking and bouncing of the <name type="ORG">Sandcrawler</name> stops, 
creating quite a commotion among the mechanical men.  
<name type="PERSON">Threepio</name>'s fist bangs the head of <name type="PERSON">Artoo</name> whose computer lights 
pop on as he begins beeping. At the far end of the long 
chamber a hatch opens, filling the chamber with blinding 
white light. a dozen or so <name type="PERSON">Jawa</name>s make their way through the 
odd assortment of robots.</sd>

<sp><speaker><name type="ORG">THREEPIO</name></speaker>
We're doomed.</sp>

<sd>A <name type="PERSON">Jawa</name> starts moving toward them.</sd>

<sp><speaker><name type="ORG">THREEPIO</name></speaker>
Do you think they'll melt us down?</sp>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Artoo</name> responds, making beeping sounds.</sd>

<sp><speaker><name type="ORG">THREEPIO</name></speaker>
Don't shoot! Don't shoot! Will this 
never end?</sp>

<setting>EXT. TATOOINE - DESERT - LARS HOMESTEAD - AFTERNOON</setting>

<sd>The <name type="PERSON">Jawa</name>s mutter gibberish as they busily line up their 
battered captives, including <name type="PERSON">Artoo</name> and <name type="PERSON">Threepio</name>, in front of 
the enormous <name type="ORG">Sandcrawler</name>, which is parked beside a small 
homestead consisting of three large holes in the ground 
surrounded by several tall moisture vaporators and one small 
adobe block house.</sd>

<sd>The <name type="PERSON">Jawa</name>s scurry around fussing over the robots, straightening 
them up or brushing some <name type="GPE">dus</name>t from a dented metallic elbow. 
The shrouded little creatures smell horribly, attracting 
small insects to the dark areas when their mouths and nostrils 
should be.</sd>

<sd>Out of the shadows of a dingy side-building limps <name type="PERSON">Owen</name> Lars, 
a large burly man in his mid-fifties. His reddish eyes are 
sunken in a <name type="GPE">dus</name>t-covered face. As the farmer carefully 
inspects each robot, he is closely followed by his slump- 
shouldered nephew, <name type="PERSON">Luke</name> <name type="PERSON">Skywalker</name>. One of the vile little 
<name type="PERSON">Jawa</name>s walks ahead of the farmer spouting an animated sales 
pitch in a queer, unintelligible language.</sd>

<sd>A voice calls out from one of the huge holes that form the 
homestead. <name type="PERSON">Luke</name> goes over to the edge and sees his <name type="PERSON">Aunt Beru</name> 
standing in the main courtyard.</sd>

<sp><speaker>BERU</speaker>
<name type="PERSON">Luke</name>, tell <name type="PERSON">Owen</name> that if he gets a 
translator to be sure it speaks Bocce.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
It looks like we don't have much of 
a choice but I'll remind him.</sp>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Luke</name> returns to his uncle as they look over the eq<name type="ORG">uip</name>ment 
for sale with the <name type="PERSON">Jawa</name> leader.</sd>

<sp><speaker><name type="ORG">OWEN</name></speaker>
I have no need for a protocol droid.</sp>

<sp><speaker><name type="ORG">THREEPIO</name></speaker>
(quickly)
Sir -- not in an environment such as 
this -- that's why I've also been 
programmed for over thirty secondary 
functions that...</sp>

<sp><speaker><name type="ORG">OWEN</name></speaker>
What I really need is a droid that 
understands the binary language of 
moisture vaporators.</sp>

<sp><speaker><name type="ORG">THREEPIO</name></speaker>
Vaporators! Sir -- My first job was 
programming binary load lifter... 
very similar to your vaporators. You 
could say...</sp>

<sp><speaker><name type="ORG">OWEN</name></speaker>
Do you speak Bocce?</sp>

<sp><speaker><name type="ORG">THREEPIO</name></speaker>
Of course I can, sir. It's like a 
second language for me... I'm as 
fluent in Bocce...</sp>

<sp><speaker><name type="ORG">OWEN</name></speaker>
All right shut up!
(turning to <name type="PERSON">Jawa</name>)
I'll take this one.</sp>

<sp><speaker><name type="ORG">THREEPIO</name></speaker>
Shutting up, sir.</sp>

<sp><speaker><name type="ORG">OWEN</name></speaker>
<name type="PERSON">Luke</name>, take these two over to the 
garage, will you? I want you to have 
both of them cleaned up before dinner.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
But I was going into Toshi Station 
to pick up some power converters...</sp>

<sp><speaker><name type="ORG">OWEN</name></speaker>
You can waste time with your friends 
when your chores are done. Now come 
on, get to it!</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
All right, come on! And the red one, 
come on. Well, come on, Red, let's 
go.</sp>

<sd>As the <name type="PERSON">Jawa</name>s start to lead the three remaining robots back 
into the <name type="ORG">Sandcrawler</name>, <name type="PERSON">Artoo</name> lets out a pathetic little beep 
and starts after his old friend <name type="PERSON">Threepio</name>. He is restrained 
by a slimy <name type="PERSON">Jawa</name>, who zaps him with a control box.</sd>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Owen</name> is negotiating with the head <name type="PERSON">Jawa</name>. <name type="PERSON">Luke</name> and the two 
robots start off for the garage when a plate pops off the 
head of the red astro-droid's head plate and it sparks wildly.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
Uncle <name type="PERSON">Owen</name>...</sp>

<sp><speaker><name type="ORG">OWEN</name></speaker>
Yeah?</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
This R2 unit has a bad motivator. 
Look!</sp>

<sp><speaker><name type="ORG">OWEN</name></speaker>
(to the head <name type="PERSON">Jawa</name>)
Hey, what're you trying to push on 
us?</sp>

<sd>The <name type="PERSON">Jawa</name> goes into a loud spiel. Meanwhile, <name type="PERSON">Artoo</name> has sneaked 
out of line and is moving up and down trying to attract 
attention. He lets out with a low whistle. <name type="PERSON">Threepio</name> taps 
<name type="PERSON">Luke</name> on the shoulder.</sd>

<sp><speaker><name type="ORG">THREEPIO</name></speaker>
(pointing to <name type="PERSON">Artoo</name>)
Excuse me, sir, but that R2 unit is 
in prime condition. A real bargain.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
Uncle <name type="PERSON">Owen</name>...</sp>

<sp><speaker><name type="ORG">OWEN</name></speaker>
Yeah?</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
What about that one?</sp>

<sp><speaker><name type="ORG">OWEN</name></speaker>
(to <name type="PERSON">Jawa</name>)
What about that blue one? We'll take 
that one.</sp>

<sd>With a little reluctance the scruffy dwarf trades the damaged 
astro-droid for <name type="PERSON">Artoo</name>.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
Yeah, take it away.</sp>

<sp><speaker><name type="ORG">THREEPIO</name></speaker>
Uh, I'm quite sure you'll be very 
pleased with that one, sir. He really 
is in first-class condition. I've 
worked with him before. Here he comes.</sp>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Owen</name> pays off the whining <name type="PERSON">Jawa</name> as <name type="PERSON">Luke</name> and the two robots 
trudge off toward a grimy homestead entry.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
Okay, let's go.</sp>

<sp><speaker><name type="ORG">THREEPIO</name></speaker>
(to <name type="PERSON">Artoo</name>)
Now, don't you forget this! Why I 
should stick my neck out for you is 
quite beyond my capacity!</sp>

<setting>INT. LARS HOMESTEAD - GARAGE AREA - LATE AFTERNOON</setting>

<sd>The garage is cluttered and worn, but a friendly peaceful 
atmosphere permeates the low grey chamber. <name type="PERSON">Threepio</name> lowers 
himself into a large tub filled with warm oil. Near the 
battered <name type="PERSON">Landspeeder</name> little <name type="PERSON">Artoo</name> rests on a large battery 
with a cord to his face.</sd>

<sp><speaker><name type="ORG">THREEPIO</name></speaker>
Thank the maker! This oil bath is 
going to feel so good. I've got such 
a bad case of <name type="GPE">dus</name>t contamination, I 
can barely move!</sp>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Artoo</name> beeps a muffled reply. <name type="PERSON">Luke</name> seems to be lost in thought 
as he runs his hand over the damaged fin of a small two-man 
<name type="ORG">Skyhopper</name> spaceship resting in a low hangar off the garage. 
Finally <name type="PERSON">Luke</name>'s frustrations get the better of him and he 
slams a wrench across the workbench.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
It just isn't fair. Oh, <name type="PERSON">Biggs</name> is 
right. I'm never gonna get out of 
here!</sp>

<sp><speaker><name type="ORG">THREEPIO</name></speaker>
Is there anything I might do to help?</sp>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Luke</name> glances at the battered robot. A bit of his anger drains 
and a tiny smile creeps across his face.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
Well, not unless you can alter time, 
speed up the harvest, or teleport me 
off this rock!</sp>

<sp><speaker><name type="ORG">THREEPIO</name></speaker>
I don't think so, sir. I'm only a 
droid and not very knowledgeable 
about such things. Not on this planet, 
anyways. As a matter of fact, I'm 
not even sure which planet I'm on.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
Well, if there's a bright center to 
the universe, you're on the planet 
that it's farthest from.</sp>

<sp><speaker><name type="ORG">THREEPIO</name></speaker>
I see, sir.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
Uh, you can call me <name type="PERSON">Luke</name>.</sp>

<sp><speaker><name type="ORG">THREEPIO</name></speaker>
I see, sir <name type="PERSON">Luke</name>.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
(laughing)
Just <name type="PERSON">Luke</name>.</sp>

<sp><speaker><name type="ORG">THREEPIO</name></speaker>
And I am See-<name type="PERSON">Threepio</name>, human-cyborg 
relations, and this is my counterpart, 
<name type="PERSON">Artoo</name>-Detoo.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
Hello.</sp>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Artoo</name> beeps in response. <name type="PERSON">Luke</name> unplugs <name type="PERSON">Artoo</name> and begins to 
scrape several connectors on the robot's head with a chrome 
pick. <name type="PERSON">Threepio</name> climbs out of the oil tub and begins wiping 
oil from his bronze body.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
You got a lot of carbon scoring here. 
It looks like you boys have seen a 
lot of action.</sp>

<sp><speaker><name type="ORG">THREEPIO</name></speaker>
With all we've been through, sometimes 
I'm amazed we're in as good condition 
as we are, what with the Rebellion 
and all.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
You know of the Rebellion against 
the <name type="ORG">Empire</name>?</sp>

<sp><speaker><name type="ORG">THREEPIO</name></speaker>
That's how we came to be in your 
service, if you take my meaning, 
sir.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
Have you been in many battles?</sp>

<sp><speaker><name type="ORG">THREEPIO</name></speaker>
Several, I think. Actually, there's 
not much to tell. I'm not much more 
than an interpreter, and not very 
good at telling stories. Well, not 
at making them interesting, anyways.</sp>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Luke</name> struggles to remove a small metal fragment from <name type="PERSON">Artoo</name>'s 
neck joint. He uses a larger pick.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
Well, my little friend, you've got 
something jammed in here real good. 
Were you on a cruiser or...</sp>

<sd>The fragment breaks loose with a snap, sending <name type="PERSON">Luke</name> tumbling 
head over heels. He sits up and sees a twelve-inch three-
dimensional hologram of <name type="PERSON">Leia</name> <name type="PERSON">Organa</name>, the Rebel <name type="PERSON">senator</name>, being 
projected from the face of little <name type="PERSON">Artoo</name>. The image is a 
rainbow of colors as it flickers and jiggles in the dimly 
lit garage. <name type="PERSON">Luke</name>'s mouth hangs open in awe.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LEIA</speaker>
Help me, Obi-Wan <name type="PERSON">Kenobi</name>. You're my 
only hope.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
What's this?</sp>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Artoo</name> looks around and sheepishly beeps an answer for <name type="PERSON">Threepio</name> 
to translate. <name type="PERSON">Leia</name> continues to repeat the sentence fragment 
over and over.</sd>

<sp><speaker><name type="ORG">THREEPIO</name></speaker>
What is what?!? He asked you a 
question...
(pointing to <name type="PERSON">Leia</name>)
What is that?</sp>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Artoo</name> whistles his surprise as he pretends to just notice 
the hologram. He looks around and sheepishly beeps an answer 
for <name type="PERSON">Threepio</name> to translate. <name type="PERSON">Leia</name> continues to repeat the 
sentence fragment over and over.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LEIA</speaker>
Help me, Obi-Wan <name type="PERSON">Kenobi</name>. You're my 
only hope. Help me, Obi-Wan <name type="PERSON">Kenobi</name>. 
You're my only hope.</sp>

<sp><speaker><name type="ORG">THREEPIO</name></speaker>
Oh, he says it's nothing, sir. Merely 
a malfunction. Old data. Pay it no 
mind.</sp>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Luke</name> becomes intrigued by the beautiful girl.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
Who is she? She's beautiful.</sp>

<sp><speaker><name type="ORG">THREEPIO</name></speaker>
I'm afraid I'm not quite sure, sir.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LEIA</speaker>
Help me, Obi-Wan <name type="PERSON">Kenobi</name>...</sp>

<sp><speaker><name type="ORG">THREEPIO</name></speaker>
I think she was a passenger on our 
last voyage. A person of some 
importance, sir -- I believe. Our 
captain was attached to...</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
Is there more to this recording?</sp>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Luke</name> reaches out for <name type="PERSON">Artoo</name> but he lets out several frantic 
squeaks and a whistle.</sd>

<sp><speaker><name type="ORG">THREEPIO</name></speaker>
Behave yourself, <name type="PERSON">Artoo</name>. You're going 
to get us in trouble. It's all right, 
you can trust him. He's our new 
master.</sp>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Artoo</name> whistles and beeps a long message to <name type="PERSON">Threepio</name>.</sd>

<sp><speaker><name type="ORG">THREEPIO</name></speaker>
He says he's the property of Obi-Wan 
<name type="PERSON">Kenobi</name>, a resident of these parts. 
And it's a private message for him. 
Quite frankly, sir I don't know what 
he's talking about. Our last master 
was Captain <name type="PERSON">Antilles</name>, but with what 
we've been through, this little R2 
unit has become a bit eccentric.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
Obi-Wan <name type="PERSON">Kenobi</name>? I wonder if he means 
old <name type="PERSON">Ben</name> <name type="PERSON">Kenobi</name>?</sp>

<sp><speaker><name type="ORG">THREEPIO</name></speaker>
I beg your pardon, sir, but do you 
know what he's talking about?</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
Well, I don't know anyone named Obi-
Wan, but old <name type="PERSON">Ben</name> lives out beyond 
the dune sea. He's kind of a strange 
old hermit.</sp>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Luke</name>'s gazes at the beautiful young princess for a few 
moments.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
I wonder who she is. It sounds like 
she's in trouble. I'd better play 
back the whole thing.</sp>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Artoo</name> beeps something to <name type="PERSON">Threepio</name>.</sd>

<sp><speaker><name type="ORG">THREEPIO</name></speaker>
He says the restraining bolt has 
short circuited his recording system. 
He suggests that if you remove the 
bolt, he might be able to play back 
the entire recording.</sp>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Luke</name> looks longingly at the lovely, little princess and hasn't 
really heard what <name type="PERSON">Threepio</name> has been saying.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
H'm? Oh, yeah, well, I guess you're 
too small to run away on me if I 
take this off! Okay.</sp>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Luke</name> takes a wedged bar and pops the restraining bolt off 
<name type="PERSON">Artoo</name>'s side.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
There you go.</sp>

<sd>The princess immediately disappears...</sd>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
Well, wait a minute. Where'd she go? 
Bring her back! Play back the entire 
message.</sp>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Artoo</name> beeps an innocent reply as <name type="PERSON">Threepio</name> sits up in 
embarrassment.</sd>

<sp><speaker><name type="ORG">THREEPIO</name></speaker>
What message? The one you're carrying 
inside your rusty innards!</sp>

<sd>A women's voice calls out from another room.</sd>

<sp><speaker>AUNT BERU</speaker>
<name type="PERSON">Luke</name>? <name type="PERSON">Luke</name>! Come to dinner!</sp>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Luke</name> stands up and shakes his head at the malfunctioning 
robot.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
All right, I'll be right there, Aunt 
Beru.</sp>

<sp><speaker><name type="ORG">THREEPIO</name></speaker>
I'm sorry, sir, but he appears to 
have picked up a slight flutter.</sp>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Luke</name> tosses <name type="PERSON">Artoo</name>'s restraining bolt on the workbench and 
hurries out of the room.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
Well, see what you can do with him. 
I'll be right back.</sp>

<sp><speaker><name type="ORG">THREEPIO</name></speaker>
(to <name type="PERSON">Artoo</name>)
Just you reconsider playing that 
message for him.</sp>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Artoo</name> beeps in response.</sd>

<sp><speaker><name type="ORG">THREEPIO</name></speaker>
No, I don't think he likes you at 
all.</sp>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Artoo</name> beeps.</sd>

<sp><speaker><name type="ORG">THREEPIO</name></speaker>
No, I don't like you either.</sp>

<setting>INT. LARS HOMESTEAD - DINING AREA</setting>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Luke</name>'s <name type="PERSON">Aunt Beru</name>, a warm, motherly woman, fills a pitcher 
with blue fluid from a refrigerated container in the well-
used kitchen. She puts the pitcher on a tray with some bowls 
of food and starts for the dining area.</sd>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Luke</name> sits with his Uncle <name type="PERSON">Owen</name> before a table covered with 
steaming bowls of food as <name type="PERSON">Aunt Beru</name> carries in a bowl of red 
grain.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
You know, I think that R2 unit we 
bought might have been stolen.</sp>

<sp><speaker><name type="ORG">OWEN</name></speaker>
What makes you think that?</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
Well, I stumbled across a recording 
while I was cleaning him. He says he 
belongs to someone called Obi-Wan 
<name type="PERSON">Kenobi</name>.</sp>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Owen</name> is greatly alarmed at the mention of his name, but 
manages to control himself.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
I thought he might have meant old 
<name type="PERSON">Ben</name>. Do you know what he's talking 
about? Well, I wonder if he's related 
to <name type="PERSON">Ben</name>.</sp>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Owen</name> breaks loose with a fit of uncontrolled anger.</sd>

<sp><speaker><name type="ORG">OWEN</name></speaker>
That old man's just a crazy old 
wizard. Tomorrow I want you to take 
that R2 unit into Anchorhead and 
have its memory flushed. That'll be 
the end of it. It belongs to us now.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
But what if this Obi-Wan comes looking 
for him?</sp>

<sp><speaker><name type="ORG">OWEN</name></speaker>
He won't, I don't think he exists 
any more. He died about the same 
time as your father.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
He knew my father?</sp>

<sp><speaker><name type="ORG">OWEN</name></speaker>
I told you to forget it. Your only 
concern is to prepare the new <name type="NORP">droids</name> 
for tomorrow. In the morning I want 
them on the south ridge working out 
those condensers.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
Yes, sir. I think those new <name type="NORP">droids</name> 
are going to work out fine. In fact, 
I, uh, was also thinking about our 
agreement about my staying on another 
season. And if these new <name type="NORP">droids</name> do 
work out, I want to transmit my 
application to the Academy this year.</sp>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Owen</name>'s face becomes a scowl, although he tries to suppress 
it.</sd>

<sp><speaker><name type="ORG">OWEN</name></speaker>
You mean the next semester before 
harvest?</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
Sure, there're more than enough 
<name type="NORP">droids</name>.</sp>

<sp><speaker><name type="ORG">OWEN</name></speaker>
Harvest is when I need you the most. 
Only one more season. This year we'll 
make enough on the harvest so I'll 
be able to hire some more hands. And 
then you can go to the Academy next 
year.</sp>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Luke</name> continues to toy with his food, not looking at his uncle.</sd>

<sp><speaker><name type="ORG">OWEN</name></speaker>
You must understand I need you here, 
<name type="PERSON">Luke</name>.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
But it's a whole 'nother year.</sp>

<sp><speaker><name type="ORG">OWEN</name></speaker>
Look, it's only one more season.</sp>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Luke</name> pushes his half-eaten plate of food aside and stands.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
Yeah, that's what you said last year 
when <name type="PERSON">Biggs</name> and Tank left.</sp>

<sp><speaker>AUNT BERU</speaker>
Where are you going?</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
It looks like I'm going nowhere. I 
have to finish cleaning those <name type="NORP">droids</name>.</sp>

<sd>Resigned to his fate, <name type="PERSON">Luke</name> paddles out of the room. <name type="PERSON">Owen</name> 
mechanically finishes his dinner.</sd>

<sp><speaker>AUNT BERU</speaker>
<name type="PERSON">Owen</name>, he can't stay here forever. 
Most of his friends have gone. It 
means so much to him.</sp>

<sp><speaker><name type="ORG">OWEN</name></speaker>
I'll make it up to him next year. I 
promise.</sp>

<sp><speaker>AUNT BERU</speaker>
<name type="PERSON">Luke</name>'s just not a farmer, <name type="PERSON">Owen</name>. He 
has too much of his father in him.</sp>

<sp><speaker><name type="ORG">OWEN</name></speaker>
That's what I'm afraid of.</sp>

<setting>EXT. TATOOINE - LARS HOMESTEAD</setting>

<sd>The giant twin suns of <name type="LOC">Tatooine</name> slowly disappear behind a 
distant dune range. <name type="PERSON">Luke</name> stands watching them for a few 
moments, then reluctantly enters the doomed entrance to the 
homestead.</sd>

<setting>INT. LARS HOMESTEAD - GARAGE</setting>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Luke</name> enters the garage to discover the robots nowhere in 
sight. He takes a small control box from his utility belt 
similar to the one the <name type="PERSON">Jawa</name>s were carrying. He activates the 
box, which creates a low hum, and <name type="PERSON">Threepio</name>, letting out a 
short yell, pops up from behind the <name type="ORG">Skyhopper</name> spaceship.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
What are you doing hiding there?</sp>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Threepio</name> stumbles forward, but <name type="PERSON">Artoo</name> is still nowhere in 
sight.</sd>

<sp><speaker><name type="ORG">THREEPIO</name></speaker>
It wasn't my fault, sir. Please don't 
deactivate me. I told him not to go, 
but he's faulty, malfunctioning; 
kept babbling on about his mission.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
Oh, no!</sp>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Luke</name> races out of the garage followed by <name type="PERSON">Threepio</name>.</sd>

<setting>EXT. TATOOINE - LARS HOMESTEAD</setting>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Luke</name> rushes out of the small doomed entry to the homestead 
and searches the darkening horizon for the small triped astro-
robot. <name type="PERSON">Threepio</name> struggles out of the homestead and on the 
salt flat as <name type="PERSON">Luke</name> scans the landscape with his 
electrobinoculars.</sd>

<sp><speaker><name type="ORG">THREEPIO</name></speaker>
That R2 unit has always been a 
problem. These astro-<name type="NORP">droids</name> are 
getting quite out of hand. Even I 
can't understand their logic at times.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
How could I be so stupid? He's nowhere 
in sight. Blast it!</sp>

<sp><speaker><name type="ORG">THREEPIO</name></speaker>
Pardon me, sir, but couldn't we go 
after him?</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
It's too dangerous with all the 
Sandpeople around. We'll have to 
wait until morning.</sp>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Owen</name> yells up from the homestead plaza.</sd>

<sp><speaker><name type="ORG">OWEN</name></speaker>
<name type="PERSON">Luke</name>, I'm shutting the power down 
for the night.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
All right, I'll be there in a few 
minutes. Boy, am I gonna get it.</sp>

<sd>He takes one final look across the dim horizon.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
You know that little droid is going 
to cause me a lot of trouble.</sp>

<sp><speaker><name type="ORG">THREEPIO</name></speaker>
Oh, he excels at that, sir.</sp>

<setting>INT. LARS HOMESTEAD - PLAZA</setting>

<sd>Morning slowly creeps into the sparse but sparkling oasis of 
the open courtyard. The idyll is broken be the yelling of 
Uncle <name type="PERSON">Owen</name>, his voice echoing throughout the homestead.</sd>

<sp><speaker><name type="ORG">OWEN</name></speaker>
<name type="PERSON">Luke</name>? <name type="PERSON">Luke</name>? <name type="PERSON">Luke</name>? Where could he be 
loafing now!</sp>

<setting>INT. LARS HOMESTEAD - <name type="GPE">KI</name>TCHEN</setting>

<sd>The interior of the kitchen is a worm glow as <name type="PERSON">Aunt Beru</name> 
prepares the morning breakfast. <name type="PERSON">Owen</name> enters in a huff.</sd>

<sp><speaker><name type="ORG">OWEN</name></speaker>
Have you seen <name type="PERSON">Luke</name> this morning?</sp>

<sp><speaker>AUNT BERU</speaker>
He said he had some things to do 
before he started today, so he left 
early.</sp>

<sp><speaker><name type="ORG">OWEN</name></speaker>
Uh? Did he take those two new <name type="NORP">droids</name> 
with him?</sp>

<sp><speaker>AUNT BERU</speaker>
I think so.</sp>

<sp><speaker><name type="ORG">OWEN</name></speaker>
Well, he'd better have those units 
in the south range repaired be midday 
or there'll be hell to pay!</sp>

<setting>EXT. TATOOINE - DESERT WASTELAND - LUKE'S SPEEDER - DAY</setting>

<sd>The rock and sand of the desert floor are a blur as <name type="PERSON">Threepio</name> 
pilots the sleek <name type="PERSON">Landspeeder</name> gracefully across the vast 
wasteland.</sd>

<setting>INT./EXT. LUKE'S SPEEDER - DESERT WASTELAND - TRAVELING - DAY</setting>


<sd><name type="PERSON">Luke</name> leans over the back of the speeder and adjusts something 
in the motor compartment.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
(yelling)
How's that.</sp>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Threepio</name> signals that is fine and <name type="PERSON">Luke</name> turns back into the 
wind-whipped cockpit and pops the canopy shut.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
Old <name type="PERSON">Ben</name> <name type="PERSON">Kenobi</name> lives out in this 
direction somewhere, but I don't see 
how that R2 unit could have come 
this far. We must have missed him. 
Uncle <name type="PERSON">Owen</name> isn't going to take this 
very well.</sp>

<sp><speaker><name type="ORG">THREEPIO</name></speaker>
Sir, would it help if you told him 
it was my fault.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
(brightening)
Sure. He needs you. He'd probably 
only deactivate you for a day or 
so...</sp>

<sp><speaker><name type="ORG">THREEPIO</name></speaker>
Deactivate! Well, on the other hand 
if you hadn't removed his restraining 
bolt...</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
Wait, there's something dead ahead 
on the scanner. It looks like our 
droid... hit the accelerator.</sp>

<setting>EXT. TATOOINE - ROCK MESA - DUNE SEA - COASTLINE - DAY</setting>

<sd>From high on a rock <name type="ORG">mesa</name>, the tiny <name type="PERSON">Landspeeder</name> can be seen 
gliding across the desert floor. Suddenly in the foreground 
two weather-beaten Sandpeople shrouded in their grimy desert 
cloaks peer over the edge of the rock <name type="ORG">mesa</name>. One of the 
marginally human creatures raises a long ominous laser rifle 
and points it at the speeder but the second creature grabs 
the gun before it can be fired.</sd>

<sd>The Sandpeople, or <name type="GPE">Tusken</name> <name type="PERSON">Raider</name>s as they're sometimes called, 
speak in a coarse barbaric language as they get into an 
animated argument. The second <name type="GPE">Tusken</name> <name type="PERSON">Raider</name> seems to get in 
the final word and the nomads scurry over the rocky terrain.</sd>

<setting>EXT. TATOOINE - ROCK MESA - CANYON</setting>

<sd>The <name type="GPE">Tusken</name> <name type="PERSON">Raider</name> approaches two large Banthas standing tied 
to a rock. The monstrous, bear-like creatures are as large 
as elephants, with huge red eyes, tremendous looped horns, 
and long, furry, dinosaur-like tails. The <name type="GPE">Tusken</name> <name type="PERSON">Raider</name>s 
mount saddles strapped to the huge creatures' shaggy backs 
and ride off down the rugged bluff.</sd>

<setting>EXT. TATOOINE - ROCK CANYON - FLOOR</setting>

<sd>The speeder is parked on the floor of a massive canyon. <name type="PERSON">Luke</name>, 
with his long laser rifle slung over his shoulder, stands 
before little <name type="PERSON">Artoo</name>.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
Hey, whoa, just where do you think 
you're going?</sp>

<sd>The little droid whistles a feeble reply, as <name type="PERSON">Threepio</name> poses 
menacingly behind the little runaway.</sd>

<sp><speaker><name type="ORG">THREEPIO</name></speaker>
Master <name type="PERSON">Luke</name> here is your rightful 
owner. We'll have no more of this 
Obi-Wan <name type="PERSON">Kenobi</name> jibberish... and don't 
talk to me about your mission, either. 
You're fortunate he doesn't blast 
you into a million pieces right here.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
Well, come on. It's getting late. I 
only hope we can get back before 
Uncle <name type="PERSON">Owen</name> really blows up.</sp>

<sp><speaker><name type="ORG">THREEPIO</name></speaker>
If you don't mind my saying so, sir, 
I think you should deactivate the 
little fugitive until you've gotten 
him back to your workshop.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
No, he's not going to try anything.</sp>

<sd>Suddenly the little robot jumps to life with a mass of frantic 
whistles and screams.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
What's wrong with him now?</sp>

<sp><speaker><name type="ORG">THREEPIO</name></speaker>
Oh my... sir, he says there are 
several creatures approaching from 
the southeast.</sp>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Luke</name> swings his rifle into position and looks to the south.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
Sandpeople! Or worst! Come on, let's 
have a look. Come on.</sp>

<setting>EXT. TATOOINE - ROCK CANYON - RIDGE - DAY</setting>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Luke</name> carefully makes his way to the top of a rock ridge and 
scans the canyon with his electrobinoculars. He spots the 
two riderless Banthas. <name type="PERSON">Threepio</name> struggles up behind the young 
adventurer.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
There are two Banthas down there but 
I don't see any... wait a second, 
they're Sandpeople all right. I can 
see one of them now.</sp>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Luke</name> watches the distant <name type="GPE">Tusken</name> <name type="PERSON">Raider</name> through his 
electrobinoculars. Suddenly something huge moves in front of 
his field of view. Before <name type="PERSON">Luke</name> or <name type="PERSON">Threepio</name> can react, a large, 
gruesome <name type="GPE">Tusken</name> <name type="PERSON">Raider</name> looms over them. <name type="PERSON">Threepio</name> is startled 
and backs away, right off the side if the cliff. He can be 
heard for several moments as he clangs, bangs and rattles 
down the side of the mountain.</sd>

<sd>The towering creature brings down his curved, double-pointed 
gaderffii -- the dreaded axe blade that has struck terror in 
the heart of the local settlers. But <name type="PERSON">Luke</name> manages to block 
the blow with his laser rifle, which is smashed to pieces. 
The terrified farm boy scrambles backward until he is forced 
to the edge of a deep crevice. The sinister <name type="PERSON">Raider</name> stands 
over him with his weapon raised and lets out a horrible 
shrieking laugh.</sd>

<setting>EXT. TATOOINE - ROCK CANYON - FLOOR - DAY</setting>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Artoo</name> forces himself into the shadows of a small alcove in 
the rocks as the vicious Sandpeople walk past carrying the 
inert <name type="PERSON">Luke</name> <name type="PERSON">Skywalker</name>, who is dropped in a heap before the 
speeder.  The Sandpeople ransack the speeder, throwing parts 
and supplies in all directions. Suddenly they stop. Then 
everything is quiet for a few moments. A great howling moan 
is heard echoing throughout the canyon which sends the 
Sandpeople fleeing in terror.</sd>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Artoo</name> moves even tighter into the shadows as the slight 
swishing sound that frightened off the Sandpeople grows even 
closer, until a shabby old desert-rat-of-a-man appears and 
leans over <name type="PERSON">Luke</name>. His ancient leathery face, cracked and 
weathered by exotic climates is set off by dark, penetrating 
eyes and a scraggly white beard. <name type="PERSON">Ben</name> <name type="PERSON">Kenobi</name> squints his eyes 
as he scrutinizes the unconscious farm boy. <name type="PERSON">Artoo</name> makes a 
slight sound and <name type="PERSON">Ben</name> turns and looks right at him.</sd>

<sp><speaker>BEN</speaker>
Hello there! Come here my little 
friend. Don't be afraid.</sp>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Artoo</name> waddles over to were <name type="PERSON">Luke</name> lies crumpled in a heap and 
begins to whistle and beep his concern. <name type="PERSON">Ben</name> puts his hand on 
<name type="PERSON">Luke</name>'s forehead and he begins to come around.</sd>

<sp><speaker>BEN</speaker>
Don't worry, he'll be all right.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
What happened?</sp>

<sp><speaker>BEN</speaker>
Rest easy, son, you've had a busy 
day. You're fortunate you're still 
in one piece.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
<name type="PERSON">Ben</name>? <name type="PERSON">Ben</name> <name type="PERSON">Kenobi</name>! Boy, am I glad to 
see you!</sp>

<sp><speaker>BEN</speaker>
The <name type="PERSON">Jundland</name> wastes are not to be 
traveled lightly. Tell me young <name type="PERSON">Luke</name>, 
what brings you out this far?</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
Oh, this little droid! I think he's 
searching for his former master... 
I've never seen such devotion in a 
droid before... there seems to be no 
stopping him. He claims to be the 
property of an Obi-Wan <name type="PERSON">Kenobi</name>. Is he 
a relative of yours? Do you know who 
he's talking about?</sp>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Ben</name> ponders this for a moment, scratching his scruffy beard.</sd>

<sp><speaker>BEN</speaker>
Obi-Wan <name type="PERSON">Kenobi</name>... Obi-Wan? Now thats 
a name I haven't heard in a long 
time... a long time.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
I think my uncle knew him. He said 
he was dead.</sp>

<sp><speaker>BEN</speaker>
Oh, he's not dead, not... not yet.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
You know him!</sp>

<sp><speaker>BEN</speaker>
Well of course, of course I know 
him. He's me! I haven't gone by the 
name Obi-Wan since oh, before you 
were born.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
Then the droid does belong to you.</sp>

<sp><speaker>BEN</speaker>
Don't seem to remember ever owning a 
droid. Very interesting...</sp>

<sd>He suddenly looks up at the overhanging cliffs.</sd>

<sp><speaker>BEN</speaker>
I think we better get indoors. The 
Sandpeople are easily startled but 
they will soon be back and in greater 
numbers.</sp>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Luke</name> sits up and rubs his head. <name type="PERSON">Artoo</name> lets out a pathetic 
beep causing <name type="PERSON">Luke</name> to remember something. He looks around.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
<name type="PERSON">Threepio</name>!</sp>

<setting>EXT. TATOOINE - SAND PIT - ROCK MESA - DAY</setting>

<sd>Little <name type="PERSON">Artoo</name> stands at the edge of a large sand pit and begins 
to chatter away in electronic whistles and beeps. <name type="PERSON">Luke</name> and 
<name type="PERSON">Ben</name> stand over a very dented and tangled <name type="PERSON">Threepio</name> lying half 
buried in the sand. One of his arms has broken off.</sd>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Luke</name> tries to revive the inert robot by shaking him and then 
flips a hidden switch on his back several times until finally 
the mechanical man's systems turn on.</sd>

<sp><speaker><name type="ORG">THREEPIO</name></speaker>
Where am I? I must have taken a bad 
step...</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
Can you stand? We've got to get out 
of here before the Sandpeople return.</sp>

<sp><speaker><name type="ORG">THREEPIO</name></speaker>
I don't think I can make it. You go 
on, Master <name type="PERSON">Luke</name>. There's no sense in 
you risking yourself on my account. 
I'm done for.</sp>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Artoo</name> makes a beeping sound.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
No, you're not. What kind of talk is 
that?</sp>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Luke</name> and <name type="PERSON">Ben</name> help the battered robot to his feet. Little 
<name type="PERSON">Artoo</name> watches from the top of the pit. <name type="PERSON">Ben</name> glances around 
suspiciously. Sensing something, he stands up and sniffs the 
air.</sd>

<sp><speaker>BEN</speaker>
Quickly, son... they're on the move.</sp>

<setting>INT. KENOBI'S DWELLING</setting>

<sd>The small, spartan hovel is cluttered with desert junk but 
still manages to radiate an air of time-worn comfort and 
security. <name type="PERSON">Luke</name> is in one corner repairing <name type="PERSON">Threepio</name>'s arm, as 
old <name type="PERSON">Ben</name> sits thinking.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
No, my father didn't fight in the 
wars. He was a navigator on a spice 
freighter.</sp>

<sp><speaker>BEN</speaker>
That's what your uncle told you. He 
didn't hold with your father's ideals. 
Thought he should have stayed here 
and not gotten involved.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
You fought in the Clone Wars?</sp>

<sp><speaker>BEN</speaker>
Yes, I was once a Jedi Knight the 
same as your father.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
I wish I'd known him.</sp>

<sp><speaker>BEN</speaker>
He was the best star-pilot in the 
galaxy, and a cunning warrior. I 
understand you've become quite a 
good pilot yourself. And he was a 
good friend. Which reminds me...</sp>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Ben</name> gets up and goes to a chest where he rummages around.  
As <name type="PERSON">Luke</name> finishes repairing <name type="PERSON">Threepio</name> and starts to fit the 
restraining bolt back on, <name type="PERSON">Threepio</name> looks at him nervously.  
<name type="PERSON">Luke</name> thinks about the bolt for a moment then puts it on the 
table. <name type="PERSON">Ben</name> shuffles up and presents <name type="PERSON">Luke</name> with a short handle 
with several electronic gadgets attached to it.</sd>

<sp><speaker>BEN</speaker>
I have something here for you. Your 
father wanted you to have this when 
you were old enough, but your uncle 
wouldn't allow it. He feared you 
might follow old Obi-Wan on some 
damned-fool idealistic crusade like 
your father did.</sp>

<sp><speaker><name type="ORG">THREEPIO</name></speaker>
Sir, if you'll not be needing me, 
I'll close down for awhile.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
Sure, go ahead.</sp>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Ben</name> hands <name type="PERSON">Luke</name> the saber.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
What is it?</sp>

<sp><speaker>BEN</speaker>
Your fathers lightsaber. This is the 
weapon of a Jedi Knight. Not as clumsy 
or as random as a blaster.</sp>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Luke</name> pushes a button on the handle. A long beam shoots out 
about four feet and flickers there. The light plays across 
the ceiling.</sd>

<sp><speaker>BEN</speaker>
An elegant weapon for a more civilized 
time. For over a thousand generations 
<name type="FAC">the Jedi</name> <name type="ORG">Knights</name> were the guardians 
of peace and justice in the Old 
Republic. Before the dark times, 
before the <name type="ORG">Empire</name>.</sp>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Luke</name> hasn't really been listening.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
How did my father die?</sp>

<sp><speaker>BEN</speaker>
A young Jedi named Darth <name type="PERSON">Vader</name>, who 
was a pupil of mine until he turned 
to evil, helped the <name type="ORG">Empire</name> hunt down 
and destroy <name type="FAC">the Jedi</name> <name type="ORG">Knights</name>. He 
betrayed and murdered your father. 
Now <name type="FAC">the Jedi</name> are all but extinct. 
<name type="PERSON">Vader</name> was seduced by the dark side 
of the <name type="ORG">Force</name>.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
The <name type="ORG">Force</name>?</sp>

<sp><speaker>BEN</speaker>
Well, the <name type="ORG">Force</name> is what gives a Jedi 
his power. It's an energy field 
created by all living things. It 
surrounds us and penetrates us. It 
binds the galaxy together.</sp>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Artoo</name> makes beeping sounds.</sd>

<sp><speaker>BEN</speaker>
Now, let's see if we can't figure 
out what you are, my little friend. 
And where you come from.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
I saw part of the message he was...</sp>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Luke</name> is cut short as the recorded image of the beautiful 
young Rebel princess is projected from <name type="PERSON">Artoo</name>'s face.</sd>

<sp><speaker>BEN</speaker>
I seem to have found it.</sp>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Luke</name> stops his work as the lovely girl's image flickers before 
his eyes.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LEIA</speaker>
General <name type="PERSON">Kenobi</name>, years ago you served 
my father in the Clone Wars. Now he 
begs you to help him in his struggle 
against the <name type="ORG">Empire</name>. I regret that I 
am unable to present my father's 
request to you in person, but my 
ship has fallen under attack and I'm 
afraid my mission to bring you to 
<name type="LOC">Alderaan</name> has failed. I have placed 
information vital to the survival of 
the Rebellion into the memory systems 
of this R2 unit. My father will know 
how to retrieve it. You must see 
this droid safely delivered to him 
on <name type="LOC">Alderaan</name>. This is our most 
desperate hour. Help me, Obi-Wan 
<name type="PERSON">Kenobi</name>, you're my only hope.</sp>

<sd>There is a little static and the transmission is cut short.  
Old <name type="PERSON">Ben</name> leans back and scratches his head. He silently puffs 
on a tarnished chrome water pipe. <name type="PERSON">Luke</name> has stars in his eyes.</sd>

<sp><speaker>BEN</speaker>
You must learn the ways of the <name type="ORG">Force</name> 
if you're to come with me to <name type="LOC">Alderaan</name>.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
(laughing)
<name type="LOC">Alderaan</name>? I'm not going to <name type="LOC">Alderaan</name>. 
I've got to go home. It's late, I'm 
in for it as it is.</sp>

<sp><speaker>BEN</speaker>
I need your help, <name type="PERSON">Luke</name>. She needs 
your help. I'm getting too old for 
this sort of thing.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
I can't get involved! I've got work 
to do! It's not that I like the 
<name type="ORG">Empire</name>. I hate it! But there's nothing 
I can do about it right now. It's 
such a long way from here.</sp>

<sp><speaker>BEN</speaker>
That's your uncle talking.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
(sighing)
Oh, God, my uncle. How am I ever 
going to explain this?</sp>

<sp><speaker>BEN</speaker>
Learn about the <name type="ORG">Force</name>, <name type="PERSON">Luke</name>.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
Look, I can take you as far as 
Anchorhead. You can get a transport 
there to <name type="PERSON">Mos Eisley</name> or wherever you're 
going.</sp>

<sp><speaker>BEN</speaker>
You must do what you feel is right, 
of course.</sp>

<setting>EXT. <name type="LOC">SPACE</name>.</setting>

<sd>An <name type="ORG">Imperial</name> Stardestroyer heads toward the evil planet-like 
battle station: the <name type="ORG">Death Star</name>!</sd>

<setting>INT. DEATH STAR - CONFERENCE ROOM</setting>

<sd>Eight <name type="ORG">Imperial</name> <name type="PERSON">senator</name>s and generals sit around a black 
conference table. <name type="ORG">Imperial</name> stormtroopers stand guard around 
the room. Commander <name type="PERSON">Tagge</name>, a young, slimy-looking general, 
is speaking.</sd>

<sp><speaker>TAGGE</speaker>
Until this battle station is fully 
operational we are vulnerable. The 
Rebel Alliance is too well eq<name type="ORG">uip</name>ped. 
They're more dangerous than you 
realize.</sp>

<sd>The bitter Admiral <name type="PERSON">Motti</name> twists nervously in his chair.</sd>

<sp><speaker>MOTTI</speaker>
Dangerous to your starfleet, 
Commander, not to this battle station!</sp>

<sp><speaker>TAGGE</speaker>
The Rebellion will continue to gain 
a support in the <name type="ORG">Imperial</name> <name type="LOC">Senate</name> as 
long as....</sp>

<sd>Suddenly all heads turn as Commander <name type="PERSON">Tagge</name>'s speech is cut 
short and the <name type="ORG">Grand <name type="PERSON">Moff <name type="PERSON">Tarkin</name></name></name>, governor of the <name type="ORG">Imperial</name> 
outland regions, enters. He is followed by his powerful ally, 
The Sith Lord, Darth <name type="PERSON">Vader</name>. All of the generals stand and 
bow before the thin, evil-looking governor as he takes his 
place at the head of the table. The <name type="PERSON">Dark Lord</name> stands behind 
him.</sd>

<sp><speaker>TAR<name type="GPE">KI</name>N</speaker>
The <name type="ORG">Imperial</name> <name type="LOC">Senate</name> will no longer 
be of any concern to us. I've just 
received word that <name type="FAC">the Emperor</name> has 
dissolved the council permanently. 
The last remnants of the Old Republic 
have been swept away.</sp>

<sp><speaker>TAGGE</speaker>
That's impossible! How will the 
Emperor maintain control without the 
bureaucracy?</sp>

<sp><speaker>TAR<name type="GPE">KI</name>N</speaker>
The regional governors now have direct 
control over territories. Fear will 
keep the local systems in line. Fear 
of this battle station.</sp>

<sp><speaker>TAGGE</speaker>
And what of the Rebellion? If the 
<name type="ORG">Rebels</name> have obtained a complete 
technical readout of this station, 
it is possible, however unlikely, 
that they might find a weakness and 
exploit it.</sp>

<sp><speaker>VADER</speaker>
The plans you refer to will soon be 
back in our hands.</sp>

<sp><speaker>MOTTI</speaker>
Any attack made by the <name type="ORG">Rebels</name> against 
this station would be a useless 
gesture, no matter what technical 
data they've obtained. This station 
is now the ultimate power in the 
universe. I suggest we use it!</sp>

<sp><speaker>VADER</speaker>
Don't be too proud of this 
technological terror you've 
constructed. The ability to destroy 
a planet is insignificant next to 
the power of the <name type="ORG">Force</name>.</sp>

<sp><speaker>MOTTI</speaker>
Don't try to frighten us with your 
sorcerer's ways, <name type="PERSON">Lord <name type="PERSON">Vader</name></name>. Your 
sad devotion to that ancient religion 
has not helped you conjure up the 
stolen data tapes, or given you 
clairvoyance enough to find the 
Rebel's hidden fort...</sp>

<sd>Suddenly <name type="PERSON">Motti</name> chokes and starts to turn blue under <name type="PERSON">Vader</name>'s 
spell.</sd>

<sp><speaker>VADER</speaker>
I find your lack of faith disturbing.</sp>

<sp><speaker>TAR<name type="GPE">KI</name>N</speaker>
Enough of this! <name type="PERSON">Vader</name>, release him!</sp>

<sp><speaker>VADER</speaker>
As you wish.</sp>

<sp><speaker>TAR<name type="GPE">KI</name>N</speaker>
This bickering is pointless. Lord 
<name type="PERSON">Vader</name> will provide us with the 
location of the Rebel fortress by 
the time this station is operational. 
We will then crush the Rebellion 
with one swift stroke.</sp>

<setting>EXT. TATOOINE - WASTELAND</setting>

<sd>The speeder stops before what remains of the huge <name type="PERSON">Jawa</name>s 
<name type="ORG">Sandcrawler</name>. <name type="PERSON">Luke</name> and <name type="PERSON">Ben</name> walk among the smoldering rubble 
and scattered bodies.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
It looks like Sandpeople did this, 
all right. Look, here are Gaffi 
sticks, Bantha tracks. It's just... 
I never heard of them hitting anything 
this big before.</sp>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Ben</name> is crouching in the sand studying the tracks.</sd>

<sp><speaker>BEN</speaker>
They didn't. But we are meant to 
think they did. These tracks are 
side by side. Sandpeople always ride 
single file to hide there numbers.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
These are the same <name type="PERSON">Jawa</name>s that sold 
us <name type="PERSON">Artoo</name> and <name type="PERSON">Threepio</name>.</sp>

<sp><speaker>BEN</speaker>
And these blast points, too accurate 
for Sandpeople. Only <name type="ORG">Imperial</name> 
stormtroopers are so precise.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
Why would <name type="ORG">Imperial</name> troops want to 
slaughter <name type="PERSON">Jawa</name>s?</sp>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Luke</name> looks back at the speeder where <name type="PERSON">Artoo</name> and <name type="PERSON">Threepio</name> are 
inspecting the dead <name type="PERSON">Jawa</name>s, and put two and two together.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
If they traced the robots here, they 
may have learned who they sold them 
to. And that would lead them home!</sp>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Luke</name> reaches a sudden horrible realization, then races for 
the speeder and jumps it.</sd>

<sp><speaker>BEN</speaker>
Wait, <name type="PERSON">Luke</name>! It's too dangerous.</sp>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Luke</name> races off leaving <name type="PERSON">Ben</name> and the two robots alone with the 
burning <name type="ORG">Sandcrawler</name>.</sd>

<setting>EXT. TATOOINE - WASTELAND</setting>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Luke</name> races across the wasteland in his battered <name type="PERSON">Landspeeder</name>.</sd>

<setting>EXT. TATOOINE - LARS HOMESTEAD</setting>

<sd>The speeder roars up to the burning homestead. <name type="PERSON">Luke</name> jumps 
out and runs to the smoking holes that were once his home. 
Debris is scattered everywhere and it looks as if a great 
battle has taken place.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
Uncle <name type="PERSON">Owen</name>! <name type="PERSON">Aunt Beru</name>! Uncle <name type="PERSON">Owen</name>!</sp>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Luke</name> stumbles around in a daze looking for his aunt and uncle. 
Suddenly he comes upon their smoldering remains. He is 
stunned, and cannot speak. Hate replaces fear and a new 
resolve comes over him.</sd>

<setting>EXT. <name type="LOC">SPACE</name></setting>

<sd><name type="ORG">Imperial</name> <name type="ORG">TIE</name> fighter races toward the <name type="ORG">Death Star</name>.</sd>

<setting>INT. DEATH STAR - DE<name type="ORG">TEN</name>TION CORRIDOR</setting>

<sd>Two stormtroopers open an electronic cell door and allow 
several <name type="ORG">Imperial</name> guards to enter. Princess <name type="PERSON">Leia</name>'s face is 
filled with defiance, which slowly gives way to fear as a 
giant black torture robot enters, followed by Darth <name type="PERSON">Vader</name>.</sd>

<sp><speaker>VADER</speaker>
And, now Your Highness, we will 
discuss the location of your hidden 
Rebel base.</sp>

<sd>The torture robot gives off a steady beeping sound as it 
approaches Princess <name type="PERSON">Leia</name> and extends one of its mechanical 
arms bearing a large hypodermic needle. The door slides shut 
and the long cell block hallway appears peaceful. The muffled 
screams of the Rebel princess are barely heard.</sd>

<setting>EXT. TATOOINE - WASTELAND</setting>

<sd>There is a large bonfire of <name type="PERSON">Jawa</name> bodies blazing in front of 
the <name type="ORG">Sandcrawler</name> as <name type="PERSON">Ben</name> and the robots finish burning the 
dead.  <name type="PERSON">Luke</name> drives up in the speeder and <name type="PERSON">Ben</name> walks over to 
him.</sd>

<sp><speaker>BEN</speaker>
There's nothing you could have done, 
<name type="PERSON">Luke</name>, had you been there. You'd have 
been killed, too, and the <name type="NORP">droids</name> 
would be in the hands of the <name type="ORG">Empire</name>.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
I want to come with you to <name type="LOC">Alderaan</name>. 
There's nothing here for me now. I 
want to learn the ways of the <name type="ORG">Force</name> 
and become a Jedi like my father.</sp>

<setting>EXT. TATOOINE - WASTELAND</setting>

<sd>The <name type="PERSON">Landspeeder</name> with <name type="PERSON">Luke</name>, <name type="PERSON">Artoo</name>, <name type="PERSON">Threepio</name>, and <name type="PERSON">Ben</name> in it 
zooms across the desert. The speeder stops on a bluff 
overlooking the spaceport at <name type="PERSON">Mos Eisley</name>. It is a haphazard 
array of low, grey, concrete structures and semi-domes. A 
harsh gale blows across the stark canyon floor. <name type="PERSON">Luke</name> adjusts 
his goggles and walks to the edge of the craggy bluff where 
<name type="PERSON">Ben</name> is standing.</sd>

<sp><speaker>BEN</speaker>
<name type="PERSON">Mos Eisley</name> Spaceport. You will never 
find a more wretched hive of scum 
and villainy. We must be cautious.</sp>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Ben</name> looks over at <name type="PERSON">Luke</name>, who gives the old Jedi a determined 
smile.</sd>

<setting>EXT. TATOOINE - MOS EISLEY - STREET</setting>

<sd>The speeder is stopped on a crowded street by several combat-
hardend stormtroopers who look over the two robots. A <name type="ORG">Trooper</name> 
questions <name type="PERSON">Luke</name>.</sd>

<sp><speaker>TROOPER</speaker>
How long have you had these <name type="NORP">droids</name>?</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
About three or four seasons.</sp>

<sp><speaker>BEN</speaker>
They're for sale if you want them.</sp>

<sp><speaker>TROOPER</speaker>
Let me see your identification.</sp>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Luke</name> becomes very nervous as he fumbles to find his ID while 
<name type="PERSON">Ben</name> speaks to the <name type="ORG">Trooper</name> in a very controlled voice.</sd>

<sp><speaker>BEN</speaker>
You don't need to see his 
identification.</sp>

<sp><speaker>TROOPER</speaker>
We don't need to see his 
identification.</sp>

<sp><speaker>BEN</speaker>
These are not the <name type="NORP">droids</name> your looking 
for.</sp>

<sp><speaker>TROOPER</speaker>
These are not the <name type="NORP">droids</name> we're looking 
for.</sp>

<sp><speaker>BEN</speaker>
He can go about his business.</sp>

<sp><speaker>TROOPER</speaker>
You can go about your business.</sp>

<sp><speaker>BEN</speaker>
(to <name type="PERSON">Luke</name>)
Move along.</sp>

<sp><speaker>TROOPER</speaker>
Move along. Move along.</sp>

<setting>EXT. TATOOINE - MOS EISLEY - STREET</setting>

<sd>The speeder pulls up in front of a rundown blockhouse cantina 
on the outskirts of the spaceport. Various strange forms of 
transport, including several unusual beasts of burden, are 
parked outside the bar. A <name type="PERSON">Jawa</name> runs up and begins to fondle 
the speeder.</sd>

<sp><speaker><name type="ORG">THREEPIO</name></speaker>
I can't abide these <name type="PERSON">Jawa</name>s. Disgusting 
creatures.</sp>

<sd>As <name type="PERSON">Luke</name> gets out of the speeder he tries to shoo the <name type="PERSON">Jawa</name> 
away.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
Go on, go on. I can't understand how 
we got by those troopers. I thought 
we were dead.</sp>

<sp><speaker>BEN</speaker>
The <name type="ORG">Force</name> can have a strong influence 
on the weak-minded. You will find it 
a powerful ally.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
Do you really think we're going to 
find a pilot here that'll take us to 
<name type="LOC">Alderaan</name>?</sp>

<sp><speaker>BEN</speaker>
Well, most of the best freighter 
pilots can be found here. Only watch 
your step. This place can be a little 
rough.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
I'm ready for anything.</sp>

<sp><speaker><name type="ORG">THREEPIO</name></speaker>
Come along, <name type="PERSON">Artoo</name>.</sp>

<setting>INT. TATOOINE - MOS EISLEY - CANTINA</setting>

<sd>The young adventurer and his two mechanical servants follow 
<name type="PERSON">Ben</name> <name type="PERSON">Kenobi</name> into the smoke-filled cantina. The murky, moldy 
den is filled with a startling array of weird and exotic 
alien creatures and monsters at the long metallic bar. At 
first the sight is horrifying. One-eyed, thousand-eyed, slimy, 
furry, scaly, tentacled, and clawed creatures huddle over 
drinks. <name type="PERSON">Ben</name> moves to an empty spot at the bar near a group 
of repulsive but human scum. A huge, rough-looking Bartender 
stops <name type="PERSON">Luke</name> and the robots.</sd>

<sp><speaker>BAR<name type="ORG">TEN</name>DER</speaker>
We don't serve their kind here!</sp>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Luke</name> still recovering from the shock of seeing so many 
outlandish creatures, doesn't quite catch the bartender's 
drift.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
What?</sp>

<sp><speaker>BAR<name type="ORG">TEN</name>DER</speaker>
Your <name type="NORP">droids</name>. They'll have to wait 
outside. We don't want them here.</sp>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Luke</name> looks at old <name type="PERSON">Ben</name>, who is busy talking to one of the 
<name type="NORP">Galactic</name> pirates. He notices several of the gruesome creatures 
along the bar are giving him a very unfriendly glare.</sd>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Luke</name> pats <name type="PERSON">Threepio</name> on the shoulder.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
Listen, why don't you wait out by 
the speeder. We don't want any 
trouble.</sp>

<sp><speaker><name type="ORG">THREEPIO</name></speaker>
I heartily agree with you sir.</sp>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Threepio</name> and his stubby partner go outside and most of the 
creatures at the bar go back to their drinks.</sd>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Ben</name> is standing next to <name type="PERSON">Chewbacca</name>, an eight-foot-tall savage-
looking creature resembling a huge grey bushbaby monkey with 
fierce baboon-like fangs. His large blue eyes dominate a fur-
covered face and soften his otherwise awesome appearance.  
Over his matted, furry body he wears two chrome bandoliers, 
and little else. He is a two-hundred-year-old <name type="NORP">Wookiee</name> and a 
sight to behold.</sd>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Ben</name> speaks to the <name type="NORP">Wookiee</name>, pointing to <name type="PERSON">Luke</name> several times 
during his conversation and the huge creature suddenly lets 
out a horrifying laugh. <name type="PERSON">Luke</name> is more than a little bit 
disconcerted and pretends not to hear the conversation between 
<name type="PERSON">Ben</name> and the giant <name type="NORP">Wookiee</name>.</sd>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Luke</name> is terrified but tries not to show it. He quietly sips 
his drink, looking over the crowd for a more sympathetic ear 
or whatever.</sd>

<sd>A large, multiple-eyed Creature gives <name type="PERSON">Luke</name> a rough shove.</sd>

<sp><speaker>CREATURE</speaker>
Negola dewaghi wooldugger?!?</sp>

<sd>The hideous freak is obviously drunk. <name type="PERSON">Luke</name> tries to ignore 
the creature and turns back on his drink. A short, grubby 
Human and an even smaller rodent-like beast join the 
belligerent monstrosity.</sd>

<sp><speaker>HUMAN</speaker>
He doesn't like you.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
I'm sorry.</sp>

<sp><speaker>HUMAN</speaker>
I don't like you either.</sp>

<sd>The big creature is getting agitated and yells out some 
unintelligible gibberish at the now rather nervous, young 
adventurer.</sd>

<sp><speaker>HUMAN</speaker>
Don't insult us. You just watch 
yourself. We're wanted men. I have 
the death sentence in twelve systems.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
I'll be careful than.</sp>

<sp><speaker>HUMAN</speaker>
You'll be dead.</sp>

<sd>The rodent lets out a loud grunt and everything at the bar 
moves away. <name type="PERSON">Luke</name> tries to remain cool but it isn't easy. His 
three adversaries ready their weapons. Old <name type="PERSON">Ben</name> moves in behind 
<name type="PERSON">Luke</name>.</sd>

<sp><speaker>BEN</speaker>
This little one isn't worth the 
effort. Come let me buy you 
something...</sp>

<sd>A powerful blow from the unpleasant creature sends the young 
would-be Jedi sailing across the room, crashing through tables 
and breaking a large jug filled with a foul-looking liquid. 
With a blood curdling shriek, the monster draws a wicked 
chrome laser pistol from his belt and levels it at old <name type="PERSON">Ben</name>. 
The bartender panics.</sd>

<sp><speaker>BAR<name type="ORG">TEN</name>DER</speaker>
No blasters! No blaster!</sp>

<sd>With astounding agility old <name type="PERSON">Ben</name>'s laser sword sparks to life 
and in a flash an arm lies on the floor. The rodent is cut 
in two and the giant multiple-eyed creature lies doubled, 
cut from chin to <name type="PERSON">groin</name>. <name type="PERSON">Ben</name> carefully and precisely turns 
off his laser sword and replaces it on his utility belt. 
<name type="PERSON">Luke</name>, shaking and totally amazed at the old man's abilities, 
attempts to stand. The entire fight has lasted only a matter 
of seconds. The cantina goes back to normal, although <name type="PERSON">Ben</name> is 
given a respectable amount of room at the bar. <name type="PERSON">Luke</name>, rubbing 
his bruised head, approaches the old man with new awe. <name type="PERSON">Ben</name> 
points the the <name type="NORP">Wookiee</name>.</sd>

<sp><speaker>BEN</speaker>
This is <name type="PERSON">Chewbacca</name>. He's first-mate 
on a ship that might suit our needs.</sp>

<setting>EXT. TATOOINE - MOS EISLEY - STREET</setting>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Threepio</name> paces in front of the cantina as <name type="PERSON">Artoo</name> carries on 
an electronic conversation with another little red astro-
droid. A creature comes out of the cantina and approaches 
two stormtroopers in the street.</sd>

<sp><speaker><name type="ORG">THREEPIO</name></speaker>
I don't like the look of this.</sp>

<setting>INT. TATOOINE - MOS EISLEY - CANTINA</setting>

<sd>Strange creatures play exotic big band music on odd-looking 
instruments as <name type="PERSON">Luke</name>, still giddy, downs a fresh drink and 
follows <name type="PERSON">Ben</name> and <name type="PERSON">Chewbacca</name> to a booth where <name type="PERSON">Han</name> <name type="PERSON">Solo</name> is 
sitting. <name type="PERSON">Han</name> is a tough, roguish starpilot about thirty years 
old. A mercenary on a starship, he is simple, sentimental, 
and cocksure.</sd>

<sp><speaker>HAN</speaker>
<name type="PERSON">Han</name> <name type="PERSON">Solo</name>. I'm captain of the 
Millennium <name type="ORG">Falcon</name>. <name type="PERSON">Chewie</name> here tells 
me you're looking for passage to the 
<name type="LOC">Alderaan</name> system.</sp>

<sp><speaker>BEN</speaker>
Yes, indeed. If it's a fast ship.</sp>

<sp><speaker>HAN</speaker>
Fast ship? You've never heard of the 
Millennium <name type="ORG">Falcon</name>?</sp>

<sp><speaker>BEN</speaker>
Should I have?</sp>

<sp><speaker>HAN</speaker>
It's the ship that made the Kessel 
run in less than twelve parsecs!</sp>

<sd><name type="PERSON">Ben</name> reacts to <name type="PERSON">Solo</name>'s stupid attempt to impress them with 
obvious misinformation.</sd>

<sp><speaker>HAN</speaker>
I've outrun <name type="ORG">Imperial</name> starships, not 
the local bulk-cruisers, mind you. 
I'm talking about the big <name type="NORP">Corellian</name> 
ships now. She's fast enough for 
you, old man. What's the cargo?</sp>

<sp><speaker>BEN</speaker>
Only passengers. Myself, the boy, 
two <name type="NORP">droids</name>, and no questions asked.</sp>

<sp><speaker>HAN</speaker>
What is it? Some kind of local 
trouble?</sp>
