<?xml-model href="sw_schema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<root>
 <title>Star Wars: Episode VI - Return of the Jedi (1983)</title>
by <writer>Lawrence Kasdan &amp; George Lucas</writer>


<script>The boundless heavens <verb lemma="serve">serve</verb> as a back-drop for the MAIN TITLE, followed 
by a ROLL-UP, which crawls into infinity.

<subTitle epNum="6">EPISODE 6 RETURN OF THE JEDI</subTitle>

<crawl>Luke Skywalker <verb lemma="have">has</verb> returned to his home planet of Tatooine in an 
<verb lemma="attempt">attempt</verb> to <verb lemma="rescue">rescue</verb> his friend Han Solo from the <verb lemma="clutch">clutches</verb> of the vile 
gangster Jabba the Hutt. Little does Luke <verb lemma="know">know</verb> that the GALACTIC EMPIRE 
<verb lemma="have">has</verb> secretly begun construction on a new armored space <verb lemma="station">station</verb> even 
more powerful than the first dreaded Death Star. When completed, this 
ultimate weapon will <verb lemma="spell">spell</verb> certain doom for the small band of Rebels 
<verb lemma="struggle">struggling</verb> to restore freedom to the galaxy...</crawl>

<sd>PAN DOWN to <verb lemma="reveal">reveal</verb> a monstrous half-completed Death Star, its massive 
superstructure curling away from the completed section <verb lemma="like">like</verb> the arms of 
a giant octopus. Beyond, in benevolent contrast, floats the small, 
green moon of ENDOR.</sd>

<sd>An Imperial Star Destroyer moves overhead toward the massive armored 
space station, followed by two zipping TIE fighters. A small Imperial 
shuttle rockets from the main bay of the <verb lemma="ship">ship</verb> and hustles toward the 
Death Star.</sd>

<setting>2    INT IMPERIAL SHUTTLE - COCKPIT </setting>
The shuttle captain makes contact with the Death Star.

<sp><speaker>SHUTTLE CAPTAIN</speaker>
Command station, this <verb lemma="be">is</verb> ST 321. Code Clearance Blue. We're starting 
our approach. <verb lemma="deactivate">Deactiv<verb lemma="eat">ate</verb></verb> the security shield.</sp>

<sp><speaker>DEATH STAR CONTROLLER	(filtered VO)</speaker>
The security deflector <verb lemma="shield">shield</verb> will <verb lemma="be">be</verb> deactivated when we <verb lemma="have">have</verb> 
confirmation of your code transmission. <verb lemma="stand">Stand</verb> by... You <verb lemma="be">are</verb> <verb lemma="clear">clear</verb> to 
proceed.</sp>

<sp><speaker>SHUTTLE CAPTAIN</speaker>
We're starting our approach.</sp>

<setting>3    INT DEATH STAR - CONTROL ROOM</setting>

<sd>Operators <verb lemma="move">move</verb> about among the <verb lemma="control">control</verb> panels. A SHIELD OPERATOR hits 
switches beside a large screen, on which <verb lemma="be">is</verb> a disp<verb lemma="lay">lay</verb> of the Death 
Star, the moon Endor, and a bright web <verb lemma="delineate">delineating</verb> the invisible 
deflector shield.</sd>

<sd>A <verb lemma="control">control</verb> officer rushes over to the <verb lemma="shield">shield</verb> operator.</sd>

<sp><speaker>OFFICER</speaker>
<verb lemma="inform">Inform</verb> the commander that Lord Vader's shuttle <verb lemma="have">has</verb> arrived.</sp>

<sp><speaker>OPERATOR</speaker>
Yes, sir.</sp>

<sd>The <verb lemma="control">control</verb> officer moves to a view port and watches as the Imperial 
shuttle lands in the massive docking bay. A squad of Imperial 
stormtroopers moves into formation before the craft.</sd>

<setting>4    INT DEATH STAR - MAIN DOCKING BAY</setting>

<sd>The DEATH STAR COMMANDER, MOFF JERJERROD, a tall, confident technocrat, 
strides through the assembled troops to the base of the shuttle ramp. 
The troops <verb lemma="snap">snap</verb> to attention; many <verb lemma="be">are</verb> uneasy about the new arrival. 
But the Death Star commander stands arrogantly tall.</sd>

<sd>The <verb lemma="exit">exit</verb> hatch of the shuttle opens with a WHOOSH, revealing only 
darkness. Then, heavy FOOTSTEPS AND MECHANICAL BREATHING. From this 
black void appears DARTH VADER, LORD OF THE SITH. Vader looks over the 
assemblage as he walks down the ramp.</sd>

<sp><speaker>JERJERROD</speaker>
Lord Vader, this <verb lemma="be">is</verb> an unexpected pleasure. We're honored by your 
presence.</sp>

<sp><speaker>VADER</speaker>
You may <verb lemma="dispense">disp<verb lemma="en">en</verb>se</verb> with the pleasantries, Commander. I'm here to <verb lemma="put">put</verb> you 
<verb lemma="back">back</verb> on
schedule.</sp>

<sd>The commander turns ashen and begins to shake.</sd>

<sp><speaker>JERJERROD</speaker>
I <verb lemma="assure">assure</verb> you, Lord Vader, my men <verb lemma="be">are</verb> working as fast as they can.</sp>

<sp><speaker>VADER</speaker>
Perhaps I can <verb lemma="find">find</verb> new ways to motivate them.</sp>

<sp><speaker>JERJERROD</speaker>
I <verb lemma="tell">tell</verb> you, this <verb lemma="station">station</verb> will <verb lemma="be">be</verb> operational as planned.</sp>

<sp><speaker>VADER</speaker>
The Emperor does not share your optimistic appraisal of the situation.</sp>

<sp><speaker>JERJERROD</speaker>
But he asks the impossible. I <verb lemma="need">need</verb> more men.</sp>

<sp><speaker>VADER</speaker>
Then perhaps you can <verb lemma="tell">tell</verb> him when he arrives.</sp>

<sp><speaker>JERJERROD	 (aghast)</speaker>
The Emperor's coming here?</sp>

<sp><speaker>VADER</speaker>
That <verb lemma="be">is</verb> correct, Commander. And he <verb lemma="be">is</verb> most displeased with your 
apparent lack of progress.</sp>

<sp><speaker>JERJERROD</speaker>
We shall double our efforts.</sp>

<sp><speaker>VADER</speaker>
I <verb lemma="hope">hope</verb> so, Commander, for your sake. The Emperor <verb lemma="be">is</verb> not as forgiving as 
I am.</sp>

<setting>5    EXT ROAD TO JABBA'S PALACE - TATOOINE</setting>

<sd>A lonely, windswept road meanders through the desolate Tatooine 
terrain. We HEAR a familiar BEEPING and a distinctive reply before 
catching sight of ARTOO-DETOO and SEE-THREEPIO, <verb lemma="make">making</verb> their way along 
the road toward the ominous palace of Jabba the Hutt.</sd>

<sp><speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
Of <verb lemma="course">course</verb> I'm worried. And you should be, too. Lando Calrissian and 
poor Chewbacca never returned from this awful place.</sp>

<sd>Artoo whistles timidly.</sd>

<sp><speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
Don't <verb lemma="be">be</verb> so sure. If I <verb lemma="tell">told</verb> you half the things I've heard about this 
Jabba the Hutt, you'd probably short-circuit.</sp>

<sd>The two droids fearfully <verb lemma="approach">approach</verb> the massive gate to the palace.</sd>

<sp><speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
Artoo, <verb lemma="be">are</verb> you <verb lemma="sure">sure</verb> this <verb lemma="be">is</verb> the right place? I better knock, I suppose.</sp>

<setting>6    EXT JABBA'S PALACE - GATE </setting>

<sd>Threepio looks around for some kind of signaling device, then timidly 
knocks on the iron door.</sd>

<sp><speaker>THREEPIO	 (instantly) </speaker>
There doesn't seem to <verb lemma="be">be</verb> anyone there. Let's <verb lemma="go">go</verb> <verb lemma="back">back</verb> and <verb lemma="tell">tell</verb> Master 
Luke.</sp>

<sd>A small hatch in the middle of the door opens and a spidery mechanical 
arm, with a large electronic eyeball on the end, pops out and inspects 
the two droids.</sd>

<sp><speaker>STRANGE VOICE</speaker>
Tee chuta hhat yudd!</sp>

<sp><speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
Goodness gracious me!</sp>

 Threepio points to Artoo, then to himself.

<sp><speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
Artoo Detoowha bo Seethreepiowha ey toota odd mischka Jabba du Hutt.</sp>

<sd>The <verb lemma="eye">eye</verb> looks from one robot to the other, there <verb lemma="be">is</verb> a <verb lemma="laugh">laugh</verb> then the 
<verb lemma="eye">eye</verb> zips <verb lemma="back">back</verb> into the door. The hatch slams shut. Artoo beeps his 
concern.</sd>

<sp><speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
I don't think they're going to <verb lemma="let">let</verb> us in, Artoo. We'd better go.</sp>

<sd>Artoo beeps his reluctance as Threepio turns to leave. Suddenly the 
massive door starts to rise with a horrific metallic SCREECH. The 
robots <verb lemma="turn">turn</verb> <verb lemma="back">back</verb> and <verb lemma="face">face</verb> an endless black cavity. The droids <verb lemma="look">look</verb> at 
one another, <verb lemma="afraid">afraid</verb> to enter.</sd>

<sd>Artoo starts forward into the gloom. Threepio rushes after his stubby 
companion. The door lowers noisily behind them.</sd>

<sp><speaker>THREEPIO </speaker>
Artoo, wait. Oh, dear! Artoo. Artoo, I really don't think we should 
<verb lemma="rush">rush</verb> into all this.</sp>

<sd>Artoo continues down the corridor, with Threepio following.</sd>

<sp><speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
Oh, Artoo!  Artoo, wait for me!</sp>

<setting>7    INT JABBA'S PALACE - HALLWAY</setting>

<sd>The door slams <verb lemma="shut">shut</verb> with a loud <verb lemma="crash">crash</verb> that echoes throughout the dark 
passageway. The frightened robots <verb lemma="be">are</verb> <verb lemma="meet">met</verb> by two giant, green GAMORREAN 
GUARDS, who <verb lemma="fall">fall</verb> in behind them. Threepio <verb lemma="glance">glances</verb> quickly <verb lemma="back">back</verb> at the 
two lumbe<verb lemma="ring">ring</verb> brutes, then <verb lemma="back">back</verb> to Artoo. One <verb lemma="guard">guard</verb> <verb lemma="grunt">grunts</verb> an order. 
Artoo beeps nervously.</sd>

<sp><speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
Just you <verb lemma="deliver">deliver</verb> Master Luke's message and <verb lemma="get">get</verb> us out of here. Oh my! 
Oh! Oh, no.</sp>

<sd>Walking toward them out of the darkness <verb lemma="be">is</verb> BIB FORTUNA, a humanlike 
alien with long tentacles <verb lemma="protrude">protruding</verb> from his skull.</sd>

<sp><speaker>BIB</speaker>
<verb lemma="die">Die</verb> Wanna Wanga!</sp>

<sp><speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
Oh, my! <verb lemma="die">Die</verb> Wanna Wauaga. We -- we <verb lemma="bring">bring</verb> a message to your master, 
Jabba the Hutt.</sp>

<sd>Artoo lets out a series of quick beeps.</sd>

<sp><speaker>THREEPIO	 (cont)</speaker>
...and a gift.
(thinks a moment, then to Artoo)
Gift, what gift?</sp>

<sd>Bib shakes his <verb lemma="head">head</verb> negatively.</sd>

<sp><speaker>BIB</speaker>
Nee Jabba no badda. Me <verb lemma="chaade">chaade</verb> su goodie.</sp>

<sd>Bib holds out his <verb lemma="hand">hand</verb> toward Artoo and the tiny <verb lemma="droid">droid</verb> backs up a bit, 
letting out a protesting array of squeaks. Threepio turns to the 
strange-looking alien.</sd>

<sp><speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
He says that our instructions <verb lemma="be">are</verb> to <verb lemma="give">give</verb> it only to Jabba himself.</sp>

<sd>Bib thinks about this for a moment.</sd>

<sp><speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
I'm terribly sorry. I'm <verb lemma="afraid">afraid</verb> he's ever so stubborn about these sort 
of things.</sp>

<sd>Bib gestures for the droids to follow.</sd>

<sp><speaker>BIB</speaker>
Nudd Chaa.</sp>

<sd>The droids <verb lemma="follow">follow</verb> the tall, tentac<verb lemma="lead">led</verb> alien into the darkness, trai<verb lemma="lead">led</verb> 
by the two guards.</sd>

<sp><speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
Artoo, I <verb lemma="have">have</verb> a bad feeling about this.</sp>

<setting>8    INT JABBA'S THRONE ROOM</setting>

<sd>The throne room <verb lemma="be">is</verb> filled with the vilest, most grotesque CREATURES 
ever <verb lemma="conceive">conceived</verb> in the universe. Artoo and Threepio seem very small as 
they <verb lemma="pause">pause</verb> in the doorway to the dimly <verb lemma="light">lit</verb> chamber. Light shafts 
partially illuminate the drunk<verb lemma="en">en</verb> courtiers as Bib Fortuna crosses the 
room to the platform upon which rests the leader of this nauseating 
crowd: JABBA THE HUTT. The monarch of the galactic underworld <verb lemma="be">is</verb> a 
repulsive blob of bloated fat with a maniacal grin. <verb lemma="chain">Chained</verb> to the 
horrible creature <verb lemma="be">is</verb> the beautiful alien female dancer <verb lemma="name">named</verb> OOLA. At 
the foot of the dais sits an obnoxious birdlike creature, SALACIOUS 
CRUMB. Bib whispers something in the slobbe<verb lemma="ring">ring</verb> degenerate's ear. Jabba 
laughs horribly, at the two <verb lemma="terrify">terrified</verb> droids before him. Threepio bows 
politely.</sd>

<sp><speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
Good morning.</sp>

<sp><speaker>JABBA</speaker>
Bo Shuda!</sp>

<sd>The robots <verb lemma="jump">jump</verb> forward to <verb lemma="stand">stand</verb> before the repulsive, loose-skinned 
villain.</sd>

<sp><speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
The message, Artoo, the message.</sp>

<sd>Artoo whistles, and a beam of <verb lemma="light">light</verb> projects from his domed head, 
<verb lemma="create">creating</verb> a hologram of LUKE on the floor. The image grows to over ten 
feet tall, and the young Jedi towers over the space gangsters.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
Greetings, <verb lemma="exalt">Exalted</verb> One. <verb lemma="allow">Allow</verb> me to <verb lemma="introduce">introduce</verb> myself. I am Luke 
Skywalker, Jedi Knight and friend to Captain Solo. I <verb lemma="know">know</verb> that you <verb lemma="be">are</verb> 
powerful, mighty Jabba, and that your anger with Solo must <verb lemma="be">be</verb> equally 
powerful. I seek an audience with Your Greatness to bargain for Solo's 
life. 
(Jabba's <verb lemma="crowd">crowd</verb> laughs) 
With your wisdom, I'm <verb lemma="sure">sure</verb> that we can <verb lemma="work">work</verb> out an <verb lemma="arrange">arrange</verb>ment which 
will <verb lemma="be">be</verb> mutually beneficial and enable us to <verb lemma="avoid">avoid</verb> any unpleasant 
confrontation. As a token of my goodwill, I present to you a gift: 
these two droids.</sp>

<sd>Threepio <verb lemma="be">is</verb> startled by this announcement.</sd>

<sp><speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
What <verb lemma="do">did</verb> he say?</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE	 (cont)</speaker>
... Both <verb lemma="be">are</verb> hardworking and will <verb lemma="serve">serve</verb> you well.</sp>

<sp><speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
This can't be! Artoo, you're playing the wrong message.</sp>

<sd>Luke's hologram disappears.</sd>

<sd>Jabba laughs while Bib speaks to him in Huttese.</sd>

<sp><speaker>JABBA	 (in Huttese subtitled)</speaker>
There will <verb lemma="be">be</verb> no bargain.</sp>

<sp><speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
We're doomed.</sp>

<sp><speaker>JABBA	 (in Huttese subtitled)</speaker>
I will not <verb lemma="give">give</verb> up my favorite decoration. I <verb lemma="like">like</verb> Captain Solo where he 
is.</sp>

<sd>Jabba laughs hideously and looks toward an alcove beside the throne. 
Hanging high, flat against the wall, exactly as we <verb lemma="see">saw</verb> him last, <verb lemma="be">is</verb> a 
carbonized HAN SOLO.</sd>

<sp><speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
Artoo, look! Captain Solo. And he's still frozen in carbonite.</sp>

<setting>9    INT DUNGEON CORRIDOR </setting>

<sd>One of Jabba's Gamorrean guards marches Artoo and Threepio down a dank, 
shadowy passageway <verb lemma="line">lined</verb> with holding cells. The <verb lemma="cry">cries</verb> of unspeakable 
creatures <verb lemma="bounce">bounce</verb> off the cold stone walls. Occasionally a repulsive arm 
or tentacle grabs through the bars at the hapless droids. Artoo beeps 
pitifully.</sd>

<sp><speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
What could possibly <verb lemma="have">have</verb> <verb lemma="come">come</verb> over Master Luke. Is it something I did? 
He never expressed any unhappiness with my work. Oh! Oh! <verb lemma="hold">Hold</verb> it! Ohh!</sp>

<sd>A large tentacle <verb lemma="wrap">wraps</verb> around Threepio's neck. He <verb lemma="manage">manages</verb> to <verb lemma="break">break</verb> 
free, and they <verb lemma="move">move</verb> on to a door at the end of the corridor.</sd>

<setting>10   INT BOILER ROOM</setting>

<sd>The door slides open, revealing a room filled with steam and noisy 
machinery. The <verb lemma="guard">guard</verb> <verb lemma="motion">motions</verb> them into the boiler room, where they <verb lemma="be">are</verb> 
<verb lemma="meet">met</verb> by a tall, <verb lemma="thin">thin</verb> humanlike robot <verb lemma="name">named</verb> EV-9D9. Behind the robot can 
<verb lemma="be">be</verb> seen a torture rack pulling the legs off a screaming baby <verb lemma="work">work</verb> 
droid. A second power <verb lemma="droid">droid</verb> <verb lemma="be">is</verb> upside down.  As <verb lemma="smoke">smoking</verb> <verb lemma="brand">branding</verb> irons 
<verb lemma="be">are</verb> pressed into his feet, the stubby robot lets out an agonized 
electronic scream. Artoo and Threepio <verb lemma="cringe">cringe</verb> as the <verb lemma="guard">guard</verb> <verb lemma="grunt">grunts</verb> to EV-
9D9.</sd>

<sp><speaker>NINEDENINE</speaker>
Ah, good. New acquisitions. You <verb lemma="be">are</verb> a protocol droid, <verb lemma="be">are</verb> you not?</sp>

<sp><speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
I am See-Threepio, human-cy...</sp>

<sp><speaker>NINEDENINE</speaker>
Yes or no will do.</sp>

<sp><speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
Oh. Well, yes.</sp>

<sp><speaker>NINEDENINE</speaker>
How many languages <verb lemma="do">do</verb> you speak?</sp>

<sp><speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
I am fluent in over six million forms of communication, and can 
readily...</sp>

<sp><speaker>NINEDENINE</speaker>
Splendid! We <verb lemma="have">have</verb> been without an interpreter since our master got 
angry with our <verb lemma="last">last</verb> protocol <verb lemma="droid">droid</verb> and disintegrated him.</sp>

<sp><speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
Disintegrated?</sp>

<sp><speaker>NINEDENINE	 (to a Gamorrean guard)</speaker>
Guard! This protocol <verb lemma="droid">droid</verb> might <verb lemma="be">be</verb> useful. <verb lemma="fit">Fit</verb> him with a restraining 
bolt and <verb lemma="take">take</verb> him <verb lemma="back">back</verb> to His Excellency's main audience chamber.</sp>

<sd>The <verb lemma="guard">guard</verb> shoves Threepio toward the door.</sd>

<sp><speaker>THREEPIO	 (disappearing)</speaker>
Artoo, don't <verb lemma="leave">leave</verb> me! Ohhh!</sp>

<sd>Artoo lets out a plaintive <verb lemma="cry">cry</verb> as the door closes. Then he beeps 
angrily.</sd>

<sp><speaker>NINEDENINE</speaker>
You're a feisty little one, but you'll soon <verb lemma="learn">learn</verb> some respect. I <verb lemma="have">have</verb> 
<verb lemma="need">need</verb> for you on the master's Sail Barge. And I think you'll <verb lemma="fit">fit</verb> in 
nicely.</sp>

<sd>The poor <verb lemma="work">work</verb> <verb lemma="droid">droid</verb> in the background lets out another tortured 
electronic scream.</sd>

<setting>11   INT JABBA'S THRONE ROOM</setting>

<sd>The court of Jabba the Hutt <verb lemma="be">is</verb> in the midst of a drunken, raucous 
party. Sloppy, smelly monsters <verb lemma="cheer">cheer</verb> and <verb lemma="make">make</verb> rude noises as Oola and a 
fat female dancer perform in <verb lemma="front">front</verb> of Jabba's throne.</sd>

<sd>Jabba leers at the dancers and with a lustful gleam in his <verb lemma="eye">eye</verb> beckons 
Oola to <verb lemma="come">come</verb> and <verb lemma="sit">sit</verb> with him. She stops <verb lemma="dance">dancing</verb> and backs away, 
<verb lemma="shake">shaking</verb> her head. Jabba gets angry and points to a <verb lemma="spot">spot</verb> next to him.</sd>

<sp><speaker>JABBA</speaker>
Da Eitha!</sp>

<sd>The lovely alien shakes her <verb lemma="head">head</verb> again and screams.</sd>

<sp><speaker>OOLA</speaker>
Na Chuba negatorie Na! Na! Natoota...</sp>

<sd>Jabba <verb lemma="be">is</verb> furious and pulls her toward him, <verb lemma="tug">tugging</verb> on the chain.</sd>

<sp><speaker>JABBA</speaker>
Boscka!</sp>

<sd>He pushes a button and, before the dancer can flee, a trap door in the 
floor springs open and swallows her up. As the door snaps shut, a 
muffled growl <verb lemma="be">is</verb> followed by a hideous scream. Jabba and his monstrous 
friends <verb lemma="laugh">laugh</verb> hysterically and several revelers <verb lemma="hurry">hurry</verb> over to <verb lemma="watch">watch</verb> her 
fate through a grate.</sd>

<sd>Threepio cringes and <verb lemma="glance">glances</verb> wistfully at the carbonite <verb lemma="form">form</verb> of Han 
Solo, but <verb lemma="be">is</verb> immediately distracted by a gunshot offscreen.�An 
unnatural <verb lemma="quiet">quiet</verb> sweeps the boisterous gathering. On the far <verb lemma="side">side</verb> of the 
room, the <verb lemma="crush">crush</verb> of debauchers moves aside to <verb lemma="allow">allow</verb> the <verb lemma="approach">approach</verb> of two 
guards followed by BOUSHH, an oddly <verb lemma="cloak">cloaked</verb> bounty hunter, leading his 
captive, Han Solo's copilot, CHEWBACCA THE WOOKIEE.</sd>

<sd>Bib takes his place next to his disgusting master, and whispers into 
his ear, pointing at Chewbacca and the bounty hunter. Jabba listens 
intently, then the bounty hunter bows before the gangster and speaks a 
greeting in a strange, electronically <verb lemma="process">processed</verb> tongue (Ubese).</sd>

<sp><speaker>BOUSHH	 (in Ubese subtitled)</speaker>
I <verb lemma="have">have</verb> <verb lemma="come">come</verb> for the bounty on this Wookiee.</sp>

<sp><speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
Oh, no! Chewbacca!</sp>

<sp><speaker>JABBA	 (in Huttese subtitled)</speaker>
At <verb lemma="last">last</verb> we <verb lemma="have">have</verb> the mighty Chewbacca.</sp>

<sd>Jabba lets out a loud, long, blood-curdling <verb lemma="laugh">laugh</verb> and turns to 
Threepio, <verb lemma="wave">waving</verb> him closer. The reluctant <verb lemma="droid">droid</verb> obeys.</sd>

<sp><speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
Oh, uh, yes, uh, I am here, Your Worshipfulness. Uh... yes!</sp>

<sd>Jabba continues speaking, as Threepio nervously translates. Boushh 
listens, studying the dangerous creatures around the room. He notices 
BOBA FETT standing near the door.</sd>

<sp><speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
Oh. The illustrious Jabba bids you welcome and will gladly <verb lemma="pay">pay</verb> you the 
reward of twenty-five thousand.</sp>

<sp><speaker>BOUSHH	 (in Ubese subtitled)</speaker>
I <verb lemma="want">want</verb> fifty thousand. No less.</sp>

<sd>Jabba immediately <verb lemma="fly">flies</verb> into a rage, knocking the golden <verb lemma="droid">droid</verb> off the 
raised throne into a <verb lemma="clatter">clattering</verb> heap on the floor. Boushh adjusts his 
weapon as Jabba <verb lemma="rave">raves</verb> in Huttese and Threepio struggles <verb lemma="back">back</verb> onto the 
throne. The disheve<verb lemma="lead">led</verb> <verb lemma="droid">droid</verb> <verb lemma="try">tries</verb> to <verb lemma="compose">compose</verb> himself.</sd>

<sp><speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
Uh, oh... but what, what <verb lemma="do">did</verb> I say?
(to Boushh)
Uh, the mighty Jabba asks why he must <verb lemma="pay">pay</verb> fifty thousand.</sp>

<sd>The bounty hunter holds up a small silver ball in his hand. Threepio 
looks at it, then looks at Jabba, then <verb lemma="back">back</verb> to the bounty hunter. The 
<verb lemma="droid">droid</verb> <verb lemma="be">is</verb> very nervous and Jabba <verb lemma="be">is</verb> getting very impatient.</sd>

<sp><speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
Because he's holding a thermal detonator.</sp>

<sd>The guards instantly <verb lemma="back">back</verb> away, as <verb lemma="do">do</verb> most of the other monsters in the 
room. Jabba stares at the silver ball, which begins to <verb lemma="glow">glow</verb> in the 
bounty hunter's hand. The room <verb lemma="have">has</verb> fallen into a tense hush. Jabba 
stares at the bounty hunter malevolently until a sly <verb lemma="grin">grin</verb> creeps across 
his vast mouth and he begins to laugh.</sd>

<sp><speaker>JABBA	 (in Huttese subtitled)</speaker>
This bounty hunter <verb lemma="be">is</verb> my kind of scum. Fearless and inventive.</sp>

<sd>Jabba continues.</sd>

<sp><speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
Jabba offers the sum of thirty-five. And I <verb lemma="suggest">suggest</verb> you <verb lemma="take">take</verb> it.</sp>

<sd>Bib and the other monsters <verb lemma="study">study</verb> the bounty hunter and wait for his 
reaction. Boushh releases a <verb lemma="switch">switch</verb> on the thermal detonator and it goes 
dead.</sd>

<sp><speaker>BOUSHH</speaker>
Zeebuss.</sp>

<sp><speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
He agrees!</sp>

<sd>The raucous <verb lemma="crowd">crowd</verb> of monsters erupts in a symphony of cheers and 
applause as the party returns to its full noisy pitch. Chewbacca 
growls. As he <verb lemma="be">is</verb> <verb lemma="lead">led</verb> away we <verb lemma="spot">spot</verb> LANDO CALRISSIAN, <verb lemma="disguise">disgu<verb lemma="be">is</verb>ed</verb> as a 
skiff <verb lemma="guard">guard</verb> in a partial <verb lemma="face">face</verb> mask. The band starts up and <verb lemma="dance">dancing</verb> 
girls <verb lemma="take">take</verb> the <verb lemma="center">center</verb> of the floor, to the hoots of the loudly 
appreciative creatures.</sd>

<sd>Boushh <verb lemma="lean">leans</verb> against a column with gunfighter cool and <verb lemma="survey">surveys</verb> the 
scene, his gaze stopping only when it <verb lemma="connect">connects</verb> with a glare from across 
the room. Boba Fett <verb lemma="be">is</verb> watching him. Boushh shifts slightly, <verb lemma="cradle">cradling</verb> 
his weapon lovingly. Boba Fett shifts with equally ominous arrogance.</sd>

<setting>12   INT DUNGEON CORRIDOR AND CELL</setting>

<sd>Gamorrean guards <verb lemma="lead">lead</verb> Chewie down the same hallway we <verb lemma="see">saw</verb> before. When 
a tentacle reaches out at the Wookiee, Chewie's ferocious ROAR echoes 
against the walls and the tentacle snaps <verb lemma="back">back</verb> into its cell in terror. 
It takes all the guards to <verb lemma="hurl">hurl</verb> Chewie roughly into a cell, slamming 
the door behind him. Chewie lets out a pathetic howl and bangs on the 
iron door.</sd>

<setting>13   EXT JABBA'S PALACE</setting>

<sd>The palace <verb lemma="be">is</verb> sitting in the <verb lemma="light">light</verb> of the double sunset. On the road in 
front, a large toadlike creature flicks its tongue out for a desert 
rodent and <verb lemma="burp">burps</verb> in satisfaction.</sd>

<setting>14   INT JABBA'S THRONE ROOM - NIGHT</setting>

<sd>Silence. The room <verb lemma="be">is</verb> deserted, only the awful debris of the alien 
celebration <verb lemma="give">giving</verb> mute witness to the activity here before. Several 
drunk creatures <verb lemma="lie">lie</verb> unconscious around the room, snoring loudly.</sd>

<sd>A shadowy <verb lemma="figure">figure</verb> moves stealthily among the columns at the perimeter of 
the room and <verb lemma="be">is</verb> revealed to <verb lemma="be">be</verb> Boushh, the bounty hunter. He picks his 
way carefully through the snoring, drunk<verb lemma="en">en</verb> monsters.</sd>

<sd>Han Solo, the frozen space pirate, hangs spotlighted on the wall, his 
coffin-like case suspended by a <verb lemma="force">force</verb> field. The bounty hunter 
deactivates the <verb lemma="force">force</verb> field by flipping a <verb lemma="control">control</verb> <verb lemma="switch">switch</verb> to one <verb lemma="side">side</verb> of 
the coffin. The heavy case slowly lowers to the floor of the alcove.</sd>

<sd>Boushh steps up to the case, studying Han, and then turns to the 
controls on the <verb lemma="side">side</verb> of the coffin. He activates a series of switches 
and, after one <verb lemma="last">last</verb> hesitant <verb lemma="look">look</verb> at Han, slides the de-carbonization 
lever. The case begins to <verb lemma="emit">emit</verb> a <verb lemma="sound">sound</verb> as the hard shell covering the 
contours of Han's <verb lemma="face">face</verb> begins to <verb lemma="melt">melt</verb> away. The bounty hunter watches 
as Han's body <verb lemma="be">is</verb> freed of its metallic coat and his forearms and hands, 
previously raised in reflexive protest, <verb lemma="drop">drop</verb> slackly to his side. His 
<verb lemma="face">face</verb> muscles <verb lemma="relax">relax</verb> from their mask of horror. He appears quite dead.</sd>

<sd>Boushh's ugly helmet <verb lemma="lean">leans</verb> <verb lemma="close">close</verb> to Han's <verb lemma="face">face</verb> listening for the breath 
of life. Nothing. He waits. Han's eyes <verb lemma="pop">pop</verb> open with a <verb lemma="start">start</verb> and he 
begins coughing. The bounty hunter steadies the staggering newborn.</sd>

<sp><speaker>BOUSHH</speaker>
Just <verb lemma="relax">relax</verb> for a moment. You're <verb lemma="free">free</verb> of the carbonite.</sp>

<sd>Han touches his <verb lemma="face">face</verb> with his <verb lemma="hand">hand</verb> and moans.</sd>

<sp><speaker>BOUSHH</speaker>
Shhh. You <verb lemma="have">have</verb> hibernation sickness.</sp>

<sp><speaker>HAN</speaker>
I can't see.</sp>

<sp><speaker>BOUSHH</speaker>
Your eyesight will <verb lemma="return">return</verb> in time.</sp>

<sp><speaker>HAN</speaker>
Where am I?</sp>

<sp><speaker>BOUSHH</speaker>
Jabba's palace.</sp>

<sp><speaker>HAN</speaker>
Who <verb lemma="be">are</verb> you?</sp>

<sd>The bounty hunter reaches up and lifts the helmet from his head, 
revealing the beautiful <verb lemma="face">face</verb> of PRINCESS LEIA.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LEIA</speaker>
Someone who loves you.</sp>

<sp><speaker>HAN</speaker>
Leia!</sp>

<sp><speaker>LEIA</speaker>
I gotta <verb lemma="get">get</verb> you out of here.</sp>

<sd>As Leia helps her weakened lover to <verb lemma="stand">stand</verb> up, the relative <verb lemma="quiet">quiet</verb> <verb lemma="be">is</verb> 
<verb lemma="pierce">pierced</verb> by an obscene HUTTESE CACKLE from the other <verb lemma="side">side</verb> of the alcove.</sd>

<sp><speaker>HAN</speaker>
What's that? I <verb lemma="know">know</verb> that laugh.</sp>

<sd>The curtain on the far <verb lemma="side">side</verb> of the alcove opens, revealing Jabba the 
Hutt, surrounded by Bib and other aliens. He laughs again, and his 
gross cronies <verb lemma="join">join</verb> in a cacophony of alien glee.</sd>

<sp><speaker>HAN</speaker>
Hey, Jabba. Look, Jabba, I <verb lemma="be">was</verb> just on my way to <verb lemma="pay">pay</verb> you back, but I 
got a little sidetracked. It's not my fault.</sp>

<sd>Jabba laughs.</sd>

<sp><speaker>JABBA	 (in Huttese subtitled)</speaker>
It's too late for that, Solo. You may <verb lemma="have">have</verb> been a good smuggler, but 
now you're Bantha fodder.</sp>

<sp><speaker>HAN</speaker>
Look...</sp>

<sp><speaker>JABBA	 (cont Huttese subtitled)</speaker>
<verb lemma="take">Take</verb> him away!</sp>

<sd>The guards <verb lemma="grab">grab</verb> Han and <verb lemma="start">start</verb> to <verb lemma="lead">lead</verb> him away.</sd>

<sp><speaker>HAN</speaker>
Jabba... I'll <verb lemma="pay">pay</verb> you triple! You're throwing away a fortune here. 
Don't <verb lemma="be">be</verb> a fool!</sp>

<sd>Han <verb lemma="be">is</verb> dragged off, as Lando quickly moves forward and attempts to <verb lemma="lead">lead</verb> 
Leia away.</sd>

<sp><speaker>JABBA	 (in Huttese subtitled)</speaker>
<verb lemma="bring">Bring</verb> her to me.</sp>

<sd>Jabba chuckles as Lando and a second <verb lemma="guard">guard</verb> <verb lemma="drag">drag</verb> the beautiful young 
princess toward him. Threepio peeks from behind a monster and quickly 
turns away in disgust.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LEIA</speaker>
We <verb lemma="have">have</verb> powerful friends. You're gonna <verb lemma="regret">regret</verb> this...</sp>

<sp><speaker>JABBA	 (in Huttese subtitled)</speaker>
I'm sure.</sp>

<sd>Inexorably her lovely <verb lemma="face">face</verb> moves to within a few inches of Jabba's ugly 
blob of a head, and Leia turns away in disgust.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LEIA</speaker>
Ugh!</sp>

<sp><speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
Ohhh, I can't bear to watch.</sp>

<setting>15   INT DUNGEON CELL</setting>

<sd>The heavy metal door of the dungeon whines and slowly <verb lemma="creak">creaks</verb> open. A 
<verb lemma="guard">guard</verb> throws the <verb lemma="blind">blinded</verb> star captain into the dark cell and the door 
slams <verb lemma="shut">shut</verb> behind him, <verb lemma="leave">leaving</verb> only a <verb lemma="thin">thin</verb> sliver of <verb lemma="light">light</verb> from a crack 
in the door. Han <verb lemma="be">is</verb> trying to <verb lemma="collect">collect</verb> himself when suddenly a growl <verb lemma="be">is</verb> 
heard from the far <verb lemma="side">side</verb> of the cell. He jumps <verb lemma="back">back</verb> against the cell 
door and listens.</sd>

<sp><speaker>HAN</speaker>
Chewie? Chewie, <verb lemma="be">is</verb> that you?</sp>

<sd>The shadowy <verb lemma="figure">figure</verb> lets out a crazy <verb lemma="yell">yell</verb> and races toward Han, lifting 
him off the <verb lemma="grind">ground</verb> with a big <verb lemma="hug">hug</verb> that <verb lemma="carry">carries</verb> them into the light, 
revealing Chewie.</sd>

<sp><speaker>HAN</speaker>
Ah! Chew--Chewie!</sp>

<sd>The giant Wookiee <verb lemma="bark">barks</verb> with glee.</sd>

<sp><speaker>HAN</speaker>
<verb lemma="wait">Wait</verb>. I can't see, pal. What's goin' on?</sp>

<sd>Chewie <verb lemma="bark">barks</verb> an excited blue streak.</sd>

<sp><speaker>HAN</speaker>
Luke? Luke's crazy. He can't even <verb lemma="take">take</verb> care of himself, much less 
<verb lemma="rescue">rescue</verb> anybody.</sp>

<sd>Chewie <verb lemma="bark">barks</verb> a reply.</sd>

<sp><speaker>HAN</speaker>
A...Jedi Knight? I--I'm out of it for a little while, everybody gets 
delusions of grandeur.</sp>

<sd>Chewie growls insistently. He holds Han to his chest and <verb lemma="pet">pets</verb> his head.</sd>

<sp><speaker>HAN</speaker>
I'm all right, pal. I'm all right.</sp>

<setting>16   INT MAIN GATE AND HALL - JABBA'S PALACE</setting>

<sd>Noisily, the main gate lifts to <verb lemma="flood">flood</verb> the blackness with <verb lemma="blind">blinding</verb> LIGHT 
and <verb lemma="reveal">reveal</verb> the <verb lemma="silhouette">silhouetted</verb> <verb lemma="figure">figure</verb> of LUKE SKYWALKER. He <verb lemma="be">is</verb> <verb lemma="clothe">clad</verb> in a 
robe similar to Ben's and wears neither pistol nor laser sword. Luke 
strides purposefully into the hallway. Two giant guards <verb lemma="move">move</verb> to <verb lemma="block">block</verb> 
Luke's path. Luke halts.</sd>

<sd>Luke raises his <verb lemma="hand">hand</verb> and points at the puzzled guards, who immediately 
<verb lemma="lower">lower</verb> their spears and <verb lemma="fall">fall</verb> back. The young Jedi lowers his <verb lemma="hand">hand</verb> and 
moves on down the hallway.</sd>

<sd>Bib Fortuna appears out of the gloom. He speaks to Luke as they 
<verb lemma="approach">approach</verb> each other, but Luke doesn't <verb lemma="stop">stop</verb> and Bib must <verb lemma="reverse">reverse</verb> his 
direction and <verb lemma="hurry">hurry</verb> alongside the young Jedi in order to <verb lemma="carry">carry</verb> on the 
conversation. Several other guards <verb lemma="fall">fall</verb> in behind them in the darkness.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
I must <verb lemma="speak">speak</verb> with Jabba.</sp>

<sd>Bib answers in Huttese, <verb lemma="shake">shaking</verb> his <verb lemma="head">head</verb> in denial. Luke stops and 
stares at Bib; he raises his <verb lemma="hand">hand</verb> slightly.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
You will <verb lemma="take">take</verb> me to Jabba now!</sp>

<sd>Bib turns in hypnotic response to Luke's command, and Luke follows him 
into the gloom.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
You <verb lemma="serve">serve</verb> your master well.</sp>

<sd>Bib responds.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
And you will <verb lemma="be">be</verb> rewarded.</sp>

<setting>17   INT JABBA'S THRONE ROOM</setting>

<sd>Jabba <verb lemma="be">is</verb> asleep on his throne, with Leia <verb lemma="lie">lying</verb> in <verb lemma="front">front</verb> of him. 
Salacious sits by Jabba's tail, watching it wriggle. Leia <verb lemma="be">is</verb> now 
<verb lemma="dress">dressed</verb> in the skimpy costume of a <verb lemma="dance">dancing</verb> girl; a chain runs from a 
manacle/necklace at her throat to her new master, Jabba the Hutt. 
Threepio stands behind Jabba as Bib comes up to the gangster slug.</sd>

<sp><speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
At last! Master Luke's <verb lemma="come">come</verb> to <verb lemma="rescue">rescue</verb> me.</sp>

<sp><speaker>BIB</speaker>
Master.</sp>

<sd>Jabba awakens with a <verb lemma="start">start</verb> and Bib continues, in Huttese.</sd>

<sp><speaker>BIB</speaker>
...Luke Skywalker, Jedi Knight.</sp>

<sp><speaker>JABBA	 (in Huttese subtitled)</speaker>
I <verb lemma="tell">told</verb> you not to <verb lemma="admit">admit</verb> him.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
I must <verb lemma="be">be</verb> allowed to speak.</sp>

<sp><speaker>BIB	 (in Huttese subtitled)</speaker>
He must <verb lemma="be">be</verb> allowed to speak.</sp>

<sd>Jabba, furious, clobbers Bib and shoves him away.</sd>

<sp><speaker>JABBA	 (in Huttese subtitled)</speaker>
You weak-minded fool! He's <verb lemma="use">using</verb> an old Jedi <verb lemma="mind">mind</verb> trick.</sp>

<sd>Luke stares hard at Jabba.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
You will <verb lemma="bring">bring</verb> Captain Solo and the Wookiee to me.</sp>

<sp><speaker>JABBA	 (in Huttese subtitled)</speaker>
Your <verb lemma="mind">mind</verb> powers will not <verb lemma="work">work</verb> on me, boy.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
Nevertheless, I'm <verb lemma="take">taking</verb> Captain Solo and his friends. You can either 
profit by this... or <verb lemma="be">be</verb> destroyed! It's your choice. But I <verb lemma="warn">warn</verb> you not 
to underestim<verb lemma="eat">ate</verb> my powers.</sp>

<sd>Jabba's <verb lemma="laugh">laugh</verb> <verb lemma="be">is</verb> <verb lemma="mean">mean</verb> and loud. Threepio attempts to <verb lemma="warn">warn</verb> Luke about 
the pit.</sd>

<sp><speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
Master Luke, you're standing on...</sp>

<sp><speaker>JABBA	 (in Huttese subtitled)</speaker>
There will <verb lemma="be">be</verb> no bargain, young Jedi. I shall enjoy watching you die.</sp>

<sd>Luke reaches out, and a pistol jumps out of a guard's holster and <verb lemma="fly">flies</verb> 
into Luke's hand. The bewildered <verb lemma="guard">guard</verb> grabs for it as Jabba raises his 
hand.</sd>

<sp><speaker>JABBA</speaker>
Bascka!</sp>

<sd>The floor suddenly drops away, sending Luke and the hapless <verb lemma="guard">guard</verb> into 
the pit. The pistol goes off, blasting a hole in the ceiling. Jabba 
laughs and his courtiers <verb lemma="join">join</verb> in. Leia starts forward but <verb lemma="be">is</verb> restrained 
by a human guard-- Lando, recognizable behind his mask. She looks at 
him and he shakes his <verb lemma="head">head</verb> "no."</sd>

<setting>18   INT RANCOR PIT</setting>

<sd>Luke and the <verb lemma="guard">guard</verb> <verb lemma="have">have</verb> dropped twenty-five feet from a chute into the 
dungeonlike cage. Luke gets to his feet as the <verb lemma="guard">guard</verb> yells hysterically 
for help. A <verb lemma="crowd">crowd</verb> gathers up around the edge of the pit as the door in 
the <verb lemma="side">side</verb> of the pit starts to RUMBLE open. The <verb lemma="guard">guard</verb> screams in panic. 
Luke looks calmly around for a means of escape.</sd>

<sp><speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
Oh, no! The Rancor!</sp>

<sd>At the <verb lemma="side">side</verb> of the pit, an iron door <verb lemma="rumble">rumbles</verb> upward and a giant, <verb lemma="fange">fanged</verb> 
RANCOR emerges. The <verb lemma="guard">guard</verb> runs to the <verb lemma="side">side</verb> of the pit and <verb lemma="try">tries</verb> 
futilely to <verb lemma="scramble">scramble</verb> to the top. The hideous beast closes in on him.</sd>

<sd>The Rancor moves past Luke, and as the <verb lemma="guard">guard</verb> continues to scramble, the 
Rancor picks him up and pops him into its slavering jaws. A few 
screams, and the <verb lemma="guard">guard</verb> <verb lemma="be">is</verb> swallowed with a gulp. The audience cheers 
and laughs at the guard's fate.</sd>

<sd>The monster turns and starts for Luke. The young Jedi dashes away just 
ahead of the monster's <verb lemma="swipe">swipe</verb> at him, and picks up the long arm bone of 
an earlier victim. The monster grabs Luke and brings him up to his 
<verb lemma="salivate">salivating</verb> mouth. At the <verb lemma="last">last</verb> moment, Luke wedges the bone in the 
monster's mouth and <verb lemma="be">is</verb> dropped to the floor. The monster bellows in 
<verb lemma="rage">rage</verb> and flails about, hitting the <verb lemma="side">side</verb> of the pit, <verb lemma="cause">causing</verb> an 
avalanche.</sd>

<sd>The monster crushes the bone in its jaws and sees Luke, who squeezes 
into a crevice in the pit wall. Luke looks past the monster to the 
holding cave beyond. On the far <verb lemma="side">side</verb> of the holding cave <verb lemma="be">is</verb> a utility 
door--if only he can <verb lemma="get">get</verb> to it. The Rancor spots Luke and reaches into 
the crevice for him. Luke grabs a large <verb lemma="rock">rock</verb> and raises it, smashing it 
down on the Rancor's finger.</sd>

19   HOLDING TUNNEL - RANCOR PIT

<sd>The Rancor lets out a loud howl as Luke makes a <verb lemma="run">run</verb> for the holding 
cave. He reaches the door and pushes a button to open it. When he 
succeeds, he sees a heavy <verb lemma="bar">barred</verb> gate between him and safety. Beyond 
the gate two guards <verb lemma="look">look</verb> up from their dinner. Luke turns to <verb lemma="see">see</verb> the 
monster heading for him, and pulls with all his might on the gate. The 
guards <verb lemma="move">move</verb> to the gate and <verb lemma="start">start</verb> <verb lemma="poke">poking</verb> at the young Jedi with spears, 
laughing.</sd>

<sd>Luke crouches (against the wall) as the monster starts to <verb lemma="reach">reach</verb> for 
him. Suddenly he notices a main door <verb lemma="control">control</verb> panel halfway up the wall. 
As the Rancor moves in for the kill, Luke picks up a skull from the 
cave floor and hurls it at the panel. The giant overhead door comes 
crashing down on the beast's head, squashing it <verb lemma="like">like</verb> a sledgehammer on 
an egg.</sd>

<sd>A startled gasp <verb lemma="be">is</verb> heard from the <verb lemma="stun">stunned</verb> court. There's consternation 
at this <verb lemma="turn">turn</verb> of events. Heads <verb lemma="look">look</verb> to Jabba, who <verb lemma="be">is</verb> actually turning 
<verb lemma="red">red</verb> with anger. Leia cannot suppress her joy. Jabba <verb lemma="utter">utters</verb> harsh 
<verb lemma="command">commands</verb> to his guards and they <verb lemma="hurry">hurry</verb> off.</sd>

<sp><speaker>JABBA	 (in Huttese subtitled)</speaker>
<verb lemma="bring">Bring</verb> me Solo and the Wookiee. They will all <verb lemma="suffer">suffer</verb> for this outrage.</sp>

<setting>21   INT RANCOR PIT</setting>

<sd>The Rancor KEEPERS <verb lemma="have">have</verb> <verb lemma="come">come</verb> into the cage and <verb lemma="be">are</verb> <verb lemma="examine">examining</verb> their dead 
beast. One of them breaks down and weeps. The other glares menacingly 
at Luke, who <verb lemma="be">is</verb> unworried. Several guards <verb lemma="rush">rush</verb> into the holding tunnel 
and <verb lemma="take">take</verb> Luke away.</sd>

<setting>22   INT THRONE ROOM</setting>

<sd>The <verb lemma="crowd">crowd</verb> of creepy courtiers parts as Han and Chewie <verb lemma="be">are</verb> <verb lemma="bring">brought</verb> into 
the throne room, and other guards <verb lemma="drag">drag</verb> Luke up the steps.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
Han!</sp>

<sp><speaker>HAN</speaker>
Luke!</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
Are you all right?</sp>

<sp><speaker>HAN</speaker>
Fine. Together again, huh?</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
Wouldn't miss it.</sp>

<sp><speaker>HAN</speaker>
How <verb lemma="be">are</verb> we doing?</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
The same as always.</sp>

<sp><speaker>HAN</speaker>
That bad, huh? Where's Leia?</sp>

<sd>Luke looks to Leia.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LEIA</speaker>
I'm here.</sp>

<sd>Threepio <verb lemma="be">is</verb> standing behind the grotesque gangster as he <verb lemma="stroke">strokes</verb> Leia 
<verb lemma="like">like</verb> a pet cat. Several of the guards, <verb lemma="include">including</verb> Lando, <verb lemma="bring">bring</verb> Luke from 
the other <verb lemma="side">side</verb> of the room. Boba <verb lemma="be">is</verb> standing behind Jabba.</sd>

<sd>Threepio steps forward and translates for the captives.</sd>

<sp><speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
Oh, dear. His High Exaltedness, the great Jabba the Hutt, <verb lemma="have">has</verb> <verb lemma="decree">decreed</verb> 
that you <verb lemma="be">are</verb> to <verb lemma="be">be</verb> terminated immediately.</sp>

<sp><speaker>HAN</speaker>
Good, I hate long waits.</sp>

<sp><speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
You will therefore <verb lemma="be">be</verb> taken to the Dune Sea and <verb lemma="cast">cast</verb> into the pit of 
Carkoon, the nesting place of the all-powerful Sarlacc.</sp>

<sp><speaker>HAN	 (to Luke)</speaker>
Doesn't <verb lemma="sound">sound</verb> so bad.</sp>

<sp><speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
In his belly, you will <verb lemma="find">find</verb> a new definition of pain and suffering, as 
you <verb lemma="be">are</verb> slowly digested over a thousand years.</sp>

<sp><speaker>HAN</speaker>
On second thought, let's <verb lemma="pass">pass</verb> on that, huh?</sp>

<sd>Chewie <verb lemma="bark">barks</verb> his agreement.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
You should <verb lemma="have">have</verb> bargained, Jabba. That's the <verb lemma="last">last</verb> mis<verb lemma="take">take</verb> you'll ever 
make.</sp>

<sd>Jabba <verb lemma="cackle">cackles</verb> evilly at this.</sd>

<sd>As the guards <verb lemma="drag">drag</verb> the prisoners from the throne room, a loud <verb lemma="cheer">cheer</verb> 
rises from the crowd. Leia and Chewie exchange concerned looks, but 
Luke Skywalker, Jedi warrior, cannot suppress a smile.</sd>

<setting>23   EXT TATOOINE SEA - SKIFF</setting>

<sd>Jabba's huge SAIL BARGE moves above the desert surface <verb lemma="accompany">accompanied</verb> by 
two smaller Skiffs. One of the skiffs <verb lemma="glide">glides</verb> close, revealing Luke, 
Han, and Chewie -- all in bonds -- surrounded by guards, one of whom <verb lemma="be">is</verb> 
Lando in disguise.</sd>

<sp><speaker>HAN</speaker>
I think my eyes <verb lemma="be">are</verb> getting better. Instead of a big dark blur, I <verb lemma="see">see</verb> a 
big <verb lemma="light">light</verb> blur.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
There's nothing to see. I used to <verb lemma="live">live</verb> here, you know.</sp>

<sp><speaker>HAN</speaker>
You're gonna <verb lemma="die">die</verb> here, you know. Convenient.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
Just <verb lemma="stick">stick</verb> <verb lemma="close">close</verb> to Chewie and Lando. I've taken care of everything.</sp>

<sp><speaker>HAN</speaker>
Oh... great!</sp>

<setting>24   INT BARGE OBSERVATION DECK</setting>

<sd>Jabba the Hutt rides <verb lemma="like">like</verb> a sultan in the massive antigravity ship. His 
entire retinue <verb lemma="be">is</verb> with him, drinking, eating, and <verb lemma="have">having</verb> a good time. 
Leia <verb lemma="be">is</verb> watching her friends in the skiff when the chain attached to 
her neck <verb lemma="be">is</verb> pulled tight and Jabba <verb lemma="tug">tugs</verb> the scantily <verb lemma="clothe">clad</verb> princess to 
him.</sd>

<sp><speaker>JABBA	 (in Huttese subtitled)</speaker>
Soon you will <verb lemma="learn">learn</verb> to <verb lemma="appreciate">appreciate</verb> me.</sp>

<sd>Threepio <verb lemma="wander">wanders</verb> among the Sail Barge aliens, bumping into a smaller 
<verb lemma="droid">droid</verb> <verb lemma="serve">serving</verb> drinks, spilling them all over the place. The stubby 
<verb lemma="droid">droid</verb> lets out an angry series of beeps and whistles.</sd>

<sp><speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
Oh, I'm terribly sor... Artoo! What <verb lemma="be">are</verb> you doing here?</sp>

<sd>Artoo beeps a quick reply.</sd>

<sp><speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
Well, I can <verb lemma="see">see</verb> you're <verb lemma="serve">serving</verb> drinks, but this place <verb lemma="be">is</verb> dangerous. 
They're going to execute Master Luke and, if we're not careful, us too!</sp>

<sd>Artoo whistles a singsong response.</sd>

<sp><speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
Hmm.  I wish I <verb lemma="have">had</verb> your confidence.</sp>

<setting>25   EXT SARLACC PIT </setting>

<sd>The convoy moves up over a huge sand pit. The Sail Barge stops to one 
<verb lemma="side">side</verb> of the depression, as does the <verb lemma="escort">escort</verb> skiff. But the prisoner's 
skiff moves out directly over the <verb lemma="center">center</verb> and hovers. At the bottom of 
the deep cone of sand <verb lemma="be">is</verb> a repulsive, mucous-lined hole, surrounded by 
thousands of needle-sharp teeth. This <verb lemma="be">is</verb> the SARLACC. A plank <verb lemma="be">is</verb> 
extended from the edge of the prisoner's skiff. Guards release Luke's 
bonds and <verb lemma="shove">shove</verb> him out onto the plank above the Sarlacc's mouth.</sd>

<setting>26   EXT SAIL BARGE OBSERVATION DECK</setting>

<sd>Jabba and Leia <verb lemma="be">are</verb> now by the rail, watching. Threepio <verb lemma="lean">leans</verb> forward 
and the slobbe<verb lemma="ring">ring</verb> villain mumbles something to him. As Threepio steps 
up to a comlink, Jabba raises his arm and the motley array of 
intergalactic pirates <verb lemma="fall">fall</verb> silent. Threepio's voice <verb lemma="be">is</verb> <verb lemma="amplify">amplified</verb> across 
loudspeakers.</sd>

<sp><speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
Victims of the almighty Sarlacc: His Excellency hopes that you will <verb lemma="die">die</verb> 
honorably. But should any of you wish to beg for mercy, the great Jabba 
the Hutt will now list<verb lemma="en">en</verb> to your pleas.</sp>

<setting>27   EXT SKIFF</setting>

<sd>Han steps forward arrogantly and begins to speak.</sd>

<sp><speaker>HAN</speaker>
Threepio, you <verb lemma="tell">tell</verb> that <verb lemma="slimy">slimy</verb> piece of... worm-ridden filth he'll <verb lemma="get">get</verb> 
no such pleasure from us. Right?</sp>

<sd>Chewie growls his agreement.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
Jabba! This <verb lemma="be">is</verb> your <verb lemma="last">last</verb> chance. <verb lemma="free">Free</verb> us or die.</sp>

<sd>Lando moves unobtrusively along the skiff as Luke shoots a quick <verb lemma="look">look</verb> 
of conspiracy to him.</sd>

<setting>28   INT SAIL BARGE OBSERVATION DECK</setting>

<sd>The assembled monsters <verb lemma="rock">rock</verb> with mocking laughter as Artoo zips 
unnoticed up the ramp to the upper deck. Jabba's laughter subsides as 
he speaks into the comlink.</sd>

<sp><speaker>JABBA	 (in Huttese subtitled)</speaker>
<verb lemma="move">Move</verb> him into position.</sp>

<sd>Jabba makes a thumbs-down gesture. Leia looks worried.</sd>

<setting>29   EXT BARGE - UPPER DECK</setting>

<sd>Artoo appears from below and zips over to the rail <verb lemma="face">facing</verb> the pit. 
Below, in the skiff, Luke <verb lemma="be">is</verb> <verb lemma="prod">prodded</verb> by a <verb lemma="guard">guard</verb> to the edge of the 
plank over the <verb lemma="gape">gaping</verb> Sarlacc. Luke looks up at Artoo, then gives a 
jaunty salute: the signal the little <verb lemma="droid">droid</verb> <verb lemma="have">has</verb> been waiting for. A <verb lemma="flap">flap</verb> 
opens in Artoo's domed head.</sd>

<sp><speaker>JABBA	 (in Huttese subtitled)</speaker>
<verb lemma="put">Put</verb> him in.</sp>

<setting>30   EXT SKIFF - PLANK</setting>

<sd>Luke <verb lemma="be">is</verb> <verb lemma="prod">prodded</verb> and jumps off the plank to the cheers of the 
bloodthirsty spectators. But, before anyone can even <verb lemma="perceive">perceive</verb> what <verb lemma="be">is</verb> 
happening, he spins around and grabs the end of the plank by his 
fingertips. The plank bends wildly from his weight and <verb lemma="catapult">catapults</verb> him 
skyward. In midair he does a <verb lemma="complete">complete</verb> <verb lemma="flip">flip</verb> and drops down on the end of 
the plank in the same <verb lemma="spot">spot</verb> he just vacated, but <verb lemma="face">facing</verb> the skiff. He 
casually extends an open palm and -- his lightsaber, which Artoo <verb lemma="have">has</verb> 
sent arcing toward him, drops into his hand.</sd>

<sd>With samurai speed, Luke ignites it and attacks the <verb lemma="guard">guard</verb> who <verb lemma="prod">prodded</verb> 
him off the plank, sending the hapless monster screaming overboard. The 
other guards <verb lemma="swarm">swarm</verb> toward Luke. He <verb lemma="wade">wades</verb> into them, lightsaber 
flashing. Lando struggles with another <verb lemma="guard">guard</verb> at the <verb lemma="back">back</verb> of the skiff.</sd>

<setting>31   EXT SARLACC PIT</setting>

<sd>A bewildered <verb lemma="guard">guard</verb> lands in the soft, sandy slope of the pit, and 
begins sliding. He <verb lemma="claw">claws</verb> desperately as a Sarlacc tentacle grabs him 
and pulls him screaming into the viscous mouth.</sd>

<setting>32   INT SAIL BARGE</setting>

<sd>Jabba watches this and explodes in rage. He <verb lemma="bark">barks</verb> commands, and the 
guards around him <verb lemma="rush">rush</verb> off to <verb lemma="do">do</verb> his bidding. The scuzzy creatures 
watching the action from the window <verb lemma="be">are</verb> in an uproar.</sd>

<setting>33   EXT SKIFF </setting>

<sd>Luke knocks another <verb lemma="guard">guard</verb> off the skiff and into the waiting mouth of 
the Sarlacc. He starts to untie Chewie's bonds.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
Easy, Chewie.</sp>

<sd>At that moment, the deck gunmen on the barge <verb lemma="unleash">unleash</verb> a series of blasts 
from a big cannon on the upper deck. Lando <verb lemma="be">is</verb> tossed from the deck of 
the rocking skiff. He <verb lemma="manage">manages</verb> to <verb lemma="grab">grab</verb> a rope, and dangles desperately 
above the Sarlacc pit.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LANDO</speaker>
Whoa! Whoa! Help!</sp>

<setting>34   EXT UPPER DECK - SAIL BARGE</setting>

<sd>With two swift strides, the dangerous Boba Fett ignites his rocket 
pack, leaps into the air, and <verb lemma="fly">flies</verb> from the barge down to the skiff.</sd>

<setting>35   EXT SKIFF</setting>

<sd>Boba lands on the skiff and starts to aim his laser <verb lemma="gun">gun</verb> at Luke, who 
<verb lemma="have">has</verb> freed Han and Chewie from their bonds. But before Boba can fire, 
the young Jedi spins on him, lightsaber sweeping, and hacks the bounty 
hunter's <verb lemma="gun">gun</verb> in half.</sd>

<sd>Immediately, the skiff takes another <verb lemma="direct">direct</verb> <verb lemma="hit">hit</verb> from the barge's deck 
gun. Shards of skiff deck fly. Chewie and Han <verb lemma="be">are</verb> thrown against the 
rail.</sd>

<sp><speaker>HAN</speaker>
Chewie, you okay? Where <verb lemma="be">is</verb> he?</sp>

<sd>The Wookiee <verb lemma="be">is</verb> <verb lemma="wound">wounded</verb> and he <verb lemma="howl">howls</verb> in pain.</sd>

<sp><speaker>HAN</speaker>
I'm okay, pal.</sp>

<sd>For a moment, Luke <verb lemma="be">is</verb> distracted, and in that moment, Boba fires a 
cable out of his armored sleeve. Instantly, Luke <verb lemma="be">is</verb> <verb lemma="wrap">wrapped</verb> in a strong 
cable, his arms <verb lemma="pin">pinned</verb> against his side, his sword arm <verb lemma="free">free</verb> only from 
the wrist down.  Luke bends his wrist so the lightsaber points straight 
up to <verb lemma="reach">reach</verb> the wire lasso and cuts through. Luke <verb lemma="shrug">shrugs</verb> away the cable 
and stands free.</sd>

<sd>Another <verb lemma="blast">blast</verb> from the Barge's deck <verb lemma="gun">gun</verb> hits near Boba and he <verb lemma="be">is</verb> 
knocked unconscious to the deck, next to where Lando <verb lemma="be">is</verb> hanging.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LANDO</speaker>
Han! Chewie?</sp>

<sp><speaker>HAN</speaker>
Lando!</sp>

<sd>Luke <verb lemma="be">is</verb> a little shaken but remains standing as a fusillade brackets 
him. The second skiff, loaded with guards <verb lemma="fire">firing</verb> their weapons, moves 
in on Luke fast. Luke leaps toward the incoming second skiff. The young 
Jedi leaps into the middle of the second skiff and begins <verb lemma="decimate">decimating</verb> 
the guards from their midst.</sd>

<sd>Chewie, wounded, <verb lemma="try">tries</verb> to <verb lemma="lift">lift</verb> himself as he <verb lemma="bark">barks</verb> directions to Han, 
<verb lemma="guide">guiding</verb> him toward a <verb lemma="spear">spear</verb> which <verb lemma="have">has</verb> been dropped by one of the guards. 
Han searches the deck as Chewie <verb lemma="bark">barks</verb> directions; finally he grabs <verb lemma="hold">hold</verb> 
of the spear.</sd>

<sd>Boba Fett, badly shaken, rises from the deck. He looks over at the 
other skiff, where Luke <verb lemma="be">is</verb> whipping a mass of guards. Boba raises his 
arm, and aims his lethal appendage.</sd>

<sd>Chewie <verb lemma="bark">barks</verb> desperately at Han.</sd>

<sp><speaker>HAN</speaker>
Boba Fett?! Boba Fett?! Where?</sp>

<sd>The space pirate turns around blindly, and the long <verb lemma="spear">spear</verb> in his <verb lemma="hand">hand</verb> 
whacks squarely in the middle of Boba's rocket pack.</sd>

<sd>The impact of the <verb lemma="swing">swing</verb> causes the rocket <verb lemma="pack">pack</verb> to ignite. Boba blasts 
off, flying over the second skiff <verb lemma="like">like</verb> a missile, smashing against the 
<verb lemma="side">side</verb> of the huge Sail Barge and <verb lemma="slide">sliding</verb> away into the pit. He screams 
as his armored body makes its <verb lemma="last">last</verb> flight past Lando and directly into 
the mucous mouth of the Sarlacc. The Sarlacc burps. Chewie growls a 
weak congratulations to Han.</sd>

<setting>36   INT SAIL BARGE</setting>

<sd>Leia turns from the spectacle outside, leaps onto Jabba's throne, and 
throws the chain that enslaves her over his <verb lemma="head">head</verb> around his bulbous 
neck. Then she dives off the other <verb lemma="side">side</verb> of the throne, pulling the 
chain violently in her grasp. Jabba's flaccid neck contracts beneath 
the tightening chain. His huge eyes <verb lemma="bulge">bulge</verb> from their sockets and his 
scum-coated tongue <verb lemma="flop">flops</verb> out. The <verb lemma="exalt">Exalted</verb> Hutt's huge tail spasms 
through its death throes and then slams down into final stillness. Leia 
struggles to <verb lemma="free">free</verb> herself of her bondage.</sd>

<setting>37   EXT SKIFF</setting>

<sd>Luke continues to <verb lemma="destroy">destroy</verb> the aliens on the guards' skiff, as Han 
extends his <verb lemma="spear">spear</verb> downward to Lando, who <verb lemma="be">is</verb> still <verb lemma="dangle">dangling</verb> precariously 
from a rope on the prisoner's skiff.</sd>

<sp><speaker>HAN</speaker>
Lando, <verb lemma="grab">grab</verb> it!</sp>

<sp><speaker>LANDO</speaker>
Lower it!</sp>

<sp><speaker>HAN</speaker>
I'm trying!</sp>

<sd>A major <verb lemma="hit">hit</verb> from the barge deck <verb lemma="gun">gun</verb> knocks the skiff on its side. Han 
and almost everything else on <verb lemma="board">board</verb> slides overboard. The rope breaks, 
and Lando falls to the <verb lemma="side">side</verb> of the Sarlacc pit. Luckily, Han's foot 
catches on the skiff railing and he dangles above Lando and the pit. 
The <verb lemma="wound">wounded</verb> Wookiee holds onto the skiff for dear life as another <verb lemma="hit">hit</verb> 
from the deck <verb lemma="gun">gun</verb> rocks the skiff violently.</sd>

<sp><speaker>HAN</speaker>
Whoa! Whoa! <verb lemma="grab">Grab</verb> me, Chewie! I'm slipping.</sp>

<sd>Chewie grabs <verb lemma="hold">hold</verb> of Han's feet, holding him upside down, as Han 
extends the <verb lemma="spear">spear</verb> toward Lando, who <verb lemma="be">is</verb> <verb lemma="clutch">clutching</verb> to the <verb lemma="side">side</verb> of the 
pit.</sd>

<sp><speaker>HAN</speaker>
<verb lemma="grab">Grab</verb> it! L--Lando. Grab!</sp>

<sd>Luke finishes off the <verb lemma="last">last</verb> <verb lemma="guard">guard</verb> on the second skiff. He sees the deck 
<verb lemma="gun">gun</verb> blasting away at his helpless companions. Luke leaps from the 
skiff, across a chasm of air, to the sheer metallic <verb lemma="side">side</verb> of the Sail 
Barge. Barely able to <verb lemma="get">get</verb> a fingerhold, he begins a painful <verb lemma="climb">climb</verb> up 
the hull, when suddenly an ax smashes through a window an inch from his 
head. With Jedi agility, Luke <verb lemma="grasp">grasps</verb> the wrist holding the ax and yanks 
the helpless <verb lemma="guard">guard</verb> through the <verb lemma="break">broken</verb> window and into the deadly pit.</sd>

<sd>The injured Chewie <verb lemma="be">is</verb> reaching over the rail for the <verb lemma="dangle">dangling</verb> Han, who 
<verb lemma="be">is</verb> in <verb lemma="turn">turn</verb> blindly reaching down toward the desperate Lando. The Baron 
<verb lemma="have">has</verb> stopped his slippage down the sandy slope of the Sarlacc pit by 
<verb lemma="lie">lying</verb> very still. Every time he <verb lemma="try">tries</verb> to <verb lemma="reach">reach</verb> for Han, the loose sand 
moves him closer to his final reward.</sd>

<sp><speaker>HAN</speaker>
<verb lemma="grab">Grab</verb> it! Almost... You almost got it!</sp>

<sd>Another <verb lemma="blast">blast</verb> hits the <verb lemma="front">front</verb> of the tilted skiff, <verb lemma="cause">causing</verb> Lando to <verb lemma="let">let</verb> 
<verb lemma="go">go</verb> of the spear.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LANDO</speaker>
<verb lemma="hold">Hold</verb> it! Whoa!</sp>

<sd>Again Han extends the <verb lemma="spear">spear</verb> toward Lando.</sd>

<sp><speaker>HAN</speaker>
Gently now. All... all right. Now easy, easy. <verb lemma="hold">Hold</verb> me, Chewie.</sp>

<sd>Lando screams. One of the Sarlacc's tentacles <verb lemma="have">has</verb> <verb lemma="wrap">wrapped</verb> tightly 
around his ankle, dragging him down the <verb lemma="side">side</verb> of the pit.</sd>

<sp><speaker>HAN</speaker>
Chewie! Chewie, <verb lemma="give">give</verb> me the gun. Don't move, Lando.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LANDO</speaker>
No, wait! I <verb lemma="think">thought</verb> you <verb lemma="be">were</verb> blind!</sp>

<sp><speaker>HAN</speaker>
It's all right. <verb lemma="trust">Trust</verb> me. Don't move.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LANDO</speaker>
All right! A little higher! Just a little higher!</sp>

<sd>Han adjusts his aim as Lando lowers his head, and the fuzzy-eyed pirate 
fires at the tentacle. Direct hit. The tentacle releases Lando, and 
Chewie starts to <verb lemma="pull">pull</verb> them on <verb lemma="board">board</verb> the skiff.</sd>

<sp><speaker>HAN</speaker>
Chewie, <verb lemma="pull">Pull</verb> us up! <verb lemma="come">Come</verb> on! Okay... up, Chewie, up!</sp>

<setting>38   EXT UPPER DECK</setting>

<sd>The deck gunners <verb lemma="have">have</verb> Chewie and the desperate <verb lemma="dangle">dangling</verb> human chain in 
their <verb lemma="gun">gun</verb> sights when something up on deck <verb lemma="command">commands</verb> their attention: 
Luke, standing before them <verb lemma="like">like</verb> a pirate king, ignites his lightsaber. 
The deck gunners <verb lemma="have">have</verb> barely reached for their pistols before the young 
Jedi <verb lemma="have">has</verb> <verb lemma="demolish">demolished</verb> them. Immediately, Luke turns to <verb lemma="see">see</verb> two more 
gunners (who <verb lemma="have">have</verb> been uncovering a giant <verb lemma="gun">gun</verb> at the end of the barge) 
<verb lemma="race">racing</verb> for him, <verb lemma="fire">firing</verb> their laser pistols.</sd>

<setting>39   INT SAIL BARGE - OBSERVATION DECK</setting>

<sd>Leia <verb lemma="be">is</verb> <verb lemma="struggle">struggling</verb> against her chains in desperation as Artoo zips 
through the tumult of <verb lemma="confuse">confused</verb> monsters to the rescue; the stubby 
little <verb lemma="droid">droid</verb> extends a small laser <verb lemma="gun">gun</verb> and blasts the chain apart.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LEIA</speaker>
<verb lemma="come">Come</verb> on. We gotta <verb lemma="get">get</verb> out of here quick.</sp>

<sd>Artoo and Leia <verb lemma="race">race</verb> for the exit, passing Threepio, who <verb lemma="be">is</verb> kicking and 
screaming as Salacious Crumb, the reptilian monkey- monster picks out 
one of the golden droid's eyes.</sd>

<sp><speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
Not my eyes! Artoo, help! Quickly, Artoo. Oh! Ohhh! You beast!</sp>

<sd>Artoo zips over and zaps Salacious, sending him skyward with a scream, 
crashing into the rafters as Artoo, Leia, and Threepio (with his <verb lemma="eye">eye</verb> 
<verb lemma="dangle">dangling</verb> from a wire) <verb lemma="hurry">hurry</verb> off.</sd>

<setting>40   EXT UPPER DECK - SAIL BARGE</setting>

<sd>Luke <verb lemma="be">is</verb> <verb lemma="ward">warding</verb> off laser blasts with his lightsaber, surrounded by 
guards and fighting <verb lemma="like">like</verb> a demon. Leia emerges onto the deck as Luke 
turns to <verb lemma="face">face</verb> another guard.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LUKE	 (to Leia)</speaker>
<verb lemma="get">Get</verb> the gun! <verb lemma="point">Point</verb> it at the deck!</sp>

<sd>Leia turns toward the barge cannon, climbs on the platform, and <verb lemma="swivel">swivels</verb> 
the <verb lemma="gun">gun</verb> around.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
<verb lemma="point">Point</verb> it at the deck!</sp>

<sd>A laser <verb lemma="blast">blast</verb> hits Luke's mechanical <verb lemma="hand">hand</verb> and he bends over in pain, 
but <verb lemma="manage">manages</verb> to <verb lemma="swing">swing</verb> his lightsaber upward and <verb lemma="take">take</verb> out the <verb lemma="last">last</verb> of the 
guards. He looks at the <verb lemma="wound">wounded</verb> hand, which reveals the mechanism. He 
<verb lemma="flex">flexes</verb> the hand; it still works.</sd>

<sd>Near the rail of the upper deck, Artoo and Threepio steady themselves 
as Threepio gets ready to jump. Artoo beeps wildly.</sd>

<sp><speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
Artoo, where <verb lemma="be">are</verb> we going? I couldn't possibly jump.</sp>

<sd>Artoo <verb lemma="butt">butts</verb> the golden <verb lemma="droid">droid</verb> over the edge and steps off himself, 
<verb lemma="tumble">tumbling</verb> toward the sand.</sd>

<sd>Luke runs along the empty deck toward Leia and the barge gun, which she 
<verb lemma="have">has</verb> <verb lemma="bring">brought</verb> around to <verb lemma="point">point</verb> down at the deck.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
<verb lemma="come">Come</verb> on!</sp>

<sd>Luke <verb lemma="have">has</verb> <verb lemma="hold">hold</verb> on one of the rigging ropes from the mast. He gathers 
Leia in his other arm and kicks the trigger of the deck gun. The <verb lemma="gun">gun</verb> 
explodes into the deck as Luke and Leia <verb lemma="swing">swing</verb> out toward the skiff.</sd>

<setting>41   EXT SKIFF  </setting>

<sd>Han <verb lemma="lean">leans</verb> <verb lemma="pant">panting</verb> against the rail as Chewie helps Lando onto the deck. 
Luke and Leia <verb lemma="land">land</verb> on the skiff with flair.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
Let's go! And don't forget the droids.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LANDO</speaker>
We're on our way.</sp>

<sd>The Sail Barge <verb lemma="be">is</verb> <verb lemma="explode">exploding</verb> in stages in the distance. Half of the huge 
craft <verb lemma="be">is</verb> on fire.</sd>

<setting>42   EXT SAND DUNE</setting>

<sd>Threepio's legs <verb lemma="stick">stick</verb> straight up from the dune where he landed. Next 
to it, Artoo's periscope <verb lemma="be">is</verb> the only thing above the sand. The skiff 
floats above them and two large electromagnets <verb lemma="dangle">dangle</verb> down on a wire. 
With a loud CLANG, both droids <verb lemma="be">are</verb> pulled 
from the sand.</sd>

<setting>43   EXT DUNE SEA</setting>

<sd>The little skiff <verb lemma="skip">skips</verb> around the burning Sail Barge, which continues 
its chain of explosions. As the skiff sails off across the desert, the 
barge settles to the sand and disappears in one final conflagration.</sd>

<setting>44   EXT DUNE SEA - LANDING AREA</setting>

<sd>A ferocious sandstorm blocks our view. Then, through the ROAR, we HEAR 
THE VOICES of our heroes. They <verb lemma="emerge">emerge</verb> slowly from the veil of sand, 
pressing on against the wind. First <verb lemma="come">come</verb> Artoo and Threepio, followed 
by Leia <verb lemma="guide">guiding</verb> Han, then Luke and Lando <verb lemma="come">come</verb> into view, each 
supporting one <verb lemma="side">side</verb> of the towe<verb lemma="ring">ring</verb> Chewbacca, who <verb lemma="hobble">hobbles</verb> from his 
wound.</sd>

<sd>Soon, they can <verb lemma="make">make</verb> out some large vague shapes in the blowing sand. It 
<verb lemma="be">is</verb> the Millennium Falcon and, <verb lemma="park">parked</verb> beside it, Luke's trusty X-wing 
and a two-seated Y-wing. They must <verb lemma="shout">shout</verb> to <verb lemma="be">be</verb> heard.</sd>

<sp><speaker>HAN</speaker>
I don't know. All I can <verb lemma="see">see</verb> <verb lemma="be">is</verb> a lot of blowing sand!</sp>

<sp><speaker>LEIA</speaker>
That's all any of us can see.</sp>

<sp><speaker>HAN	 (blinking)</speaker>
Then I <verb lemma="guess">guess</verb> I'm getting better.</sp>

<sd>As soon as the group <verb lemma="huddle">huddles</verb> under the bulk of the Falcon, the wind 
dies down to something more describable as a severe weather condition. 
Threepio hits a switch, and the gang-plank lowers with a HUM.</sd>

<sp><speaker>HAN 	(turning to Luke)</speaker>
I've got to <verb lemma="hand">hand</verb> it to you, kid, you <verb lemma="be">were</verb> pretty good out there.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE	 (shrugging it off)</speaker>
I <verb lemma="have">had</verb> a lot of help. <verb lemma="think">Think</verb> nothing of it.</sp>

<sp><speaker>HAN</speaker>
No, I'm thinking a lot about it. That carbon freeze <verb lemma="be">was</verb> the closest 
thing to dead there is. And it wasn't just sleepin'. It <verb lemma="be">was</verb> a big wide 
awake nothing!</sp>

<sd>Luke nods, as Chewie growls affectionately at the young Jedi warrior, 
<verb lemma="muss">mussing</verb> his hair <verb lemma="like">like</verb> a proud uncle. And Leia warmly hugs him.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LUKE 	(moving to his ship)</speaker>
I'll <verb lemma="see">see</verb> you <verb lemma="back">back</verb> at the fleet.</sp>

<sp><speaker>HAN</speaker>
Why don't you <verb lemma="leave">leave</verb> that crate and <verb lemma="come">come</verb> with us?</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
I <verb lemma="have">have</verb> a promise I <verb lemma="have">have</verb> to <verb lemma="keep">keep</verb> first... to an old friend.</sp>

<sd>Luke and Artoo <verb lemma="take">take</verb> off in their spacecraft.</sd>

<sp><speaker>HAN		</speaker>
(looking dubiously at Lando, obviously remembe<verb lemma="ring">ring</verb> his friend's 
betrayal and subsequent aide)
Guess I <verb lemma="owe">owe</verb> you some thanks, too, Lando.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LANDO</speaker>
<verb lemma="figure">Figured</verb> if I <verb lemma="leave">left</verb> you frozen <verb lemma="like">like</verb> that you'd just <verb lemma="give">give</verb> me bad luck the 
<verb lemma="rest">rest</verb> of my life, so I might as well <verb lemma="get">get</verb> you unfrozen sooner or later.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LEIA</speaker>
He means "You're welcome."</sp>

<sp><speaker>LANDO</speaker>
<verb lemma="come">Come</verb> on, let's <verb lemma="get">get</verb> off this miserable dust ball.</sp>

44A  EXT SPACE ABOVE TATOOINE 

<sd>The desolate yellow planet fills the screen, Luke's X-wing appears and 
peels off to the left. A moment later, the FALCON appears as a dot and 
grows huge, to <verb lemma="roar">roar</verb> directly over the CAMERA.</sd>

<setting>45   INT X-WING - COCKPIT</setting>

<sd>Luke <verb lemma="be">is</verb> at the controls, with Artoo attached behind him outside the 
canopy. Luke speaks into his <verb lemma="comlink">comlink</verb> to the others, in the MILLENNIUM 
FALCON.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
I'll <verb lemma="meet">meet</verb> you <verb lemma="back">back</verb> at the fleet.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LEIA	 (over comlink)</speaker>
Hurry. The Alliance should <verb lemma="be">be</verb> assembled by now.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
I will.</sp>

<sp><speaker>HAN	 (over comlink)</speaker>
Hey, Luke, thanks. Thanks for comin' after me. Now I <verb lemma="owe">owe</verb> you one.</sp>

<sd>A message from Artoo appears on the small monitor screen in <verb lemma="front">front</verb> of 
Luke. He smiles at the monitor and speaks to Artoo, as he pulls a black 
glove on to <verb lemma="cover">cover</verb> his <verb lemma="wound">wounded</verb> mechanical hand.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
That's right, Artoo. We're going to the Dagobah system. I <verb lemma="have">have</verb> a 
promise to keep... to an old friend.</sp>

<setting>46   EXT SPACE - DEATH STAR AND ENDOR</setting>

<sd>A Super Star Destroyer and several ships of the Imperial Fleet <verb lemma="rest">rest</verb> in 
space above the half-completed Death Star and its green neighbor, 
Endor. Four squads of TIE fighters <verb lemma="escort">escort</verb> an Imperial shuttle toward 
the Death Star.</sd>

<setting>47   INT DEATH STAR - CORRIDOR TO DOCKING BAY</setting>

<sd>Lord Vader strides down the hallway, <verb lemma="accompany">accompanied</verb> by a very nervous 
Death Star commander.</sd>

<setting>48   INT DOCKING BAY - DEATH STAR</setting>

<sd>Thousands of Imperial troops in tight formation <verb lemma="fill">fill</verb> the mammoth 
docking bay. Vader and the officer <verb lemma="walk">walk</verb> to the landing platform, where 
the shuttle <verb lemma="be">is</verb> coming to rest.</sd>

<sd>The shuttle's ramp lowers and the Emperor's Royal Guards <verb lemma="come">come</verb> out and 
create a lethal perimeter. The assembled troops <verb lemma="move">move</verb> to rigid attention 
with a momentous SNAP.</sd>

<sd>Then, in the huge SILENCE which follows, the EMPEROR appears. He <verb lemma="be">is</verb> a 
rather small, shriveled old man. His bent <verb lemma="frame">frame</verb> slowly makes its way 
down the ramp with the aid of a gnarled cane. He wears a hooded cloak 
similar to the one Ben wears, except that it <verb lemma="be">is</verb> black. The Emperor's 
<verb lemma="face">face</verb> <verb lemma="be">is</verb> <verb lemma="shroud">shrouded</verb> and difficult to see, except for his <verb lemma="pierce">piercing</verb> yellow 
eyes. Commander Jerjerrod and Darth Vader <verb lemma="kneel">kneel</verb> to him. The Supreme 
Ruler of the galaxy beckons to the Dark Lord.</sd>

<sp><speaker>EMPEROR	 (to Vader)</speaker>
Rise, my friend.</sp>

<sd>Vader rises and falls in next to the Emperor as he slowly makes his way 
along the rows of troops. Jerjerrod and the other commanders <verb lemma="stay">stay</verb> 
kneeling until the Supreme Ruler and Vader, followed by several 
Imperial dignitaries, <verb lemma="pass">pass</verb> by; only then <verb lemma="do">do</verb> they <verb lemma="join">join</verb> in the 
procession.</sd>

<sp><speaker>VADER</speaker>
The Death Star will <verb lemma="be">be</verb> completed on schedule.</sp>

<sp><speaker>EMPEROR</speaker>
You <verb lemma="have">have</verb> done well, Lord Vader. And now I sense you wish to <verb lemma="continue">continue</verb> 
your search for young Skywalker.</sp>

<sp><speaker>VADER</speaker>
Yes, my Master.</sp>

<sp><speaker>EMPEROR</speaker>
Patience, my friend. In time he will seek you out. And when he does, 
you must <verb lemma="bring">bring</verb> him
before me. He <verb lemma="have">has</verb> grown strong. Only together can we <verb lemma="turn">turn</verb> him to the 
dark <verb lemma="side">side</verb> of the
Force.</sp>

<sp><speaker>VADER</speaker>
As you wish.</sp>

<sp><speaker>EMPEROR</speaker>
Everything <verb lemma="be">is</verb> proceeding as I <verb lemma="have">have</verb> foreseen.</sp>

<sd>He laughs to himself as they <verb lemma="pass">pass</verb> along the vast line of Imperial 
troops.</sd>

<setting>49   EXT YODA'S HOUSE - DAGOBAH</setting>

<sd>Once again, Artoo finds himself waiting around in the damp environs of 
the swamp planet, and he's none too happy about it. He beeps 
disconsolately to himself and turns to <verb lemma="look">look</verb> at Yoda's cottage. Warm 
yellow <verb lemma="light">light</verb> escapes the oddly <verb lemma="shape">shaped</verb> windows to <verb lemma="fight">fight</verb> the gloom.</sd>

<setting>50   INT YODA'S HOUSE</setting>

<sd>The tip of a walking <verb lemma="stick">stick</verb> <verb lemma="tap">taps</verb> hesitantly across the earthen floor of 
the cottage. Our view travels up the <verb lemma="stick">stick</verb> to the small green <verb lemma="hand">hand</verb> that 
<verb lemma="clutch">clutches</verb> it, and then to the familiar <verb lemma="face">face</verb> of YODA, THE JEDI MASTER. 
His manner <verb lemma="be">is</verb> frail, and his voice, though cheerful, seems weaker.</sd>

<sp><speaker>YODA</speaker>
Hmm. That <verb lemma="face">face</verb> you make. <verb lemma="look">Look</verb> I so old to young eyes?</sp>

<sd>Luke <verb lemma="be">is</verb> sitting in a corner of the cramped space and, indeed, his <verb lemma="look">look</verb> 
<verb lemma="have">has</verb> been woeful. Caught, he <verb lemma="try">tries</verb> to <verb lemma="hide">hide</verb> it.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
No... of <verb lemma="course">course</verb> not.</sp>

<sp><speaker>YODA	 (tickled, chuckles)</speaker>
I do, yes, I do!  Sick <verb lemma="have">have</verb> I become. Old and weak. 
(Points a crooked finger)
When nine hundred years old you reach, <verb lemma="look">look</verb> as good you will not. Hmm?</sp>

<sd>Yoda chuckles at this, coughs, and <verb lemma="hobble">hobbles</verb> over toward his bed.</sd>

<sp><speaker>YODA</speaker>
Soon will I rest. Yes, forever sleep. <verb lemma="earn">Earned</verb> it, I have.</sp>

<sd>Yoda sits himself on his bed, with great effort.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
Master Yoda, you can't die.</sp>

<sp><speaker>YODA</speaker>
Strong am I with the Force... but not that strong! Twilight <verb lemma="be">is</verb> upon me 
and soon night must fall. That <verb lemma="be">is</verb> the way of things... the way of the 
Force.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
But I <verb lemma="need">need</verb> your help. I've <verb lemma="come">come</verb> <verb lemma="back">back</verb> to <verb lemma="complete">complete</verb> the training.</sp>

<sp><speaker>YODA</speaker>
No more training <verb lemma="do">do</verb> you require. Already <verb lemma="know">know</verb> you that which you need.</sp>

<sd>Yoda sighs, and lies <verb lemma="back">back</verb> on his bed.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
Then I am a Jedi?</sp>

<sp><speaker>YODA	 (shakes his head)</speaker>
Ohhh. Not yet. One thing remains: Vader. You must <verb lemma="confront">confront</verb> Vader. Then, 
only then, a Jedi will you be. And <verb lemma="confront">confront</verb> him you will.</sp>

<sd>Luke <verb lemma="be">is</verb> in agony. He <verb lemma="be">is</verb> silent for a long moment, <verb lemma="screw">screwing</verb> up his 
courage. Finally he <verb lemma="be">is</verb> able to ask.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
Master Yoda... <verb lemma="be">is</verb> Darth Vader my father?</sp>

<sd>Yoda's eyes <verb lemma="be">are</verb> full of weariness and compassion. An odd, sad <verb lemma="smile">smile</verb> 
<verb lemma="crease">creases</verb> his face. He turns painfully on his side, away from Luke.</sd>

<sp><speaker>YODA</speaker>
Mmm... <verb lemma="rest">rest</verb> I need. Yes... rest.</sp>

<sd>Luke watches him, each moment an eternity.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
Yoda, I must know.</sp>

<sp><speaker>YODA</speaker>
Your father he is.</sp>

<sd>Luke reacts as if cut.</sd>

<sp><speaker>YODA</speaker>
<verb lemma="tell">Told</verb> you, <verb lemma="do">did</verb> he?</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
Yes.</sp>

<sd>A new <verb lemma="look">look</verb> of <verb lemma="concern">concern</verb> crosses Yoda's face.  He closes his eyes.</sd>

<sp><speaker>YODA</speaker>
Unexpected this is, and unfortunate...</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
Unfortunate that I <verb lemma="know">know</verb> the truth?</sp>

<sd>Yoda opens his eyes again and studies the youth.</sd>

<sp><speaker>YODA		 (gathering all his strength)</speaker>
No. Unfortunate that you rushed to <verb lemma="face">face</verb> him... that incomplete <verb lemma="be">was</verb> your 
training. Not
ready for the burden <verb lemma="be">were</verb> you.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
Well, I'm sorry.</sp>

<sp><speaker>YODA</speaker>
Remember, a Jedi's strength flows from the Force.  But beware.  Anger, 
fear, aggression.
The dark <verb lemma="side">side</verb> <verb lemma="be">are</verb> they.  Once you <verb lemma="start">start</verb> down the dark path, forever 
will it dominate your
destiny.</sp>

<sd>He beckons the young Jedi closer to him.</sd>

<sp><speaker>YODA</speaker>
Luke...Luke...Do not...Do not underestim<verb lemma="eat">ate</verb> the powers of the Emperor, 
or <verb lemma="suffer">suffer</verb> your father's fate, you will. Luke, when gone am I
(cough),
the <verb lemma="last">last</verb> of the Jedi will you be. Luke, the Force runs strong in your 
family. <verb lemma="pass">Pass</verb> on what you <verb lemma="have">have</verb> learned, Luke... 
(with great effort)
There is...another...Sky...Sky...walker.</sp>

<sd>He catches his breath. A shiver runs through the ancient green 
creature, and he dies. Luke stares at his dead master as he disappears 
in <verb lemma="front">front</verb> of his eyes.</sd>

<setting>51   EXT DAGOBAH SWAMP - X-WING </setting>

<sd>Luke <verb lemma="wander">wanders</verb> <verb lemma="back">back</verb> to where his <verb lemma="ship">ship</verb> <verb lemma="be">is</verb> sitting. Artoo beeps a greeting, 
but <verb lemma="be">is</verb> ignored by his depressed master. Luke kneels down, begins to 
<verb lemma="help">help</verb> Artoo with the ship, then stops and shakes his <verb lemma="head">head</verb> dejectedly.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
I can't <verb lemma="do">do</verb> it, Artoo. I can't <verb lemma="go">go</verb> on alone.</sp>

<sp><speaker>BEN	 (OS)</speaker>
Yoda will always <verb lemma="be">be</verb> with you.</sp>

<sd>Luke looks up to <verb lemma="see">see</verb> the shimmering image of BEN KENOBI.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
Obi-Wan! Why didn't you <verb lemma="tell">tell</verb> me?</sp>

<sd>The ghost of Ben Kenobi approaches him through the swamp.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
You <verb lemma="tell">told</verb> me Vader betrayed and <verb lemma="murder">murdered</verb> my father.</sp>

<sp><speaker>BEN</speaker>
You father <verb lemma="be">was</verb> <verb lemma="seduce">seduced</verb> by the dark <verb lemma="side">side</verb> of the Force. He <verb lemma="cease">ceased</verb> to <verb lemma="be">be</verb> 
Anakin Skywalker
and became Darth Vader. When that happened, the good man who <verb lemma="be">was</verb> your 
father <verb lemma="be">was</verb> destroyed. So what I <verb lemma="have">have</verb> <verb lemma="tell">told</verb> you <verb lemma="be">was</verb> true... from a 
certain <verb lemma="point">point</verb> of view.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE	 (turning away, derisive)</speaker>
A certain <verb lemma="point">point</verb> of view!</sp>

<sp><speaker>BEN</speaker>
Luke, you're going to <verb lemma="find">find</verb> that many of the truths we <verb lemma="cling">cling</verb> to <verb lemma="depend">depend</verb> 
greatly on our own
<verb lemma="point">point</verb> of view.</sp>

<sd>Luke <verb lemma="be">is</verb> unresponsive. Ben studies him in silence for a moment.</sd>

<sp><speaker>BEN</speaker>
I don't <verb lemma="blame">blame</verb> you for being angry. If I <verb lemma="be">was</verb> wrong in what I did, it 
certainly wouldn't <verb lemma="have">have</verb> been for the first time. You see, what happened 
to your father <verb lemma="be">was</verb> my fault.</sp>

<sd>Ben pauses sadly.</sd>

<sp><speaker>BEN</speaker>
Anakin <verb lemma="be">was</verb> a good friend.</sp>

<sd>Luke turns with interest at this. As Ben speaks, Luke settles on a 
stump, mesmerized. Artoo comes over to <verb lemma="offer">offer</verb> his comforting presence.</sd>

<sp><speaker>BEN</speaker>
When I first <verb lemma="know">knew</verb> him, your father <verb lemma="be">was</verb> already a great pilot. But I <verb lemma="be">was</verb> 
amazed how strongly the Force <verb lemma="be">was</verb> with him. I <verb lemma="take">took</verb> it upon myself to 
train him as a Jedi. I <verb lemma="think">thought</verb> that I could <verb lemma="instruct">instruct</verb> him just as well 
as Yoda. I <verb lemma="be">was</verb> wrong. My pride <verb lemma="have">has</verb> <verb lemma="have">had</verb> terrible consequences for the 
galaxy.</sp>

<sd>Luke <verb lemma="be">is</verb> entranced.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
There's still good in him.</sp>

<sp><speaker>BEN</speaker>
I also <verb lemma="think">thought</verb> he could <verb lemma="be">be</verb> turned <verb lemma="back">back</verb> to the good side. It couldn't <verb lemma="be">be</verb> 
done. He <verb lemma="be">is</verb> more machine now than man. <verb lemma="twist">Twisted</verb> and evil.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
I can't <verb lemma="do">do</verb> it, Ben.</sp>

<sp><speaker>BEN</speaker>
You cannot <verb lemma="escape">escape</verb> your destiny.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
I <verb lemma="try">tried</verb> to <verb lemma="stop">stop</verb> him once. I couldn't <verb lemma="do">do</verb> it.</sp>

<sp><speaker>BEN</speaker>
Vader <verb lemma="humble">humbled</verb> you when first you <verb lemma="meet">met</verb> him, Luke... but that experience 
<verb lemma="be">was</verb> part of your training. It <verb lemma="teach">taught</verb> you, among other things, the value 
of patience. Had you not been so impatient to <verb lemma="defeat">defeat</verb> Vader then, you 
could <verb lemma="have">have</verb> finished your training here with Yoda. You would <verb lemma="have">have</verb> been 
prepared.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
But I <verb lemma="have">had</verb> to <verb lemma="help">help</verb> my friends.</sp>

<sp><speaker>BEN	 (grinning at Luke's indignation)</speaker>
And <verb lemma="do">did</verb> you <verb lemma="help">help</verb> them? It <verb lemma="be">was</verb> they who <verb lemma="have">had</verb> to <verb lemma="save">save</verb> you. You achieved 
little by rushing <verb lemma="back">back</verb> prematurely, I fear.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE	 (with sadness)</speaker>
I <verb lemma="find">found</verb> out Darth Vader <verb lemma="be">was</verb> my father.</sp>

<sp><speaker>BEN</speaker>
To <verb lemma="be">be</verb> a Jedi, Luke, you must <verb lemma="confront">confront</verb> and then <verb lemma="go">go</verb> beyond the dark <verb lemma="side">side</verb> 
- the <verb lemma="side">side</verb> your father couldn't <verb lemma="get">get</verb> past. Impatience <verb lemma="be">is</verb> the easiest 
door - for you, <verb lemma="like">like</verb> your father. Only, your father <verb lemma="be">was</verb> <verb lemma="seduce">seduced</verb> by what 
he <verb lemma="find">found</verb> on the other <verb lemma="side">side</verb> of the door, and you <verb lemma="have">have</verb> <verb lemma="hold">held</verb> firm. You're 
no longer so reckless now, Luke. You <verb lemma="be">are</verb> strong and patient. And now, 
you must <verb lemma="face">face</verb> Darth Vader again!</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
I can't <verb lemma="kill">kill</verb> my own father.</sp>

<sp><speaker>BEN</speaker>
Then the Emperor <verb lemma="have">has</verb> already won. You <verb lemma="be">were</verb> our only hope.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
Yoda spoke of another.</sp>

<sp><speaker>BEN</speaker>
The other he spoke of <verb lemma="be">is</verb> your twin sister.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
But I <verb lemma="have">have</verb> no sister.</sp>

<sp><speaker>BEN</speaker>
Hmm. To <verb lemma="protect">protect</verb> you both from the Emperor, you <verb lemma="be">were</verb> hidden from your 
father when you <verb lemma="be">were</verb> born. The Emperor knew, as I did, if Anakin <verb lemma="be">were</verb> 
to <verb lemma="have">have</verb> any offspring, they would <verb lemma="be">be</verb> a threat to him. That <verb lemma="be">is</verb> the 
reason why your sister remains safely anonymous.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
Leia! Leia's my sister.</sp>

<sp><speaker>BEN</speaker>
Your insight serves you well. <verb lemma="bury">Bury</verb> your feelings deep down, Luke. They 
<verb lemma="do">do</verb> you credit.
But they could <verb lemma="be">be</verb> <verb lemma="make">made</verb> to <verb lemma="serve">serve</verb> the Emperor.</sp>

<sd>Luke looks into the distance, trying to <verb lemma="comprehend">comprehend</verb> all this.</sd>

<sp><speaker>BEN	 (continuing his narrative)</speaker>
When your father left, he didn't <verb lemma="know">know</verb> your mother <verb lemma="be">was</verb> pregnant. Your 
mother and I <verb lemma="know">knew</verb> he would <verb lemma="find">find</verb> out eventually, but we wanted to <verb lemma="keep">keep</verb> 
you both as safe as possible, for as long as possible.  So I <verb lemma="take">took</verb> you 
to <verb lemma="live">live</verb> with my brother Owen on Tatooine... and your mother <verb lemma="take">took</verb> Leia 
to <verb lemma="live">live</verb> as the daughter of Senator Organa, on Alderaan.</sp>

<sd>Luke turns, and settles near Ben to <verb lemma="hear">hear</verb> the tale.</sd>

<sp><speaker>BEN	 (attempting to <verb lemma="give">give</verb> solace with his words)</speaker>
The Organa house<verb lemma="hold">hold</verb> <verb lemma="be">was</verb> high-born and politically quite powerful in 
that system. Leia became a princess by virtue of lineage... no one <verb lemma="know">knew</verb> 
she'd been adopted, of course. But it <verb lemma="be">was</verb> a title without real power, 
since Alderaan <verb lemma="have">had</verb> long been a democracy.  Even so, the family 
continued to <verb lemma="be">be</verb> politically powerful, and Leia, following in her foster 
father's path, became a senator as well.  That's not all she became, of 
course... she became the leader of her cell in the Alliance against the 
corrupt Empire. And because she <verb lemma="have">had</verb> diplomatic immunity, she <verb lemma="be">was</verb> a 
vital link for getting information to the Rebel cause.  That's what she 
<verb lemma="be">was</verb> doing when her path crossed yours... for her foster parents <verb lemma="have">had</verb> 
always <verb lemma="tell">told</verb> her to contact me on Tatooine, if her troubles became 
desperate.</sp>

<sd>Luke <verb lemma="be">is</verb> overwhelmed by the truth, and <verb lemma="be">is</verb> suddenly protective of his 
sister.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
But you can't <verb lemma="let">let</verb> her <verb lemma="get">get</verb> <verb lemma="involve">involved</verb> now, Ben. Vader will <verb lemma="destroy">destroy</verb> her.</sp>

<sp><speaker>BEN</speaker>
She hasn't been trained in the ways of the Jedi the way you have, 
Luke... but the Force <verb lemma="be">is</verb> strong with her, as it <verb lemma="be">is</verb> with all of your 
family. There <verb lemma="be">is</verb> no avoiding the battle. You must <verb lemma="face">face</verb> and <verb lemma="destroy">destroy</verb> 
Vader!</sp>

<setting>52   EXT SPACE - REBEL FLEET</setting>

<sd>The vast Rebel Fleet stretches as far as the <verb lemma="eye">eye</verb> can see. Overhead a 
dozen small Corellian battleships <verb lemma="fly">fly</verb> in formation. Fighters and 
battlecruisers surround the largest of the Rebel Star Cruisers, the 
HEADQUARTERS FRIGATE.</sd>

<setting>53   INT HEADQUARTERS FRIGATE - MAIN BRIEFING ROOM</setting>

<sd>Hundreds of Rebel commanders of all races and forms <verb lemma="be">are</verb> assembled in 
the WAR ROOM. WEDGE <verb lemma="be">is</verb> among them. In the <verb lemma="center">center</verb> of the room <verb lemma="be">is</verb> a 
holographic model <verb lemma="depict">depicting</verb> the half-completed Imperial Death Star, the 
nearby Moon of Endor, and the protecting deflector shield.</sd>

<sp><speaker>MON MOTHMA, the leader of the Alliance, enters the room. She <verb lemma="be">is</verb> a stern </speaker>
but beautiful woman in her fifties. <verb lemma="confer">Conferring</verb> with her <verb lemma="be">are</verb> several 
military leaders, <verb lemma="include">including</verb> GENERAL MADINE and ADMIRAL ACKBAR (a 
salmon-colored Mon Calamari). Lando moves through the <verb lemma="crowd">crowd</verb> until he 
finds Han and Chewie, standing next to Leia and the two droids.</sp>

<sd>Han peers at Lando's new insignia on his chest, and <verb lemma="be">is</verb> amused.</sd>

<sp><speaker>HAN</speaker>
Well, <verb lemma="look">look</verb> at you, a general, huh?</sp>

 LANDO
 Oh, well, someone must <verb lemma="have">have</verb> <verb lemma="tell">told</verb> them about my little <verb lemma="maneuver">maneuver</verb> at the 
<verb lemma="battle">battle</verb> of Taanab.

<sp><speaker>HAN	 (sarcastic)</speaker>
Well, don't <verb lemma="look">look</verb> at me, pal. I just said you <verb lemma="be">were</verb> a fair pilot. I 
didn't <verb lemma="know">know</verb> they <verb lemma="be">were</verb>
lookin' for somebody to <verb lemma="lead">lead</verb> this crazy attack.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LANDO	 (smiling)</speaker>
I'm surprised they didn't <verb lemma="ask">ask</verb> you to <verb lemma="do">do</verb> it.</sp>

<sp><speaker>HAN</speaker>
Well, who says they didn't.  But I ain't crazy. You're the respectable 
one, remember?</sp>

<sd>Mon Mothma signals for attention, and the room falls silent.</sd>

<sp><speaker>MON MOTHMA</speaker>
The Emperor <verb lemma="have">has</verb> <verb lemma="make">made</verb> a critical error and the time for our <verb lemma="attack">attack</verb> <verb lemma="have">has</verb> 
come.</sp>

<sd>This causes a stir. Mon Mothma turns to a holographic model of the 
Death Star, the Endor moon and the protecting deflector <verb lemma="shield">shield</verb> in the 
<verb lemma="center">center</verb> of the room.</sd>

<sp><speaker>MON MOTHMA</speaker>
The data <verb lemma="bring">brought</verb> to us by the Bothan <verb lemma="spy">spies</verb> <verb lemma="pinpoint">pinpoints</verb> the exact location 
of the Emperor's new <verb lemma="battle">battle</verb> station. We also <verb lemma="know">know</verb> that the weapon 
systems of this Death Star <verb lemma="be">are</verb> not yet operational. With the Imperial 
Fleet spread throughout the galaxy in a vain effort to engage us, it <verb lemma="be">is</verb> 
relatively unprotected. But most important of all, we've learned that 
the Emperor himself <verb lemma="be">is</verb> personally overseeing the final stages of the 
construction of this Death Star.</sp>

<sd>A volley of spirited chatter erupts from the crowd. Han turns to Leia 
as Chewie <verb lemma="bark">barks</verb> his amazement.</sd>

<sp><speaker>MON MOTHMA	 (cont)</speaker>
Many Bothans died to <verb lemma="bring">bring</verb> us this information. Admiral Ackbar, please.</sp>

<sd>Admiral Ackbar steps forward and points to the Death Star's <verb lemma="force">force</verb> field 
and the Moon of Endor.</sd>

<sp><speaker>ACKBAR</speaker>
You can <verb lemma="see">see</verb> here the Death Star <verb lemma="orbit">orbiting</verb> the forest Moon of Endor. 
Although the weapon
systems on this Death Star <verb lemma="be">are</verb> not yet operational, the Death Star does 
<verb lemma="have">have</verb> a strong defense mechanism. It <verb lemma="be">is</verb> protected by an energy shield, 
which <verb lemma="be">is</verb> generated from the nearby forest Moon of Endor. The <verb lemma="shield">shield</verb> 
must <verb lemma="be">be</verb> deactivated if any <verb lemma="attack">attack</verb> <verb lemma="be">is</verb> to <verb lemma="be">be</verb> attempted. Once the <verb lemma="shield">shield</verb> 
<verb lemma="be">is</verb> down, our cruisers will create a perimeter, while the fighters <verb lemma="fly">fly</verb> 
into the superstructure and <verb lemma="attempt">attempt</verb> to <verb lemma="knock">knock</verb> out the main reactor.</sp>

<sd>There's a concerned murmur.</sd>

<sp><speaker>ACKBAR	 (cont)</speaker>
General Calrissian <verb lemma="have">has</verb> volunteered to <verb lemma="lead">lead</verb> the fighter attack</sp>

<sd>Han turns to Lando with a <verb lemma="look">look</verb> of respect.</sd>

<sp><speaker>HAN</speaker>
Good luck.</sp>

<sd>Lando nods his thanks.</sd>

<sp><speaker>HAN</speaker>
You're gonna <verb lemma="need">need</verb> it.</sp>

<sp><speaker>ACKBAR</speaker>
General Madine.</sp>

<sd>Madine moves <verb lemma="center">center</verb> stage.</sd>

<sp><speaker>GENERAL MADINE</speaker>
We <verb lemma="have">have</verb> stolen a small Imperial shuttle. <verb lemma="disguise">Disgu<verb lemma="be">is</verb>ed</verb> as a cargo ship, and 
<verb lemma="use">using</verb> a secret
Imperial code, a <verb lemma="strike">strike</verb> team will <verb lemma="land">land</verb> on the moon and deactiv<verb lemma="eat">ate</verb> the 
<verb lemma="shield">shield</verb> generator.</sp>

<sd>The assembly begins to <verb lemma="mumble">mumble</verb> among themselves.</sd>

<sp><speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
<verb lemma="sound">Sounds</verb> dangerous.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LEIA	 (to Han)</speaker>
I wonder who they <verb lemma="find">found</verb> to <verb lemma="pull">pull</verb> that off.</sp>

<sp><speaker>GENERAL MADINE</speaker>
General Solo, <verb lemma="be">is</verb> your <verb lemma="strike">strike</verb> team assembled?</sp>

<sd>Leia, startled, looks up at Han, surprise <verb lemma="change">changing</verb> to admiration.</sd>

<sp><speaker>HAN</speaker>
Uh, my team's ready. I don't <verb lemma="have">have</verb> a command crew for the shuttle.</sp>

<sd>Chewbacca raises his hairy paw and volunteers.  Han looks up at him.</sd>

<sp><speaker>HAN</speaker>
Well, it's gonna <verb lemma="be">be</verb> rough, pal. I didn't <verb lemma="want">want</verb> to <verb lemma="speak">speak</verb> for you.</sp>

<sd>Chewie waves that off with a huge GROWL.</sd>

<sp><speaker>HAN	 (smiles)</speaker>
That's one.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LEIA</speaker>
Uh, General... <verb lemma="count">count</verb> me in.</sp>

<sp><speaker>VOICE	 (OS)</speaker>
I'm with you, too!</sp>

<sd>They <verb lemma="turn">turn</verb> in that direction and <verb lemma="peer">peer</verb> into the <verb lemma="crowd">crowd</verb> as there <verb lemma="be">are</verb> more 
cheers. The commanders part, and there at the <verb lemma="back">back</verb> stands Luke. Han and 
Leia <verb lemma="be">are</verb> surprised and delighted.</sd>

<sd>Leia moves to Luke and embraces him warmly. She senses a <verb lemma="change">change</verb> in him 
and looks into his eyes questioningly.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LEIA</speaker>
 What <verb lemma="be">is</verb> it?</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE	 (hesitant)</speaker>
<verb lemma="ask">Ask</verb> me again sometime.</sp>

<sd>Han, Chewie, and Lando <verb lemma="crowd">crowd</verb> around Luke as the assembly breaks up.</sd>

<sp><speaker>HAN</speaker>
Luke.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
Hi, Han... Chewie.</sp>

<sd>Artoo beeps a singsong observation to a <verb lemma="worry">worried</verb> Threepio.</sd>

 THREEPIO
"Exciting" <verb lemma="be">is</verb> hardly the word I would use.

<setting>54   INT HEADQUARTERS FRIGATE - MAIN DOCKING BAY</setting>

<sd>The Millennium Falcon rests beyond the stolen IMPERIAL SHUTTLE, which 
looks anomalous among all the Rebel ships in the vast docking bay. 
Chewie <verb lemma="bark">barks</verb> a final farewell to Lando and leads Artoo and Threepio up 
the shuttle, crowded now with the Rebel <verb lemma="strike">strike</verb> team loading weapons and 
supplies. Lando turns to <verb lemma="face">face</verb> Han. Luke and Leia <verb lemma="have">have</verb> said their good-
byes and <verb lemma="start">start</verb> up the ramp.</sd>

<sp><speaker>HAN</speaker>
Look. I <verb lemma="want">want</verb> you to <verb lemma="take">take</verb> her. I <verb lemma="mean">mean</verb> it. <verb lemma="take">Take</verb> her. You <verb lemma="need">need</verb> all the 
<verb lemma="help">help</verb> you can get. She's
the fastest <verb lemma="ship">ship</verb> in the fleet.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LANDO</speaker>
All right, old buddy. You know, I <verb lemma="know">know</verb> what she means to you. I'll <verb lemma="take">take</verb> 
good care of her.
She-she won't <verb lemma="get">get</verb> a scratch. All right?</sp>

<sp><speaker>HAN	 (looks at him warmly)</speaker>
Right. I got your promise now. Not a scratch.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LANDO</speaker>
Look, would you <verb lemma="get">get</verb> going, you pirate.</sp>

<sd>Han and Lando pause, then exchange salutes.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LANDO</speaker>
Good luck.</sp>

<sp><speaker>HAN</speaker>
You, too.</sp>

<sd>Han goes up the ramp. Lando watches him <verb lemma="go">go</verb> and then slowly turns away.</sd>

<setting>55   INT IMPERIAL SHUTTLE - COCKPIT</setting>

<sd>Luke <verb lemma="be">is</verb> working on a <verb lemma="back">back</verb> <verb lemma="control">control</verb> panel as Han comes in and takes the 
pilot's seat. Chewie, in the seat next to him, <verb lemma="be">is</verb> trying to <verb lemma="figure">figure</verb> out 
all the Imperial controls.</sd>

<sp><speaker>HAN</speaker>
You got her warmed?</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
Yeah, she's comin' up.</sp>

<sd>Chewie growls a complaint.</sd>

<sp><speaker>HAN</speaker>
No. I don't think the Empire <verb lemma="have">had</verb> Wookiees in <verb lemma="mind">mind</verb> when they <verb lemma="design">designed</verb> 
her, Chewie.</sp>

<sd>Leia comes in from the <verb lemma="hold">hold</verb> and takes her seat near Luke.</sd>

<sd>Chewie <verb lemma="bark">barks</verb> and hits some switches. Han's glance <verb lemma="have">has</verb> <verb lemma="stick">stuck</verb> on 
something out the window: the Millennium Falcon. Leia <verb lemma="nudge">nudges</verb> him 
gently.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LEIA</speaker>
Hey, <verb lemma="be">are</verb> you awake?</sp>

<sp><speaker>HAN</speaker>
Yeah, I just got a funny feeling. Like I'm not gonna <verb lemma="see">see</verb> her again.</sp>

<sd>Chewie, hearing this, stops his activity and looks longingly out at the 
Falcon, too. Leia puts a <verb lemma="hand">hand</verb> on Han's shoulder.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LEIA	 (softly)</speaker>
<verb lemma="come">Come</verb> on, General, let's move.</sp>

<sd>Han snaps <verb lemma="back">back</verb> to life.</sd>

<sp><speaker>HAN</speaker>
Right. Chewie, let's <verb lemma="see">see</verb> what this piece of junk can do. Ready, 
everybody?</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
All set.</sp>

<sp><speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
Here we <verb lemma="go">go</verb> again.</sp>

<sp><speaker>HAN</speaker>
All right, <verb lemma="hang">hang</verb> on.</sp>

<setting>56   EXT SPACE - THE REBEL FLEET</setting>

<sd>The stolen Imperial shuttle leaves the main docking bay of the 
Headquarters Frigate, lowers its wings into flight position, and zooms 
off into space.</sd>

<setting>57   INT EMPEROR'S THRONE ROOM</setting>

<sd>The converted <verb lemma="control">control</verb> room <verb lemma="be">is</verb> dimly lit, except for a pool of <verb lemma="light">light</verb> at 
the far end. There the Emperor sits in an elaborate <verb lemma="control">control</verb> chair 
before a large window which looks out across the half-completed Death 
Star to the giant green moon of Endor.</sd>

<sd>Darth Vader, standing with other members of the Imperial council, 
cautiously approaches his master. The ruler's <verb lemma="back">back</verb> <verb lemma="be">is</verb> to Vader. After 
several tense moments, the Emperor's chair rotates around to <verb lemma="face">face</verb> him.</sd>

<sp><speaker>VADER</speaker>
What <verb lemma="be">is</verb> thy bidding, my Master?</sp>

<sp><speaker>EMPEROR</speaker>
<verb lemma="send">Send</verb> the fleet to the far <verb lemma="side">side</verb> of Endor. There it will <verb lemma="stay">stay</verb> until 
called for.</sp>

<sp><speaker>VADER</speaker>
What of the reports of the Rebel fleet <verb lemma="mass">massing</verb> near Sullust?</sp>

<sp><speaker>EMPEROR</speaker>
It <verb lemma="be">is</verb> of no concern. Soon the Rebellion will <verb lemma="be">be</verb> crushed and young 
Skywalker will <verb lemma="be">be</verb> one of us! Your <verb lemma="work">work</verb> here <verb lemma="be">is</verb> finished, my friend. <verb lemma="go">Go</verb> 
out to the command <verb lemma="ship">ship</verb> and await my orders.</sp>

<sp><speaker>VADER</speaker>
Yes, my Master.</sp>

<sd>Vader bows, then turns and exits the throne room as the Emperor walks 
toward the waiting council members.</sd>

<setting>58   EXT SPACE - DEATH STAR - MOON</setting>

<sd>There <verb lemma="be">is</verb> a great <verb lemma="deal">deal</verb> of Imperial traffic in the area as construction 
proceeds on the Death Star. Transports, TIE fighters, and a few Star 
Destroyers <verb lemma="move">move</verb> about. Now the huge Super Star Destroyer <verb lemma="announce">announces</verb> 
itself with a low <verb lemma="roar">roar</verb> and soon fills the frame.</sd>

<setting>59   INT STOLEN IMPERIAL SHUTTLE - COCKPIT</setting>

<sd>Han looks <verb lemma="back">back</verb> at Luke and Leia as Chewie flips several switches. 
Through the viewscreen, the Death Star and the huge Super Star 
Destroyer can <verb lemma="be">be</verb> seen.</sd>

<sp><speaker>HAN</speaker>
If they don't <verb lemma="go">go</verb> for this, we're gonna <verb lemma="have">have</verb> to <verb lemma="get">get</verb> outta here pretty 
quick, Chewie.</sp>

<sd>Chewie growls his agreement.</sd>

<sp><speaker>CONTROLLER	 (over radio)</speaker>
We <verb lemma="have">have</verb> you on our screen now. Please identify.</sp>

<sp><speaker>HAN</speaker>
Shuttle Tydirium requesting deactivation of the deflector shield.</sp>

<sp><speaker>CONTROLLER	 (over radio)</speaker>
Shuttle Tydirium, transmit the clearance code for <verb lemma="shield">shield</verb> passage.</sp>

<sp><speaker>HAN</speaker>
Transmission commencing.</sp>

<sd>Leia and Chewbacca list<verb lemma="en">en</verb> tensely as the <verb lemma="sound">sound</verb> of a high <verb lemma="speed">speed</verb> 
transmission begins.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LEIA</speaker>
Now we <verb lemma="find">find</verb> out if that code <verb lemma="be">is</verb> worth the price we paid.</sp>

<sp><speaker>HAN</speaker>
It'll work. It'll work.</sp>

<sd>Chewie whines nervously. Luke stares at the Huge Super Star Destroyer 
that looms ever larger before them.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
Vader's on that ship.</sp>

<sp><speaker>HAN</speaker>
Now don't <verb lemma="get">get</verb> jittery, Luke. There <verb lemma="be">are</verb> a lot of command ships. <verb lemma="keep">Keep</verb> 
your <verb lemma="distance">distance</verb> though, Chewie, but don't <verb lemma="look">look</verb> <verb lemma="like">like</verb> you're trying to <verb lemma="keep">keep</verb> 
your distance.</sp>

<sd>Chewie <verb lemma="bark">barks</verb> a question.</sd>

<sp><speaker>HAN</speaker>
I don't know.  <verb lemma="fly">Fly</verb> casual.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
I'm endangering the mission. I shouldn't <verb lemma="have">have</verb> come.</sp>

<sp><speaker>HAN</speaker>
It's your imagination, kid. <verb lemma="come">Come</verb> on. Let's <verb lemma="keep">keep</verb> a little optimism here.</sp>

<sd>Chewie <verb lemma="bark">barks</verb> his worries as the Super Star Destroyer grows larger out 
the window.</sd>

<setting>60   INT VADER'S STAR DESTROYER - BRIDGE</setting>

<sd>Lord Vader stands, <verb lemma="back">back</verb> to us, staring out a window at the Death Star. 
Now, some vibration <verb lemma="feel">felt</verb> only by him causes him to turn. After a moment 
of stillness, he walks down the row of controllers to where ADMIRAL 
PIETT <verb lemma="be">is</verb> <verb lemma="lean">leaning</verb> over the tracking screen of the controller we've seen 
earlier. Piett straightens at Vader's approach.</sd>

<sp><speaker>VADER</speaker>
Where <verb lemma="be">is</verb> that shuttle going?</sp>

<sp><speaker>PIETT	 (into comlink)</speaker>
Shuttle Tydirium, what <verb lemma="be">is</verb> your cargo and destination?</sp>

<sp><speaker>PILOT VOICE    (HAN)   (filtered)</speaker>
Parts and technical crew for the forest moon.</sp>

<sd>The Bridge Commander looks to Vader for a reaction.</sd>

<sp><speaker>VADER</speaker>
<verb lemma="do">Do</verb> they <verb lemma="have">have</verb> a code clearance?</sp>

<sp><speaker>PIETT</speaker>
It's an older code, sir, but it checks out. I <verb lemma="be">was</verb> about to <verb lemma="clear">clear</verb> them.</sp>

<sd>Vader looks upward, as he senses Luke's presence.</sd>

<sp><speaker>PIETT</speaker>
Shall I <verb lemma="hold">hold</verb> them?</sp>

<sp><speaker>VADER</speaker>
No. <verb lemma="leave">Leave</verb> them to me. I will <verb lemma="deal">deal</verb> with them myself.</sp>

<sp><speaker>PIETT	 (surprised)</speaker>
As you wish, my lord.
(to controller)
<verb lemma="carry">Carry</verb> on.</sp>

<sd>Piett nods at controller, who switches on his comlink.</sd>

<setting>61   INT STOLEN IMPERIAL SHUTTLE - COCKPIT</setting>

<sd>The group waits tensely.</sd>

<sp><speaker>HAN</speaker>
They're not goin' for it, Chewie.</sp>

<sp><speaker>CONTROLLER	 (filtered)</speaker>
Shuttle Tydirium, deactivation of the <verb lemma="shield">shield</verb> will <verb lemma="commence">commence</verb> immediately. 
<verb lemma="follow">Follow</verb> your
present course.</sp>

<sd>Everyone <verb lemma="breath">breaths</verb> a sigh of relief. Everyone but Luke, who looks 
worried. Chewie barks.</sd>

<sp><speaker>HAN</speaker>
Okay! I <verb lemma="tell">told</verb> you it <verb lemma="be">was</verb> gonna work. No problem.</sp>

<setting>62   EXT SPACE - STOLEN IMPERIAL SHUTTLE - ENDOR</setting>

<sd>The stolen Imperial shuttle moves off toward the green Sanctuary Moon.</sd>

<setting>63   EXT FOREST LANDING SITE - ENDOR</setting>

<sd>The stolen Imperial shuttle sits in a clearing of the moon's dark, 
primeval forest, <verb lemma="dwarf">dwarfed</verb> by the ancient towe<verb lemma="ring">ring</verb> trees.</sd>

<sd>On an adjacent hill, the <verb lemma="helmete">helmeted</verb> Rebel contingent makes its way up a 
steep trail. Leia and Han <verb lemma="be">are</verb> slightly ahead of Chewie and Luke. The 
troops of the strike-team squad follow, with Artoo and Threepio 
bringing up the rear. Artoo beeps.</sd>

<sd>Up ahead, Chewie and Leia <verb lemma="reach">reach</verb> a crest in the hill and <verb lemma="drop">drop</verb> suddenly 
to the ground, signaling the <verb lemma="rest">rest</verb> of the group to stop. Han and Luke 
<verb lemma="crawl">crawl</verb> up to <verb lemma="take">take</verb> a look.</sd>

<sp><speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
Oh, I <verb lemma="tell">told</verb> you it <verb lemma="be">was</verb> dangerous here.</sp>

<sp><speaker>THEIR POV. Not far below them, two IMPERIAL SCOUTS <verb lemma="be">are</verb> wandering </speaker>
through bushes in the valley below. Their two ROCKET BIKES <verb lemma="be">are</verb> <verb lemma="park">parked</verb> 
nearby.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LEIA</speaker>
Shall we <verb lemma="try">try</verb> and <verb lemma="go">go</verb> around?</sp>

<sp><speaker>HAN</speaker>
It'll <verb lemma="take">take</verb> time. This whole party'll <verb lemma="be">be</verb> for nothing if they <verb lemma="see">see</verb> us.</sp>

<sd>Leia <verb lemma="motion">motions</verb> for the squad to <verb lemma="stay">stay</verb> put, then she, Han, Luke and Chewie 
<verb lemma="start">start</verb> quietly down.</sd>

<setting>64   EXT FOREST CLEARING - CAMPSITE</setting>

<sd>The four friends <verb lemma="make">make</verb> their way to the edge of the clearing not far 
from the two Imperial scouts.</sd>

<sp><speaker>HAN</speaker>
Chewie and I will <verb lemma="take">take</verb> care of this. You <verb lemma="stay">stay</verb> here.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
Quietly, there might <verb lemma="be">be</verb> more of them out there.</sp>

<sp><speaker>HAN	 (grins)</speaker>
Hey... it's me.</sp>

<sd>Han and Chewie <verb lemma="turn">turn</verb> and <verb lemma="start">start</verb> through the bushes toward the scouts. 
Luke and Leia exchange smiles.</sd>

<sd>Han sneaks up behind one of the scouts, steps on a twig and the scout 
whirls, knocking Han into a tree. The scout shouts for his companion.</sd>

<sp><speaker>SCOUT #1</speaker>
<verb lemma="go">Go</verb> for help! Go!</sp>

<sd>The second scout jumps on his speeder bike and takes off, but Chewie 
gets off a <verb lemma="shoot">shot</verb> on his crossbow laser weapon, <verb lemma="cause">causing</verb> the scout to 
<verb lemma="crash">crash</verb> into a tree. Han and Scout #1 <verb lemma="be">are</verb> in a rousing fistfight.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LUKE	 (sarcastic)</speaker>
Great. <verb lemma="come">Come</verb> on.</sp>

<sd>Luke starts for the scuffle, followed by Leia with her laser pistol 
drawn. As they <verb lemma="run">run</verb> through the bushes, Leia stops and points to where 
two more scouts <verb lemma="be">are</verb> sitting on their speeder bikes, with an unoccupied 
bike <verb lemma="park">parked</verb> nearby.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LEIA</speaker>
Over there! Two more of them!</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
I <verb lemma="see">see</verb> them. <verb lemma="wait">Wait</verb>, Leia!</sp>

<sd>But Leia doesn't <verb lemma="hear">hear</verb> him and races for the remaining speeder bike. She 
starts it up and takes off as Luke jumps on the bike behind her.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LUKE	 (pointing to the controls)</speaker>
Quick! <verb lemma="jam">Jam</verb> their comlink. Center switch!</sp>

<sd>Luke and Leia <verb lemma="speed">speed</verb> into the dense foliage in hot pursuit, barely 
avoiding two huge trees.</sd>

<sp><speaker>HAN</speaker>
Hey, wait! Ahhh!</sp>

<sd>He flips the remaining scout to the ground.</sd>

<setting>65   EXT FOREST - THE BIKE CHASE</setting>

<sd>The two fleeing Imperial scouts <verb lemma="have">have</verb> a good <verb lemma="lead">lead</verb> as Luke and Leia 
<verb lemma="pursue">pursue</verb> through the giant trees at 200 miles an hour, the <verb lemma="fire">fire</verb> from 
their bike's laser cannon hitting harmlessly near the <verb lemma="move">moving</verb> targets.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
<verb lemma="move">Move</verb> closer!</sp>

<sd>Leia guns it, <verb lemma="close">closing</verb> the gap, as the two scouts recklessly <verb lemma="veer">veer</verb> 
through a narrow gap in the trees. One of the bikes SCRAPES a tree, 
slowing the scout.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
<verb lemma="get">Get</verb> alongside that one!</sp>

<sd>Leia pulls her speeder bike up so <verb lemma="close">close</verb> to the scout's bike that their 
steering <verb lemma="vane">vanes</verb> SCRAPE noisily. Luke leaps from his bike to the <verb lemma="back">back</verb> of 
the scout's, grabs the Imperial warrior around the neck, and flips him 
off the bike, into a thick tree trunk. Luke gains <verb lemma="control">control</verb> of the bike 
and follows Leia, who <verb lemma="have">has</verb> pulled ahead. They <verb lemma="tear">tear</verb> off after the 
remaining scout.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
<verb lemma="get">Get</verb> him!</sp>

<sd>The speeding <verb lemma="chase">chase</verb> passes TWO MORE IMPERIAL SCOUTS. These two <verb lemma="swing">swing</verb> 
into pursuit, <verb lemma="chase">chasing</verb> Luke and Leia, <verb lemma="fire">firing</verb> away with their laser 
cannon. The two Rebels <verb lemma="look">look</verb> behind them just as Luke's bike takes a 
<verb lemma="glance">glancing</verb> hit.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LUKE	 (indicating the one ahead)</speaker>
<verb lemma="keep">Keep</verb> on that one! I'll <verb lemma="take">take</verb> these two!</sp>

<sd>With Leia shooting ahead, Luke suddenly slams his steering <verb lemma="vane">vanes</verb> into 
the braking mode. Luke's bike <verb lemma="be">is</verb> a blur to the two <verb lemma="pursue">pursuing</verb> scouts as 
they <verb lemma="zip">zip</verb> by him on either side. Luke slams his bike into forward and 
starts <verb lemma="fire">firing</verb> away, <verb lemma="have">having</verb> switched <verb lemma="place">places</verb> with his pursuers in a 
manner of seconds. Luke's aim <verb lemma="be">is</verb> good and one scout's bike <verb lemma="be">is</verb> blasted 
out of control. It explodes against a tree trunk.</sd>

<sd>The scout's cohort takes one glance <verb lemma="back">back</verb> at the <verb lemma="flash">flash</verb> and shifts into 
turbo drive, going even faster. Luke keeps on his tail.</sd>

<sp><speaker>FAR AHEAD, Leia and the first scout <verb lemma="be">are</verb> doing a highspeed slalom </speaker>
through the death-dealing trunks. Now Leia aims her bike skyward and 
rises out of sight.</sp>

<sd>The scout turns in confusion, unable to <verb lemma="see">see</verb> his pursuer. Suddenly, Leia 
dives down upon him from above, cannon blasting. The scout's bike takes 
a <verb lemma="glance">glancing</verb> hit.</sd>

<sd>Leia moves in alongside him. The scout eyes her beside him, reaches 
down, and pulls out a handgun. Before Leia can react, the scout <verb lemma="have">has</verb> 
blasted her bike, sending it out of control. Leia dives off as her bike 
explodes against a tree. The happy scout looks <verb lemma="back">back</verb> at the explosion. 
But when he turns forward again, he <verb lemma="be">is</verb> on a collision <verb lemma="course">course</verb> with a 
giant fallen tree. He hits his brakes to no avail and disappears in a 
conflagration.</sd>

<sp><speaker>ANOTHER PART OF THE FOREST: Luke and the <verb lemma="last">last</verb> remaining scout <verb lemma="continue">continue</verb> </speaker>
their <verb lemma="weave">weaving</verb> <verb lemma="chase">chase</verb> through the trees. Now Luke moves up close. The 
scout responds by slamming his bike into Luke's. A fallen tree forms a 
bridge across their path. The scout zips under. Luke goes over the top 
and crashes his bike down on the scout's. Both riders <verb lemma="look">look</verb> ahead - a 
wide trunk looms directly in Luke's path, but the scout's bike beside 
him makes it almost impossible for him to <verb lemma="avoid">avoid</verb> it. Luke banks with all 
his might, <verb lemma="lean">leaning</verb> almost horizontal over the scout's bike, and <verb lemma="be">is</verb> able 
to <verb lemma="make">make</verb> it by, just clipping the tree. When he straightens, he and the 
scout dis<verb lemma="cover">cover</verb> that their two bikes <verb lemma="have">have</verb> locked <verb lemma="front">front</verb> <verb lemma="vane">vanes</verb> and <verb lemma="be">are</verb> 
<verb lemma="move">moving</verb> as one.</sp>

<sd>Another big tree looms in Luke's path. He reacts instinctively and 
dives off his bike. The two bikes <verb lemma="come">come</verb> apart a second before Luke's 
explodes against a tree. The scout sweeps out and circles <verb lemma="back">back</verb> to <verb lemma="find">find</verb> 
Luke.</sd>

<sd>Luke rises from the undergrowth as the scout bears down on him and 
opens <verb lemma="fire">fire</verb> with his laser cannon. Luke ignites his laser sword and 
begins deflecting the bolts. The scout's bike keeps coming and it 
appears that in a second it will <verb lemma="cut">cut</verb> Luke in half. At the <verb lemma="last">last</verb> instant, 
Luke steps aside and chops off the bike's <verb lemma="control">control</verb> <verb lemma="vane">vanes</verb> with one mighty 
slash. The scout's bike begins to shudder, then, <verb lemma="pitch">pitching</verb> and rolling, 
it rises up to <verb lemma="slam">slam</verb> directly into a tree in a giant ball of fire.</sd>

<setting>66   EXT SCOUT CAMPSITE - FOREST</setting>

<sd>Han, Chewie, and the droids, along with the <verb lemma="rest">rest</verb> of the squad, wait 
anxiously in the clearing. Artoo's radar screen sticks out of his domed 
<verb lemma="head">head</verb> and revolves, scanning the forest. He beeps.</sd>

<sp><speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
Oh, General Solo, somebody's coming. Oh!</sp>

<sd>Han, Chewie, and the <verb lemma="rest">rest</verb> of the squad raise their weapons.</sd>

<sd>Luke steps out of the foliage to <verb lemma="find">find</verb> the weapons trained on him. He's 
too tired to care. He <verb lemma="plop">plops</verb> himself down on a boulder and looks around.</sd>

<sp><speaker>HAN</speaker>
Luke! Where's Leia?</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE	 (concerned)</speaker>
What? She didn't <verb lemma="come">come</verb> back?</sp>

<sp><speaker>HAN</speaker>
I <verb lemma="think">thought</verb> she <verb lemma="be">was</verb> with you.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
We got separated.</sp>

<sd>Luke and Han exchange a silent, grim look. Luke gets up wearily.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
Hey, we better <verb lemma="go">go</verb> <verb lemma="look">look</verb> for her.</sp>

<sd>Han nods, and signals to a Rebel officer.</sd>

<sp><speaker>HAN</speaker>
<verb lemma="take">Take</verb> the squad ahead.  We'll <verb lemma="meet">meet</verb> at the <verb lemma="shield">shield</verb> generator at 0300.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
<verb lemma="come">Come</verb> on, Artoo.  We'll <verb lemma="need">need</verb> your scanners.</sp>

<sd>Luke, Chewie, Han, and the droids <verb lemma="move">move</verb> off in one direction as the 
squad proceeds in another.</sd>

<sp><speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
Don't worry, Master Luke.  We <verb lemma="know">know</verb> what to do.</sp>

<sd>They <verb lemma="move">move</verb> off into the woods.</sd>

<sp><speaker>THREEPIO	 (to Artoo)</speaker>
And you said it <verb lemma="be">was</verb> pretty here. Ugh!</sp>

<setting>67   EXT FOREST CLEARING - LEIA'S CRASH SITE</setting>

<sd>A strange little furry <verb lemma="face">face</verb> with huge black eyes comes slowly into 
view. The creature <verb lemma="be">is</verb> an EWOK, by the name of WICKET. He seems somewhat 
puzzled, and <verb lemma="prod">prods</verb> Leia with a spear. The princess groans; this 
frightens the stubby ball of fuzz and he <verb lemma="prod">prods</verb> her again. Leia sits up 
and stares at the three-foot-high Ewok. She <verb lemma="try">tries</verb> to <verb lemma="figure">figure</verb> out where 
she <verb lemma="be">is</verb> and what <verb lemma="have">has</verb> happened. Her clothes <verb lemma="be">are</verb> torn; she's <verb lemma="bruise">bruised</verb> and 
disheveled.</sd>

<sd>The Ewok jumps up and grabs a four-foot-long spear, which he holds in a 
defensive position. Leia watches him as he circles warily and begins 
<verb lemma="poke">poking</verb> her with the sharp <verb lemma="point">point</verb> of the spear.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LEIA</speaker>
<verb lemma="cut">Cut</verb> it out!</sp>

<sd>She stands up, and the Ewok quickly backs away.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LEIA</speaker>
I'm not gonna <verb lemma="hurt">hurt</verb> you.</sp>

<sd>Leia looks around at the dense forest, and at the charred remains of 
her speeder bike, then sits down, with a sigh, on a fallen log.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LEIA</speaker>
Well, looks <verb lemma="like">like</verb> I'm <verb lemma="stick">stuck</verb> here. Trouble is, I don't <verb lemma="know">know</verb> where here 
is.</sp>

<sd>She puts her <verb lemma="head">head</verb> in her hands to <verb lemma="rub">rub</verb> away some of the soreness from 
her fall. She looks over at the watchful little Ewok and pats the log 
beside her.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LEIA</speaker>
Well, maybe you can <verb lemma="help">help</verb> me. <verb lemma="come">Come</verb> on, <verb lemma="sit">sit</verb> down.</sp>

<sd>Wicket holds his <verb lemma="spear">spear</verb> up warily and growls at her <verb lemma="like">like</verb> a puppy. Leia 
pats the log again.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LEIA</speaker>
I promise I won't <verb lemma="hurt">hurt</verb> you. Now <verb lemma="come">come</verb> here.</sp>

<sd>More growls and <verb lemma="squeak">squeaks</verb> from the little bear creature.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LEIA</speaker>
All right. You <verb lemma="want">want</verb> something to eat?</sp>

<sd>She takes a scrap of food out of her pocket and offers it to him. 
Wicket takes a <verb lemma="step">step</verb> backward, then cocks his <verb lemma="head">head</verb> and moves cautiously 
toward Leia, <verb lemma="chatter">chattering</verb> in his squeaky Ewok language.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LEIA</speaker>
That's right. <verb lemma="come">Come</verb> on. Hmmm?</sp>

<sd>Sniffing the food curiously, the Ewok comes toward Leia and sits on the 
log beside her. She takes off her helmet, and the little creature jumps 
back, startled again. He runs along the log, pointing his <verb lemma="spear">spear</verb> at her 
and <verb lemma="chatter">chattering</verb> a blue streak. Leia holds out the helmet to him.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LEIA</speaker>
Look, it's a hat. It's not gonna <verb lemma="hurt">hurt</verb> you. Look. You're a jittery 
little thing, aren't you?</sp>

<sd><verb lemma="reassure">Reassured</verb>, Wicket lowers his <verb lemma="spear">spear</verb> and climbs <verb lemma="back">back</verb> on the log, coming 
to investigate the helmet. Suddenly his ears <verb lemma="perk">perk</verb> up and he begins to 
<verb lemma="sniff">sniff</verb> the air. He looks around warily, whispe<verb lemma="ring">ring</verb> some Ewokese warning 
to Leia.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LEIA</speaker>
What <verb lemma="be">is</verb> it?</sp>

<sd>Suddenly a laser bolt comes out of the foliage and explodes on the log 
next to Leia. Leia and Wicket both <verb lemma="roll">roll</verb> backwards off the log, <verb lemma="hide">hiding</verb> 
behind it. Leia holds her own laser <verb lemma="gun">gun</verb> ready, while Wicket disappears 
underneath the log. Another shot, and still no sight of anyone in the 
forest. Then Leia senses something and turns to <verb lemma="find">find</verb> a large IMPERIAL 
SCOUT standing over her with his weapon pointed at her head. He reaches 
out his <verb lemma="hand">hand</verb> for her weapon.</sd>

<sp><speaker>SCOUT #l</speaker>
Freeze!  <verb lemma="come">Come</verb> on, <verb lemma="get">get</verb> up!</sp>

<sd>She hands the weapon over, as a second scout emerges from the foliage 
in <verb lemma="front">front</verb> of the log.</sd>

<sp><speaker>SCOUT #1</speaker>
<verb lemma="go">Go</verb> <verb lemma="get">get</verb> your <verb lemma="ride">ride</verb> and <verb lemma="take">take</verb> her <verb lemma="back">back</verb> to base.</sp>

<sp><speaker>SCOUT #2</speaker>
Yes, sir.</sp>

<sd>The second scout starts toward his bike, as Wicket, <verb lemma="crouch">crouched</verb> under the 
log, extends his <verb lemma="spear">spear</verb> and hits the first scout on the leg. The scout 
jumps and lets out an exclamation, and looks down at Wicket, puzzled. 
Leia grabs a branch and knocks him out. She dives for his laser pistol, 
and the second scout, now on his bike, takes off. Leia fires away and 
hits the <verb lemma="escape">escaping</verb> bike, <verb lemma="cause">causing</verb> it to <verb lemma="crash">crash</verb> into the first scout's 
bike, which <verb lemma="fly">flies</verb> end over end and explodes. The forest <verb lemma="be">is</verb> <verb lemma="quiet">quiet</verb> once 
more. Wicket pokes his fuzzy <verb lemma="head">head</verb> up from behind the log and regards 
Leia with�new respect. He mumbles his awe. Leia <verb lemma="hurry">hurries</verb> over, looking 
around all the time, and <verb lemma="motion">motions</verb> the chubby little creature into the 
dense foliage.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LEIA</speaker>
<verb lemma="come">Come</verb> on, let's <verb lemma="get">get</verb> outta here.</sp>

<sd>As they <verb lemma="move">move</verb> into the foliage, Wicket takes the lead. He shrieks and 
<verb lemma="tug">tugs</verb> at Leia to <verb lemma="follow">follow</verb> him.</sd>

<setting>68   INT DEATH STAR - CORRIDOR TO EMPEROR'S TOWER</setting>

<sd>Darth Vader walks down the corridor to the Emperor's Tower and private 
elevator. The Emperor's private <verb lemma="guard">guard</verb> steps in Vader's path.</sd>

<sp><speaker>GUARD</speaker>
Halt! The Emperor does not wish to <verb lemma="be">be</verb> disturbed at the moment.</sp>

<sp><speaker>VADER        </speaker>
(raising his gloved <verb lemma="hand">hand</verb> to the two guards and <verb lemma="choke">choking</verb> them with the 
Force)
The Emperor will <verb lemma="see">see</verb> me, now!</sp>

<sp><speaker>GUARD</speaker>
(repeating Vader's command)
The Emperor will <verb lemma="see">see</verb> you, now.</sp>

<setting>69   INT EMPEROR'S TOWER - THRONE ROOM</setting>

<sd>Two <verb lemma="red">red</verb> Imperial Guards <verb lemma="stand">stand</verb> <verb lemma="watch">watch</verb> at the elevator as the door opens 
to <verb lemma="reveal">reveal</verb> Vader. Vader enters the eerie, <verb lemma="forebode">foreboding</verb> throne room. It 
appears to <verb lemma="be">be</verb> empty. His footsteps <verb lemma="echo">echo</verb> as he approaches the throne. He 
waits, absolutely still. The Emperor sits with his <verb lemma="back">back</verb> to the Dark 
Lord.</sd>

<sp><speaker>EMPEROR</speaker>
I <verb lemma="tell">told</verb> you to remain on the command ship.</sp>

<sp><speaker>VADER</speaker>
A small Rebel <verb lemma="force">force</verb> <verb lemma="have">has</verb> penetrated the <verb lemma="shield">shield</verb> and landed on Endor.</sp>

<sp><speaker>EMPEROR	 (no surprise)</speaker>
Yes, I know.</sp>

<sp><speaker>VADER	 (after a beat)</speaker>
My son <verb lemma="be">is</verb> with them.</sp>

<sp><speaker>EMPEROR	 (very cool)</speaker>
Are you sure?</sp>

<sp><speaker>VADER</speaker>
I <verb lemma="have">have</verb> <verb lemma="feel">felt</verb> him, my Master.</sp>

<sp><speaker>EMPEROR</speaker>
Strange, that I <verb lemma="have">have</verb> not. I wonder if your feelings on this matter <verb lemma="be">are</verb> 
clear, Lord
Vader.</sp>

<sd>Vader knows what <verb lemma="be">is</verb> being asked.</sd>

<sp><speaker>VADER</speaker>
They <verb lemma="be">are</verb> clear, my Master.</sp>

<sp><speaker>EMPEROR</speaker>
Then you must <verb lemma="go">go</verb> to the Sanctuary Moon and wait for them.</sp>

<sp><speaker>VADER	 (skeptical)</speaker>
He will <verb lemma="come">come</verb> to me?</sp>

<sp><speaker>EMPEROR</speaker>
I <verb lemma="have">have</verb> foreseen it. His compassion for you will <verb lemma="be">be</verb> his undoing. He will 
<verb lemma="come">come</verb> to you and
then you will <verb lemma="bring">bring</verb> him before me.</sp>

<sp><speaker>VADER	 (bows)</speaker>
As you wish.</sp>

<sd>The Dark Lord strides out of the throne room.</sd>

<setting>70   EXT FOREST CLEARING - LEIA'S CRASH SITE</setting>

<sd>Han, Luke, Chewie, and the two droids <verb lemma="be">are</verb> spread out as they <verb lemma="move">move</verb> 
through the heavy foliage near the clearing where we <verb lemma="last">last</verb> <verb lemma="see">saw</verb> Leia. 
Luke finds Leia's helmet, picks it up with an expression of concern.</sd>

<sp><speaker>HAN	 (OS)</speaker>
Luke! Luke!</sp>

<sd>Luke runs with the helmet to where Han <verb lemma="have">has</verb> <verb lemma="find">found</verb> the charred wreckage 
of a speeder bike in the grass.</sd>

<sp><speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
Oh, Master Luke.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
There's two more wrecked speeders <verb lemma="back">back</verb> there. And I <verb lemma="find">found</verb> this.</sp>

<sd>He tosses the helmet to Han.</sd>

<sp><speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
I'm <verb lemma="afraid">afraid</verb> that Artoo's sensors can <verb lemma="find">find</verb> no trace of Princess Leia.</sp>

<sp><speaker>HAN	 (gravely)</speaker>
I <verb lemma="hope">hope</verb> she's alright.</sp>

<sd>Chewbacca growls, sniffing the air, then, with a bark, pushes off 
through the foliage.</sd>

                              HAN
What, Chewie? What? Chewie!

<sd>The others <verb lemma="rush">rush</verb> to <verb lemma="keep">keep</verb> up with the giant Wookiee. As he <verb lemma="scoot">scoots</verb> along, 
Artoo whistles nervously.</sd>

<setting>71   EXT FOREST - DENSE FOLIAGE</setting>

<sd>The group <verb lemma="have">has</verb> reached a <verb lemma="break">break</verb> in the undergrowth. Chewie walks up to a 
tall stake planted in the ground. There <verb lemma="be">is</verb> a dead animal hanging from 
it.</sd>

<sp><speaker>HAN</speaker>
Hey, I don't <verb lemma="get">get</verb> it.</sp>

<sd>The <verb lemma="rest">rest</verb> of the group joins the Wookiee around the stake.</sd>

<sp><speaker>HAN	 (cont)</speaker>
Nah, it's just a dead animal, Chewie.</sp>

<sd>Chewie can't resist. He reaches toward the meat.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
Chewie, wa-wait!  Don't!</sp>

<sd>Too late. The Wookiee <verb lemma="have">has</verb> already pulled the animal from the stake. 
SPROOING! The group finds itself hanging upside down in an Ewok net, 
suspended high above the clearing. Artoo lets out a wild series of 
beeps and whistles, and Chewie <verb lemma="howl">howls</verb> his regret. Their bodies <verb lemma="be">are</verb> a 
jumble in the net. Han removes a Wookiee paw from his mouth.</sd>

<sp><speaker>HAN</speaker>
Nice work. Great, Chewie! Great! Always thinking with your stomach.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
Will you <verb lemma="take">take</verb> it easy? Let's just <verb lemma="figure">figure</verb> out a way to <verb lemma="get">get</verb> out of this 
thing. 
(trying to <verb lemma="free">free</verb> an arm) 
Han, can you <verb lemma="reach">reach</verb> my lightsaber?</sp>

<sp><speaker>HAN</speaker>
Yeah, sure.</sp>

<sd>Artoo <verb lemma="be">is</verb> at the bottommost <verb lemma="point">point</verb> in the net. He extends his cutting 
appendage and begins <verb lemma="slice">slicing</verb> at the net. Han <verb lemma="be">is</verb> trying to <verb lemma="squeeze">squeeze</verb> an 
arm past Threepio to <verb lemma="get">get</verb> at Luke's lightsaber. The net continues to 
spin.</sd>

<sp><speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
Artoo, I'm not <verb lemma="sure">sure</verb> that's such a good idea. It's a very long dro-o-
op!!</sp>

<sd>Artoo <verb lemma="have">has</verb> <verb lemma="cut">cut</verb> through and the entire group tumbles out of the net, 
crashing to the ground. As they regain their senses and <verb lemma="sit">sit</verb> up, they 
<verb lemma="realize">realize</verb> they <verb lemma="be">are</verb> surrounded by dozens of Ewoks, each <verb lemma="brandish">brand<verb lemma="be">is</verb>hing</verb> a long 
spear.</sd>

<sp><speaker>HAN</speaker>
Wha--?  Hey!  <verb lemma="point">Point</verb> that thing someplace else.</sp>

<sd>Han pushes the <verb lemma="spear">spear</verb> <verb lemma="wield">wielded</verb> by TEEBO out of his <verb lemma="face">face</verb> and a second Ewok 
warrior comes up to <verb lemma="argue">argue</verb> with Teebo. The <verb lemma="spear">spear</verb> returns to Han's face. 
He grabs it angrily and starts to <verb lemma="go">go</verb> for his laser pistol.</sd>

<sp><speaker>HAN</speaker>
Hey!</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
Han, don't. It'll <verb lemma="be">be</verb> all right.</sp>

<sd>The Ewoks <verb lemma="swarm">swarm</verb> through them and confisc<verb lemma="eat">ate</verb> their weapons. Luke lets 
them <verb lemma="take">take</verb> his lightsaber. Chewie growls at the furry critters.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
Chewie, <verb lemma="give">give</verb> 'em your crossbow.</sp>

<sd>Artoo and Threepio <verb lemma="be">are</verb> just <verb lemma="untangle">untangling</verb> themselves. Threepio gets <verb lemma="free">free</verb> 
of the net and sits up, rattled.</sd>

<sp><speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
Oh, my head. Oh, my goodness!</sp>

<sd>When the Ewoks <verb lemma="see">see</verb> Threepio, they <verb lemma="let">let</verb> out a gasp and chatter among 
themselves. Threepio speaks to them in their native tongue. The Ewok 
nearest him drops his <verb lemma="spear">spear</verb> and prostrates himself before the droid. In 
a moment, all the Ewoks <verb lemma="have">have</verb> followed suit. Chewie lets out a puzzled 
bark. Han and Luke <verb lemma="regard">regard</verb> the bowed creatures in wonder. The Ewoks 
begin to <verb lemma="chant">chant</verb> at Threepio.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
<verb lemma="do">Do</verb> you understand anything they're saying?</sp>

<sp><speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
Oh, yes, Master Luke!  <verb lemma="remember">Remember</verb> that I am fluent in over six million 
forms of
communication.</sp>

<sp><speaker>HAN</speaker>
What <verb lemma="be">are</verb> you telling them?</sp>

<sp><speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
Hello, I think... I could <verb lemma="be">be</verb> mistaken. They're <verb lemma="use">using</verb> a very primitive 
dialect.  But
I <verb lemma="do">do</verb> believe they think I am some sort of god.</sp>

<sd>Chewbacca and Artoo think that's very funny. Han and Luke exchange 
"what next?" looks.</sd>

<sp><speaker>HAN</speaker>
Well, why don't you <verb lemma="use">use</verb> your divine influence and <verb lemma="get">get</verb> us out of this?</sp>

<sp><speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
I beg your pardon, General Solo, but that just wouldn't <verb lemma="be">be</verb> proper.</sp>

<sp><speaker>HAN</speaker>
Proper?!</sp>

<sp><speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
It's against my programming to impersonate a deity.</sp>

<sd>Han moves toward Threepio threateningly.</sd>

<sp><speaker>HAN</speaker>
Why, you--</sp>

<sd>Several Ewoks' spears <verb lemma="be">are</verb> <verb lemma="thrust">thrust</verb> in Han's <verb lemma="face">face</verb> at the affront to their 
god. The Ewoks <verb lemma="move">move</verb> in to <verb lemma="protect">protect</verb> their god and Han <verb lemma="be">is</verb> surrounded by a 
menacing <verb lemma="circle">circle</verb> of spears, all aimed at him. He holds up his hands 
placatingly.</sd>

<sp><speaker>HAN</speaker>
My mistake. He's an old friend of mine.</sp>

<setting>72   EXT FOREST - SERIES OF SHOTS</setting>

<sd>A procession of Ewoks winds through the ever-darkening forest. Their 
prisoners - Han, Luke, Chewie, and Artoo - <verb lemma="be">are</verb> tied to long poles and 
<verb lemma="wrap">wrapped</verb> in vines, cocoonlike.</sd>

<sd>Each pole <verb lemma="be">is</verb> <verb lemma="carry">carried</verb> on the shoulders of several Ewoks. Behind the 
captives, Threepio <verb lemma="be">is</verb> <verb lemma="carry">carried</verb> on a litter, <verb lemma="like">like</verb> a king, by the 
remaining creatures.</sd>

<setting>73   EXT FOREST WALKWAY - MOON FOREST</setting>

<sd>The procession moves along a shaky, narrow, wooden walkway, high in the 
giant trees. It stops at the end of the walkway, which drops off into 
nothingness. On the other <verb lemma="side">side</verb> of the abyss <verb lemma="be">is</verb> a village of mud huts 
and rickety walkways, attached to the giant trees. The <verb lemma="lead">lead</verb> Ewok takes 
<verb lemma="hold">hold</verb> of a long vine and swings across to the village square; the other 
Ewoks <verb lemma="follow">follow</verb> suit.</sd>

<setting>74   EXT EWOK VILLAGE SQUARE</setting>

<sd>The procession winds its way into the village square. Mother Ewoks 
<verb lemma="gather">gather</verb> their babies up and <verb lemma="scurry">scurry</verb> into their huts at the sight of the 
newcomers. The group stops before the largest hut.</sd>

<sd>Han, Luke, Chewie, and Artoo <verb lemma="be">are</verb> still <verb lemma="bind">bound</verb> to their poles. Han <verb lemma="be">is</verb> 
<verb lemma="place">placed</verb> on a <verb lemma="spit">spit</verb> above what looks <verb lemma="like">like</verb> a barbecue pit and the others 
<verb lemma="be">are</verb> <verb lemma="lean">leaned</verb> against a tree nearby. Threepio's litter/throne <verb lemma="be">is</verb> gently 
<verb lemma="place">placed</verb> near the pit. He watches with rapt fascination. Han, Luke, and 
Chewie <verb lemma="be">are</verb> less than fascinated.</sd>

<sp><speaker>HAN</speaker>
I <verb lemma="have">have</verb> a really bad feeling about this.</sp>

<sd>Chewie growls his concern.</sd>

<sd>Suddenly all activity stops as LOGRAY, the tribal Medicine Man, comes 
out of the big hut. He examines the captives carefully, goes to <verb lemma="join">join</verb> 
Threepio, whose throne <verb lemma="have">has</verb> been <verb lemma="place">placed</verb> on an elevated platform. A 
larger, gray-hai<verb lemma="red">red</verb> Ewok, CHIEF CHIRPA, <verb lemma="be">is</verb> <verb lemma="examine">examining</verb> Luke's lightsaber 
with great curiosity.</sd>

<sd>Logray speaks to Threepio and the assemblage of fuzzy Ewoks, pointing 
to the prisoners tied to the stakes. The Ewoks begin filling the pit 
under Han with firewood.</sd>

<sp><speaker>HAN</speaker>
What <verb lemma="do">did</verb> he say?</sp>

<sp><speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
I'm rather embarrassed, General Solo, but it appears you <verb lemma="be">are</verb> to <verb lemma="be">be</verb> the 
main <verb lemma="course">course</verb> at a
banquet in my honor.</sp>

<sd>The <verb lemma="drum">drums</verb> <verb lemma="start">start</verb> beating, and all the furry heads <verb lemma="turn">turn</verb> to the large hut. 
Leia emerges, wearing an animal-skin dress. She sees what's happening 
at the same moment the prisoners <verb lemma="see">see</verb> her.</sd>

<sp><speaker>HAN and LUKE</speaker>
Leia!</sp>

<sd>As she moves toward them, the Ewoks <verb lemma="block">block</verb> her way with raised spears.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LEIA</speaker>
Oh!</sp>

<sp><speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
Your Royal Highness.</sp>

<sd>Artoo and Chewie chime in with their welcome. Leia looks at the 
assembled Ewoks and sighs.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LEIA</speaker>
But these <verb lemma="be">are</verb> my friends. Threepio, <verb lemma="tell">tell</verb> them they must <verb lemma="be">be</verb> <verb lemma="set">set</verb> free.</sp>

<sd>Threepio talks to Chirpa and Logray, who list<verb lemma="en">en</verb> and <verb lemma="shake">shake</verb> their heads 
negatively. The Medicine Man gestures toward the prisoners and <verb lemma="bark">barks</verb> 
some orders. Several Ewoks <verb lemma="jump">jump</verb> up and <verb lemma="pile">pile</verb> more wood on the barbecue 
with vigor. Leia <verb lemma="trade">trades</verb> frantic looks with Luke and Han .</sd>

<sp><speaker>HAN</speaker>
Somehow, I got the feeling that didn't <verb lemma="help">help</verb> us very much.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
Threepio, <verb lemma="tell">tell</verb> them if they don't <verb lemma="do">do</verb> as you wish, you'll become angry 
and <verb lemma="use">use</verb> your magic.</sp>

<sp><speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
But Master Luke, what magic? I couldn't possibly --</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
Just <verb lemma="tell">tell</verb> them.</sp>

<sd>Threepio speaks to the Ewoks. The Ewoks <verb lemma="be">are</verb> disturbed. Logray steps 
forward and <verb lemma="challenge">challenges</verb> Threepio. Luke closes his eyes and begins to 
concentrate.</sd>

<sp><speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
You see, Master Luke; they didn't believe me. Just...</sp>

<sd>Now the litter/throne, with Threepio sitting upon it, rises from the 
ground. At first Threepio doesn't <verb lemma="notice">notice</verb> and keeps talking.</sd>

<sp><speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
... as I said they wouldn't. Wha-wha-what's happening! Oh! Oh, dear! 
Oh!</sp>

<sd>The Ewoks <verb lemma="fall">fall</verb> <verb lemma="back">back</verb> in terror from the floating throne. Now Threepio 
begins to <verb lemma="spin">spin</verb> as though he <verb lemma="be">were</verb> on a revolving stool, with Threepio 
calling out in total <verb lemma="panic">panic</verb> at his situation.</sd>

<sp><speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
<verb lemma="put">Put</verb> me down! He-e-elp! Master Luke! Artoo! Somebody, somebody, help! 
Master Luke, Artoo! Artoo, quickly! <verb lemma="do">Do</verb> something, somebody! Oh! Ohhh!</sp>

<sd>Chief Chirpa yells <verb lemma="order">orders</verb> to the <verb lemma="cower">cowering</verb> Ewoks. They <verb lemma="rush">rush</verb> up and 
release the <verb lemma="bind">bound</verb> prisoners. Luke and Han enfold Leia in a group 
embrace. Luke notices the spinning Threepio, with Artoo beeping up at 
him, and slowly lowers the golden <verb lemma="droid">droid</verb> and the throne to the ground. 
Logray <verb lemma="order">orders</verb> the little <verb lemma="droid">droid</verb> <verb lemma="cut">cut</verb> down. Artoo crashes to the ground. 
When the Ewoks <verb lemma="set">set</verb> him upright, the little <verb lemma="droid">droid</verb> <verb lemma="be">is</verb> fighting mad. Artoo 
beeps a blue <verb lemma="streak">streak</verb> at the nearest Ewok, and begins <verb lemma="pursue">pursuing</verb> him, 
finally getting <verb lemma="close">close</verb> enough to <verb lemma="zap">zap</verb> him with an electric charge. The 
Ewok jumps two feet in the air and runs away, screaming. A small group 
of Ewoks surround the giant Wookiee, <verb lemma="scratch">scratching</verb> their heads and 
<verb lemma="marvel">marveling</verb> at his height.</sd>

<sp><speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
Oh, oh, oh, oh! <verb lemma="thank">Thank</verb> goodness.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
Thanks, Threepio.</sp>

<sp><speaker>THREEPIO	 (still shaken)</speaker>
I...I never <verb lemma="know">knew</verb> I <verb lemma="have">had</verb> it in me.</sp>

<setting>75   INT CHIEF'S HUT - COUNCIL OF ELDERS</setting>

<sd>A glowing <verb lemma="fire">fire</verb> dances in the <verb lemma="center">center</verb> of the spartan, low-ceilinged room, 
<verb lemma="create">creating</verb> a kaleidoscope of shadows on the walls. Along one side, a 
group of ten Ewok elders flank Chief Chirpa, who sits on his throne. 
The Rebels <verb lemma="sit">sit</verb> along the walls of the hut, with Threepio between the 
two groups and Wicket and Teebo off to one side.</sd>

<sd>Threepio <verb lemma="be">is</verb> in the midst of a long, <verb lemma="animate">animated</verb> speech in the Ewok's 
squeaky native tongue. The Ewoks list<verb lemma="en">en</verb> carefully and occasionally 
murmur comments to each other. Threepio points several times at the 
Rebel group and <verb lemma="pantomime">pantomimes</verb> a <verb lemma="short">short</verb> history of the Galactic Civil War, 
<verb lemma="mimic">mimicking</verb> the explosion and rocket sounds, <verb lemma="imitate">imitating</verb> Imperial walkers. 
Throughout the long account, certain familiar names <verb lemma="be">are</verb> distinguishable 
in English: Princess Leia, Artoo, Darth Vader, Death Star, Jedi, Obi-
Wan Kenobi. Artoo begins beeping excitedly at Threepio.</sd>

<sp><speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
Yes, Artoo. I <verb lemma="be">was</verb> just coming to that.</sp>

<sd>Threepio continues with: Millennium Falcon, Cloud City, Vader, Han 
Solo, carbonite, Sarlacc, bringing the history up to the present time.</sd>

<sd>At the end of it, the Chief, Logray, and the elders confer, then <verb lemma="nod">nod</verb> in 
agreement. The Chief stands and makes a pronouncement.</sd>

<sd>The <verb lemma="drum">drums</verb> begin to sound, and all the Ewoks <verb lemma="stand">stand</verb> with a great <verb lemma="cheer">cheer</verb> 
and screeches.</sd>

<sp><speaker>HAN</speaker>
What's going on?</sp>

<sp><speaker>LEIA</speaker>
I don't know.</sp>

<sd>Luke <verb lemma="have">has</verb> been sharing the joy with <verb lemma="smile">smiling</verb> visage, but now something 
passes <verb lemma="like">like</verb> a dark cloud through his consciousness. The others <verb lemma="do">do</verb> not 
notice.</sd>

<sp><speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
Wonderful! We <verb lemma="be">are</verb> now a part of the tribe.</sp>

<sd>Several of the little teddy bears <verb lemma="run">run</verb> up and <verb lemma="hug">hug</verb> the Rebels.</sd>

<sp><speaker>HAN</speaker>
Just what I always wanted.</sp>

<sd>Chewbacca <verb lemma="be">is</verb> being enthusiastically embraced by an Ewok, while Wicket 
clings to Han's leg.</sd>

<sp><speaker>HAN	 (chuckles)</speaker>
Well, <verb lemma="short">short</verb> <verb lemma="help">help</verb> <verb lemma="be">is</verb> better than no <verb lemma="help">help</verb> at all, Chewie. 
(to Wicket) 
<verb lemma="thank">Thank</verb> you. Okay.</sp>

<sp><speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
He says the scouts <verb lemma="be">are</verb> going to <verb lemma="show">show</verb> us the quickest way to the <verb lemma="shield">shield</verb> 
generator.</sp>

<sd>Chewie barks. Luke <verb lemma="have">has</verb> <verb lemma="drift">drifted</verb> to the <verb lemma="back">back</verb> of the hut. Now he <verb lemma="wander">wanders</verb> 
outside into the moonlight. Leia notices and follows.</sd>

<sp><speaker>HAN</speaker>
Good. How far <verb lemma="be">is</verb> it? <verb lemma="ask">Ask</verb> him. We <verb lemma="need">need</verb> some fresh supplies, too. And <verb lemma="try">try</verb> 
and <verb lemma="get">get</verb> our weapons back.</sp>

<sd>Han pulls Threepio <verb lemma="back">back</verb> as he keeps trying to translate.</sd>

<sp><speaker>HAN	 (cont)</speaker>
And <verb lemma="hurry">hurry</verb> up, will ya? I haven't got all day.</sp>

<setting>76   EXT EWOK VILLAGE - NIGHT</setting>

<sd>The walkway <verb lemma="be">is</verb> <verb lemma="desert">deserted</verb> now. The windows of the little huts <verb lemma="glow">glow</verb> and 
flicker from the fires inside. The sounds of the forest <verb lemma="fill">fill</verb> the soft 
night air. Luke <verb lemma="have">has</verb> wandered away from the Chief's hut and stands 
staring up at the Death Star. Leia finds him <verb lemma="like">like</verb> that.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LEIA</speaker>
Luke, what's wrong?</sp>

<sd>Luke turns and looks at her a long moment.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
Leia... <verb lemma="do">do</verb> you remember your mother? Your real mother?</sp>

<sp><speaker>LEIA</speaker>
Just a little bit. She died when I <verb lemma="be">was</verb> very young.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
What <verb lemma="do">do</verb> you remember?</sp>

<sp><speaker>LEIA</speaker>
Just...images, really. Feelings.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
<verb lemma="tell">Tell</verb> me.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LEIA</speaker>
(a little surprised at his insistence)
She <verb lemma="be">was</verb> very beautiful. Kind, but...sad.
(looks up)
Why <verb lemma="be">are</verb> you asking me all this?</sp>

<sd>He looks away.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
I <verb lemma="have">have</verb> no memory of my mother. I never <verb lemma="know">knew</verb> her.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LEIA</speaker>
Luke, <verb lemma="tell">tell</verb> me. What's <verb lemma="trouble">troubling</verb> you?</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
Vader <verb lemma="be">is</verb> here...now, on this moon.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LEIA	 (alarmed)</speaker>
How <verb lemma="do">do</verb> you know?</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
I <verb lemma="feel">felt</verb> his presence. He's <verb lemma="come">come</verb> for me. He can <verb lemma="feel">feel</verb> when I'm near. 
That's why I <verb lemma="have">have</verb> to go.
(facing her)
As long as I stay, I'm endangering the group and our mission here.
(beat)
I <verb lemma="have">have</verb> to <verb lemma="face">face</verb> him.</sp>

<sd>Leia <verb lemma="be">is</verb> distraught, confused.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LEIA</speaker>
Why?</sp>

<sd>Luke moves <verb lemma="close">close</verb> and his manner <verb lemma="be">is</verb> gentle. And very calm.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
He's my father.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LEIA</speaker>
Your father?</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
There's more. It won't <verb lemma="be">be</verb> easy for you to <verb lemma="hear">hear</verb> it, but you must. If I 
don't <verb lemma="make">make</verb> it back, you're the only <verb lemma="hope">hope</verb> for the Alliance.</sp>

<sd>Leia <verb lemma="be">is</verb> very disturbed by this. She moves away, as if to <verb lemma="deny">deny</verb> it.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LEIA</speaker>
Luke, don't <verb lemma="talk">talk</verb> that way. You <verb lemma="have">have</verb> a power I--I don't understand and 
could never have.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
You're wrong, Leia. You <verb lemma="have">have</verb> that power too. In time you'll <verb lemma="learn">learn</verb> to 
<verb lemma="use">use</verb> it as I have. The Force <verb lemma="be">is</verb> strong in my family. My father <verb lemma="have">has</verb> 
it...I <verb lemma="have">have</verb> it...and...my sister <verb lemma="have">has</verb> it.</sp>

<sd>Leia stares into his eyes. What she sees there frightens her. But she 
doesn't <verb lemma="draw">draw</verb> away. She begins to understand.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
Yes. It's you Leia.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LEIA</speaker>
I know. Somehow...I've always known.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
Then you <verb lemma="know">know</verb> why I <verb lemma="have">have</verb> to <verb lemma="face">face</verb> him.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LEIA</speaker>
No! Luke, <verb lemma="run">run</verb> away, far away. If he can <verb lemma="feel">feel</verb> your presence, then <verb lemma="leave">leave</verb> 
this place. I wish I could <verb lemma="go">go</verb> with you.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
No, you don't. You've always been strong.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LEIA</speaker>
But, why must you <verb lemma="confront">confront</verb> him?</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
Because...there <verb lemma="be">is</verb> good in him. I've <verb lemma="feel">felt</verb> it. He won't <verb lemma="turn">turn</verb> me over to 
the Emperor. I can <verb lemma="save">save</verb> him. I can <verb lemma="turn">turn</verb> him <verb lemma="back">back</verb> to the good side. I 
<verb lemma="have">have</verb> to try.</sp>

<sd>They <verb lemma="hold">hold</verb> each other <verb lemma="close">close</verb> and <verb lemma="look">look</verb> at each other, brother and sister.</sd>

<sd>Leia holds <verb lemma="back">back</verb> her tears as Luke slowly lets her <verb lemma="go">go</verb> and moves away. He 
disappears onto the walkway that leads out of the village. Leia, bathed 
in moonlight, watches him <verb lemma="go">go</verb> as Han comes out of the Chief's hut and 
comes over to her. Leia <verb lemma="be">is</verb> crying, her body trembling. He realizes only 
now that she <verb lemma="be">is</verb> crying.</sd>

<sp><speaker>HAN</speaker>
Hey, what's goin' on?</sp>

<sd>Leia attempts to <verb lemma="stifle">stifle</verb> her sobs and wipes her eyes.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LEIA</speaker>
Nothing. I - just <verb lemma="want">want</verb> to <verb lemma="be">be</verb> alone for a little while.</sp>

<sp><speaker>HAN	 (angry)</speaker>
Nothing?  <verb lemma="come">Come</verb> on, <verb lemma="tell">tell</verb> me.  What's goin' on?</sp>

<sd>She looks up at him, <verb lemma="struggle">struggling</verb> to <verb lemma="control">control</verb> herself.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LEIA</speaker>
I...I can't <verb lemma="tell">tell</verb> you.</sp>

<sp><speaker>HAN	 (loses his temper)</speaker>
<verb lemma="do">Did</verb> you <verb lemma="tell">tell</verb> Luke? Is that who you could tell?</sp>

<sp><speaker>LEIA</speaker>
I...</sp>

<sp><speaker>HAN</speaker>
Ahhh...</sp>

<sd>He starts to <verb lemma="walk">walk</verb> away, exasperated, then stops and walks <verb lemma="back">back</verb> to her.</sd>

<sp><speaker>HAN</speaker>
I'm sorry.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LEIA</speaker>
<verb lemma="hold">Hold</verb> me.</sp>

<sd>Han gathers her tightly in his protective embrace.</sd>

<setting>77   EXT FOREST - IMPERIAL LANDING PLATFORM</setting>

<sd>An Imperial shuttle floats down from the Death Star and lands 
gracefully on the huge platform.</sd>

<sd>Now, an Imperial walker approaches the platform from the darkness of 
the forest. The whole outpost - platform, walkers, military - looks 
particularly offensive in the midst of this verdant beauty.</sd>

<setting>78   EXT IMPERIAL LANDING PLATFORM - LOWER DECK</setting>

<sd>Darth Vader walks down the ramp of the shuttle onto the platform, into 
an elevator, and appears on a ramp on a <verb lemma="lower">lower</verb> level. He walks toward 
another ramp <verb lemma="exit">exit</verb> and <verb lemma="be">is</verb> <verb lemma="meet">met</verb> by two troopers and a commander with Luke, 
in binders, at their center. The young Jedi <verb lemma="gaze">gazes</verb> at Vader with 
<verb lemma="complete">complete</verb> calm.</sd>

<sp><speaker>COMMANDER</speaker>
This <verb lemma="be">is</verb> a Rebel that surrende<verb lemma="red">red</verb> to us. Although he <verb lemma="deny">denies</verb> it, I 
believe there may <verb lemma="be">be</verb> more of them, and I <verb lemma="request">request</verb> permission to <verb lemma="conduct">conduct</verb> 
a further search of the area.</sp>

<sd>The commander extends his hand, revealing Luke's lightsaber.</sd>

<sp><speaker>COMMANDER</speaker>
He <verb lemma="be">was</verb> <verb lemma="arm">armed</verb> only with this.</sp>

<sd>Vader looks at Luke, turns away and faces the commander, <verb lemma="take">taking</verb> the 
lightsaber from the commander's hand.</sd>

<sp><speaker>VADER</speaker>
Good work, Commander. <verb lemma="leave">Leave</verb> us. <verb lemma="conduct">Conduct</verb> your search and <verb lemma="bring">bring</verb> his 
companions to me.</sp>

<sp><speaker>COMMANDER</speaker>
Yes, my Lord.</sp>

<sd>The officer and troops withdraw. Vader and Luke <verb lemma="be">are</verb> <verb lemma="leave">left</verb> standing alone 
in the oddly tranquil beauty of the place. The sounds of the forest 
<verb lemma="filter">filter</verb> in upon them.</sd>

<sp><speaker>VADER</speaker>
The Emperor <verb lemma="have">has</verb> been expecting you.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
I know, father.</sp>

<sp><speaker>VADER</speaker>
So, you <verb lemma="have">have</verb> accepted the truth.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LURE</speaker>
I've accepted the truth that you <verb lemma="be">were</verb> once Anakin Skywalker, my father.</sp>

<sp><speaker>VADER	 (turning to <verb lemma="face">face</verb> him)</speaker>
That name no longer <verb lemma="have">has</verb> any meaning for me.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
It <verb lemma="be">is</verb> the name of your true self. You've only forgotten. I <verb lemma="know">know</verb> there 
<verb lemma="be">is</verb> good in you. The Emperor hasn't driven it from you fully. That <verb lemma="be">is</verb> 
why you couldn't <verb lemma="destroy">destroy</verb> me. That's why you won't <verb lemma="bring">bring</verb> me to your 
Emperor now.</sp>

<sd>Vader looks down from Luke to the lightsaber in his own black- gloved 
hand. He seems to <verb lemma="ponder">ponder</verb> Luke's words.</sd>

<sp><speaker>VADER	 (indicating lightsaber)</speaker>
I <verb lemma="see">see</verb> you <verb lemma="have">have</verb> <verb lemma="construct">constructed</verb> a new lightsaber.</sp>

<sd>Vader ignites the lightsaber and holds it to <verb lemma="examine">examine</verb> its humming, 
brilliant blade.</sd>

<sp><speaker>VADER</speaker>
Your skills <verb lemma="be">are</verb> complete. Indeed, you <verb lemma="be">are</verb> powerful, as the Emperor <verb lemma="have">has</verb> 
foreseen.</sp>

<sd>They <verb lemma="stand">stand</verb> for a moment, the Vader <verb lemma="extinguish">extinguishes</verb> the lightsaber.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
<verb lemma="come">Come</verb> with me.</sp>

<sp><speaker>VADER</speaker>
Obi-Wan once <verb lemma="think">thought</verb> as you do.</sp>

<sd>Luke steps <verb lemma="close">close</verb> to Vader, then stops. Vader <verb lemma="be">is</verb> still.</sd>

<sp><speaker>VADER</speaker>
You don't <verb lemma="know">know</verb> the power of the dark side. I must obey my master.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
I will not turn...and you'll <verb lemma="be">be</verb> forced to <verb lemma="kill">kill</verb> me.</sp>

<sp><speaker>VADER</speaker>
If that <verb lemma="be">is</verb> your destiny.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
<verb lemma="search">Search</verb> your feelings, father. You can't <verb lemma="do">do</verb> this. I <verb lemma="feel">feel</verb> the conflict 
within you. <verb lemma="let">Let</verb> <verb lemma="go">go</verb>
of your hate.</sp>

<sp><speaker>VADER</speaker>
It <verb lemma="be">is</verb> too late for me, son. The Emperor will <verb lemma="show">show</verb> you the true nature 
of the Force. He <verb lemma="be">is</verb>
your master now.</sp>

<sd>Vader signals to some distant stormtroopers. He and Luke <verb lemma="stand">stand</verb> staring 
at one another for a long moment.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
Then my father <verb lemma="be">is</verb> truly dead.</sp>

<setting>79   EXT ENDOR - RIDGE OVERLOOKING SHIELD GENERATOR</setting>

<sd>Han, Leia, Chewbacca, the droids, Wicket, and another Ewok scout, 
PAPLOO, <verb lemma="hide">hide</verb> on a ridge overlooking the massive Imperial <verb lemma="shield">shield</verb> 
generator. At the base of the generator <verb lemma="be">is</verb> an Imperial landing 
platform. Leia studies the installation.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LEIA</speaker>
The main entrance to the <verb lemma="control">control</verb> bunker's on the far <verb lemma="side">side</verb> of that 
landing platform. This
isn't gonna <verb lemma="be">be</verb> easy.</sp>

<sp><speaker>HAN</speaker>
Hey, don't worry. Chewie and me got into a lot of <verb lemma="place">places</verb> more heavily 
guarded than this.</sp>

<sd>Wicket and Paploo <verb lemma="be">are</verb> <verb lemma="chatter">chattering</verb> away in Ewok language. They <verb lemma="speak">speak</verb> to 
Threepio.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LEIA</speaker>
What's he saying?</sp>

<sp><speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
He says there's a secret entrance on the other <verb lemma="side">side</verb> of the ridge.</sp>

<setting>80   EXT SPACE - REBEL FLEET</setting>

<sd>The vast fleet hangs in space near a blue planet. A giant Rebel Star 
Cruiser <verb lemma="be">is</verb> up at the front, but now the Millennium Flacon roars up to a 
<verb lemma="spot">spot</verb> ahead of it, tiny in comparison.</sd>

<setting>81   INT MILLENNIUM FALCON - COCKPIT</setting>

<sd>Lando <verb lemma="be">is</verb> in the <verb lemma="pilot">pilot</verb> seat. His alien copilot, NIEN NUNB, takes some 
getting used to in the familiar environs of the Falcon's cockpit. Lando 
speaks into his comlink.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LANDO</speaker>
Admiral, we're in position. All fighters <verb lemma="account">accounted</verb> for.</sp>

<sp><speaker>ACKBAR 	(VO)</speaker>
<verb lemma="proceed">Proceed</verb> with the countdown. All groups <verb lemma="assume">assume</verb> <verb lemma="attack">attack</verb> coordinates.</sp>

<sd>Lando turns to his weird copilot.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LANDO</speaker>
Don't worry, my friends <verb lemma="be">are</verb> down there. They'll <verb lemma="have">have</verb> that <verb lemma="shield">shield</verb> down 
on time...
(to himself) 
or this'll <verb lemma="be">be</verb> the shortest offensive of all time.</sp>

<sd>The copilot flips some switches and <verb lemma="grunt">grunts</verb> an alien comment.</sd>

<sp><speaker>ACKBAR	 (VO)</speaker>
All craft, prepare to <verb lemma="jump">jump</verb> to hyperspace on my mark.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LANDO</speaker>
All right. <verb lemma="stand">Stand</verb> by.</sp>

<sd>He pulls a lever, and the stars outside begin to streak.</sd>

<setting>82   EXT SPACE - REBEL FLEET</setting>

<sd>We <verb lemma="be">are</verb> treated to an awesome sight: first the Millennium Falcon, then 
Ackbar's Star Cruiser, then, in large segments, the huge fleet ROARS 
INTO HYPERSPACE. And disappears.</sd>

<setting>83   EXT ENDOR - RIDGE OVERLOOKING CONTROL BUNKER</setting>

<sd>Han, Leia, Chewie, the droids, and their two Ewok guides, Wicket and 
Paploo, <verb lemma="have">have</verb> <verb lemma="reunite">reunited</verb> with the Rebel <verb lemma="strike">strike</verb> squad. The entire group <verb lemma="be">is</verb> 
spread through the thick undergrowth. Below them <verb lemma="be">is</verb> the BUNKER that 
leads into the generator. Four Imperial scouts, their speeder bikes 
<verb lemma="park">parked</verb> nearby, <verb lemma="keep">keep</verb> <verb lemma="watch">watch</verb> over the bunker entrance. Chewie growls an 
observation, and Paploo <verb lemma="chatter">chatters</verb> away to Han in Ewok language.</sd>

<sp><speaker>HAN</speaker>
Back door, huh? Good idea.</sp>

<sd>Wicket and Paploo <verb lemma="continue">continue</verb> their Ewok conversation.</sd>

<sp><speaker>HAN	 (cont)</speaker>
It's only a few guards. This shouldn't <verb lemma="be">be</verb> too much trouble.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LEIA</speaker>
Well, it only takes one to <verb lemma="sound">sound</verb> the alarm.</sp>

<sp><speaker>HAN	 (with self-confident grin)</speaker>
Then we'll <verb lemma="do">do</verb> it real quiet-like.</sp>

<sd>Threepio explains what <verb lemma="be">is</verb> going on to Wicket and Paploo. The Ewoks 
chatter a moment between themselves. Then Paploo jumps up and scampers 
into the underbrush.</sd>

<sd>Threepio asks Wicket where Paploo went and <verb lemma="be">is</verb> given a <verb lemma="short">short</verb> reply.</sd>

<sp><speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
Oh! Oh, my. Uh, Princess Leia!</sp>

<sp><speaker>LEIA</speaker>
Quiet.</sp>

<sp><speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
I'm <verb lemma="afraid">afraid</verb> our furry companion <verb lemma="have">has</verb> gone and done something rather rash.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LEIA</speaker>
Oh, no.</sp>

<setting>84   EXT BUNKER - ENTRANCE</setting>

<sd>Paploo <verb lemma="have">has</verb> slipped out of the undergrowth near where the Imperial 
scouts <verb lemma="be">are</verb> lounging. He silently swings his furry ball of a body onto 
one of the scout's speeder bikes and begins flipping switches at 
random. Suddenly, the bike's engine fires up with a tremendous ROAR. 
Paploo grins and continues flipping switches. The scouts <verb lemma="leap">leap</verb> up in 
surprise.</sd>

<setting>85   EXT RIDGE</setting>

<sd>Han, Leia and company <verb lemma="watch">watch</verb> in distress. Chewie barks.</sd>

<sp><speaker>HAN 	(sighs)</speaker>
There goes our surprise attack.</sp>

<setting>86   EXT BUNKER</setting>

<sd>The Imperial scouts <verb lemma="race">race</verb> toward Paploo just as his speeder zooms into 
motion. Paploo hangs on by his paws and shoots away into the forest.</sd>

<sp><speaker>SCOUT</speaker>
Look! Over there! <verb lemma="stop">Stop</verb> him!</sp>

<sd>Three of the Imperial scouts <verb lemma="jump">jump</verb> on their rocket bikes and <verb lemma="speed">speed</verb> away 
in pursuit. The fourth watches them <verb lemma="go">go</verb> from his post at the door.</sd>

<setting>87   EXT RIDGE</setting>

<sd>Han, Leia, and Chewie exchange <verb lemma="delight">delighted</verb> looks.</sd>

<sp><speaker>HAN</speaker>
Not bad for a little furball. There's only one left. You <verb lemma="stay">stay</verb> here. 
We'll <verb lemma="take">take</verb> care of this.</sp>

<sd>Han and the Wookiee <verb lemma="nod">nod</verb> at each other and <verb lemma="slip">slip</verb> down toward the bunker. 
Threepio moves to <verb lemma="stand">stand</verb> next to Wicket and Artoo.</sd>

<sp><speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
I <verb lemma="have">have</verb> decided that we shall <verb lemma="stay">stay</verb> here.</sp>

<setting>88   EXT FOREST</setting>

<sd>Paploo sails through the trees, more lucky than in control. It's scary, 
but he loves it. When the Imperial scouts <verb lemma="pull">pull</verb> within sight behind him 
and begin <verb lemma="fire">firing</verb> laser bolts, he decides he's <verb lemma="have">had</verb> enough. As he rounds 
a tree, out of their sight, Paploo grabs a vine and swings up into the 
trees. A moment later, the scouts <verb lemma="tear">tear</verb> under him in pursuit of the 
still-flying, unoccupied bike.</sd>

<setting>89   EXT BUNKER</setting>

<sd>Han sneaks up behind the remaining Imperial scout, <verb lemma="tap">taps</verb> him on the 
shoulder and lets the scout <verb lemma="chase">chase</verb> him behind the bunker into the arms 
of the waiting Rebel <verb lemma="strike">strike</verb> team. Han returns to the front, and <verb lemma="tap">taps</verb> 
out a pattern on the bunker door's <verb lemma="control">control</verb> panel. Everyone stands out 
of sight, police-style, as the door opens. Han and Leia <verb lemma="peek">peek</verb> inside. No 
<verb lemma="sign">sign</verb> of life. The group enters the bunker silently, <verb lemma="leave">leaving</verb> one lookout 
behind.</sd>

<setting>90   INT DEATH STAR - EMPEROR'S THRONE ROOM</setting>

<sd>The elevator opens. Vader and Luke enter the room alone. They <verb lemma="walk">walk</verb> 
across the dark space to <verb lemma="stand">stand</verb> before the throne, father and son <verb lemma="side">side</verb> 
by <verb lemma="side">side</verb> beneath the gaze of the Emperor. Vader bows to his Master.</sd>

<sp><speaker>EMPEROR</speaker>
Welcome, young Skywalker. I <verb lemma="have">have</verb> been expecting you.</sp>

<sd>Luke peers at the hooded <verb lemma="figure">figure</verb> defiantly. The Emperor then looks down 
at Luke's binders.</sd>

<sp><speaker>EMPEROR</speaker>
You no longer <verb lemma="need">need</verb> those.</sp>

<sd>The Emperor <verb lemma="motion">motions</verb> ever so slightly with his finger and Luke's binders 
<verb lemma="fall">fall</verb> away, <verb lemma="clatter">clattering</verb> to the floor. Luke looks down at his own hands, 
<verb lemma="free">free</verb> now to <verb lemma="reach">reach</verb> out and <verb lemma="grab">grab</verb> the Emperor's neck. He does nothing.</sd>

<sp><speaker>EMPEROR</speaker>
Guards, <verb lemma="leave">leave</verb> us.</sp>

<sd>The red-cloaked guards <verb lemma="turn">turn</verb> and dis<verb lemma="appear">appear</verb> behind the elevator.</sd>

<sp><speaker>EMPEROR	 (to Luke)</speaker>
I'm looking forward to <verb lemma="complete">completing</verb> your training. In time you will <verb lemma="call">call</verb> 
me Master.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
You're gravely mistaken. You won't <verb lemma="convert">convert</verb> me as you <verb lemma="do">did</verb> my father.</sp>

<sd>The Emperor gets down from his throne and walks up very <verb lemma="close">close</verb> to Luke. 
The Emperor looks into his eyes and, for the first time, Luke can 
<verb lemma="perceive">perceive</verb> the evil visage within the hood.</sd>

<sp><speaker>EMPEROR</speaker>
Oh, no, my young Jedi. You will <verb lemma="find">find</verb> that it <verb lemma="be">is</verb> you who <verb lemma="be">are</verb> 
mistaken...about a great many things.</sp>

<sp><speaker>VADER</speaker>
His lightsaber.</sp>

<sd>Vader extends a gloved <verb lemma="hand">hand</verb> toward the Emperor, revealing Luke's 
lightsaber. The Emperor takes it.</sd>

<sp><speaker>EMPEROR</speaker>
Ah, yes, a Jedi's weapon. Much <verb lemma="like">like</verb> your father's. By now you must <verb lemma="know">know</verb> 
your father can never <verb lemma="be">be</verb> turned from the dark side. So will it <verb lemma="be">be</verb> with 
you.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
You're wrong. Soon I'll <verb lemma="be">be</verb> dead...and you with me.</sp>

<sd>The Emperor laughs.</sd>

<sp><speaker>EMPEROR</speaker>
Perhaps you <verb lemma="refer">refer</verb> to the imminent <verb lemma="attack">attack</verb> of your Rebel fleet.</sp>

<sd>Luke looks up sharply.</sd>

<sp><speaker>EMPEROR</speaker>
Yes...I <verb lemma="assure">assure</verb> you we <verb lemma="be">are</verb> quite safe from your friends here.</sp>

<sd>Vader looks at Luke.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
Your overconfidence <verb lemma="be">is</verb> your weakness.</sp>

<sp><speaker>EMPEROR</speaker>
Your faith in your friends <verb lemma="be">is</verb> yours.</sp>

<sp><speaker>VADER</speaker>
It <verb lemma="be">is</verb> pointless to resist, my son.</sp>

<sd>The Emperor turns to <verb lemma="face">face</verb> Luke.</sd>

<sp><speaker>EMPEROR	 (angry)</speaker>
Everything that <verb lemma="have">has</verb> transpi<verb lemma="red">red</verb> <verb lemma="have">has</verb> done so according to my design. 
(indicates Endor)
Your friends up there on the Sanctuary Moon...</sp>

<sd>Luke reacts. The Emperor <verb lemma="note">notes</verb> it.</sd>

<sp><speaker>EMPEROR	 (cont)</speaker>
...are walking into a trap. As <verb lemma="be">is</verb> your Rebel fleet! It <verb lemma="be">was</verb> I who 
allowed the Alliance to <verb lemma="know">know</verb> the location of the <verb lemma="shield">shield</verb> generator. It 
<verb lemma="be">is</verb> quite safe from your pitiful little band. An entire legion of my 
best troops awaits them.</sp>

<sd>Luke's <verb lemma="look">look</verb> darts from the Emperor to Vader and, finally, to the sword 
in the Emperor's hand.</sd>

<sp><speaker>EMPEROR</speaker>
Oh...I'm <verb lemma="afraid">afraid</verb> the deflector <verb lemma="shield">shield</verb> will <verb lemma="be">be</verb> quite operational when 
your friends arrive.</sp>

<setting>91   INT BUNKER - MAIN CONTROL ROOM</setting>

<sd>Han, Leia, Chewie, and the Rebel <verb lemma="strike">strike</verb> team <verb lemma="storm">storm</verb> through a door and 
enter the main <verb lemma="control">control</verb> room, <verb lemma="take">taking</verb> all of the personnel prisoner.</sd>

<sp><speaker>HAN</speaker>
All right! Up! Move! <verb lemma="come">Come</verb> on! Quickly! Quickly, Chewie.</sp>

<sd>The Rebel troops <verb lemma="herd">herd</verb> the generator controllers away from their panels. 
Leia <verb lemma="glance">glances</verb> at one of the screens on the <verb lemma="control">control</verb> panel.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LEIA</speaker>
Han! Hurry! The fleet will <verb lemma="be">be</verb> here any moment.</sp>

<sp><speaker>HAN</speaker>
Charges!  <verb lemma="come">Come</verb> on, <verb lemma="come">come</verb> on!</sp>

<sd>Outside, Threepio watches nervously in the bushes as several more 
controllers and stormtroopers <verb lemma="run">run</verb> into the bunker, <verb lemma="leave">leaving</verb> guards at 
the door.</sd>

<sp><speaker>THREEPIO	 (to Wicket)</speaker>
Oh, my! They'll <verb lemma="be">be</verb> captured!</sp>

<sd>Wicket <verb lemma="chatter">chatters</verb> in Ewok language, and then takes off full steam into 
the forest.</sd>

<sp><speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
Wa-wait! <verb lemma="wait">Wait</verb>, <verb lemma="come">come</verb> back! Artoo, <verb lemma="stay">stay</verb> with me.</sp>

<sd>Inside the bunker, Han looks up from setting charges as an Imperial 
commander enters.</sd>

<sp><speaker>COMMANDER</speaker>
Freeze! You Rebel scum.</sp>

<sd>Han and Leia spin, to <verb lemma="find">find</verb> dozens of Imperial weapons trained on them 
and their cohorts. A poised <verb lemma="force">force</verb> of Imperial troops surround them. 
Even more <verb lemma="pour">pour</verb> into the room, roughly <verb lemma="disarm">disarming</verb> the Rebel contingent. 
Han, Leia, and Chewie exchange looks. They're helpless.</sd>

<setting>92   EXT SPACE - ENDOR, DEATH STAR, REBEL FLEET</setting>

<sd>The Death Star and its Sanctuary Moon <verb lemma="hang">hang</verb> distant in space as the 
Rebel fleet comes out of hyperspace with an awesome roar. The 
Millennium Falcon and several Rebel fighters <verb lemma="be">are</verb> at the <verb lemma="front">front</verb> as the 
space armada bears down on its target.</sd>

<setting>93   INT MILLENNIUM FALCON - COCKPIT</setting>

<sd>Lando flips switches, checks his screen, and speaks into the radio.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LANDO</speaker>
All wings <verb lemma="report">report</verb> in.</sp>

<sp><speaker>WEDGE</speaker>
Red Leader standing by.</sp>

<sp><speaker>GRAY LEADER</speaker>
Gray Leader standing by.</sp>

<sp><speaker>GREEN LEADER</speaker>
Green Leader standing by.</sp>

<sp><speaker>WEDGE</speaker>
<verb lemma="lock">Lock</verb> S-foils in <verb lemma="attack">attack</verb> positions.</sp>

<setting>94   INT REBEL STAR CRUISER - BRIDGE</setting>

<sd>From the bridge of the Rebel Headquarters Frigate, Admiral Ackbar 
watches the fighters <verb lemma="mass">massing</verb> outside his viewscreen.</sd>

<sp><speaker>ACKBAR</speaker>
May the Force <verb lemma="be">be</verb> with us.</sp>

<setting>95   INT MILLENNIUM FALCON - COCKPIT</setting>

<sd>Lando looks worriedly at his alien copilot, Nien Nunb, who points to 
the <verb lemma="control">control</verb> panel and talks to Lando.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LANDO</speaker>
We've got to <verb lemma="be">be</verb> able to <verb lemma="get">get</verb> some kind of a reading on that shield, up 
or down. Well, how
could they <verb lemma="be">be</verb> <verb lemma="jam">jamming</verb> us if they don't <verb lemma="know">know</verb> if we're coming.</sp>

<sd>Lando shoots a concerned <verb lemma="look">look</verb> out at the approaching Death Star as the 
implications of what he's just said <verb lemma="sink">sink</verb> in. He hits a <verb lemma="switch">switch</verb> on his 
comlink.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LANDO</speaker>
<verb lemma="break">Break</verb> off the attack! The <verb lemma="shield">shield</verb> <verb lemma="be">is</verb> still up.</sp>

<sp><speaker>RED LEADER	 (VO)</speaker>
I <verb lemma="get">get</verb> no reading. Are you sure?</sp>

<sp><speaker>LANDO</speaker>
<verb lemma="pull">Pull</verb> up! All craft <verb lemma="pull">pull</verb> up!</sp>

<sd>The Falcon turns hard to the left. Out the window the stars and the 
Death Star <verb lemma="move">move</verb> off right.</sd>

<setting>96   EXT SPACE - DEATH STAR SHIELD</setting>

<sd>The Falcon and the fighters of Red Squad <verb lemma="veer">veer</verb> off desperately to <verb lemma="avoid">avoid</verb> 
the unseen wall.</sd>

<setting>97   INT REBEL STAR CRUISER - BRIDGE</setting>

<sd>Alarms <verb lemma="be">are</verb> screaming and lights flashing as the huge <verb lemma="ship">ship</verb> changes 
<verb lemma="course">course</verb> abruptly. Other ships in the fleet <verb lemma="shoot">shoot</verb> by outside as the 
armada <verb lemma="try">tries</verb> to <verb lemma="halt">halt</verb> its forward momentum.</sd>

<sp><speaker>ACKBAR</speaker>
<verb lemma="take">Take</verb> evasive action! Green Group, <verb lemma="stick">stick</verb> <verb lemma="close">close</verb> to holding sector MV-7.</sp>

<sd>A Mon Calamari controller turns away from his screen and calls out to 
Ackbar, quite excited. The Admiral rushes over to the controller.</sd>

<sp><speaker>CONTROLLER</speaker>
Admiral, we <verb lemma="have">have</verb> enemy ships in sector 47.</sp>

<sd>On the screen can <verb lemma="be">be</verb> seen the moon, Death Star, and the massive 
Imperial fleet. Ackbar moves to the comlink.</sd>

<sp><speaker>ACKBAR</speaker>
It's a trap!</sp>

<sp><speaker>LANDO	 (over comlink)</speaker>
Fighters coming in.</sp>

<sd>There <verb lemma="be">is</verb> much excitement on the bridge as the <verb lemma="attack">attack</verb> begins.</sd>

<sd>The Millennium Falcon and several squads of Rebel fighters <verb lemma="head">head</verb> into an 
armada of TIE fighters. The sky explodes as a fierce dogfight ensues in 
and around the giant Rebel cruisers.</sd>

<sp><speaker>REBEL PILOT</speaker>
There's too many of them!</sp>

<sp><speaker>LANDO</speaker>
Accelerate to <verb lemma="attack">attack</verb> speed! <verb lemma="draw">Draw</verb> their <verb lemma="fire">fire</verb> away from the cruisers.</sp>

<sp><speaker>WEDGE</speaker>
Copy, Gold Leader.</sp>

<sd>The <verb lemma="battle">battle</verb> continues around the giant cruisers.</sd>

<setting>98   INT DEATH STAR - EMPEROR'S THRONE ROOM</setting>

<sd>Through the <verb lemma="round">round</verb> window behind the Emperor's throne can <verb lemma="be">be</verb> seen the 
distant flashes of the space <verb lemma="battle">battle</verb> in progress.</sd>

<sp><speaker>EMPEROR</speaker>
Come, boy. <verb lemma="see">See</verb> for yourself.</sp>

<sd>The Emperor <verb lemma="be">is</verb> sitting in his throne, with Vader standing at his side. 
Luke moves to <verb lemma="look">look</verb> through a small section of the window.</sd>

<sp><speaker>EMPEROR</speaker>
From here you will witness the final destruction of the Alliance, and 
the end of your insignificant Rebellion.</sp>

<sd>Luke <verb lemma="be">is</verb> in torment. He <verb lemma="glance">glances</verb> at his lightsaber sitting on the armrest 
of the throne. The Emperor watches him and smiles, touches the 
lightsaber.</sd>

<sp><speaker>EMPEROR</speaker>
You <verb lemma="want">want</verb> this, don't you? The hate <verb lemma="be">is</verb> <verb lemma="swell">swelling</verb> in you now. <verb lemma="take">Take</verb> your 
Jedi weapon. <verb lemma="use">Use</verb> it. I am unarmed. <verb lemma="strike">Strike</verb> me down with it. <verb lemma="give">Give</verb> in to 
your anger. With each passing moment, you <verb lemma="make">make</verb> yourself more my 
servant.</sp>

<sd>Vader watches Luke in his agony.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
No!</sp>

<sp><speaker>EMPEROR</speaker>
It <verb lemma="be">is</verb> unavoidable. It <verb lemma="be">is</verb> your destiny. You, <verb lemma="like">like</verb> your father, <verb lemma="be">are</verb> now 
mine!</sp>

<setting>99   EXT FOREST - GENERATOR BUNKER</setting>

<sd>Han, Leia, Chewie, and the <verb lemma="rest">rest</verb> of the <verb lemma="strike">strike</verb> team <verb lemma="be">are</verb> <verb lemma="lead">led</verb> out of the 
bunker by their captors. The surrounding area, <verb lemma="desert">deserted</verb> before, <verb lemma="be">is</verb> now 
crowded with two-legged Imperial walkers and hundreds of Imperial 
troops. The situation looks hopeless.</sd>

<sp><speaker>STORMTROOPER</speaker>
All right, <verb lemma="move">move</verb> it! I said <verb lemma="move">move</verb> it! <verb lemma="go">Go</verb> on!</sp>

<sd>From the undergrowth beyond the clearing comes a wild series of beeps 
and whistles. 
And --</sd>

<sp><speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
Hello! I say, over there! Were you looking for me?</sp>

<sp><speaker>BUNKER COMMANDER</speaker>
<verb lemma="bring">Bring</verb> those two down here!</sp>

<sp><speaker>STORMTROOPER</speaker>
Let's go!</sp>

<sd>Artoo and Threepio <verb lemma="be">are</verb> standing near one of the big trees. As six 
Imperial stormtroopers <verb lemma="rush">rush</verb> over to <verb lemma="take">take</verb> them captive, the two droids 
<verb lemma="duck">duck</verb> out of sight behind the tree.</sd>

<sp><speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
Well, they're on their way. Artoo, <verb lemma="be">are</verb> you <verb lemma="sure">sure</verb> this <verb lemma="be">was</verb> a good idea?</sp>

<sp><speaker>STORMTROOPER</speaker>
Freeze! Don't move!</sp>

<sp><speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
We surrender.</sp>

<sd>The stormtroopers <verb lemma="come">come</verb> around the tree and <verb lemma="find">find</verb> the two droids waiting 
quietly to <verb lemma="be">be</verb> taken. As the Imperial troops <verb lemma="move">move</verb> to <verb lemma="do">do</verb> that, however, a 
band of Ewoks drops down from above and <verb lemma="overpower">overpowers</verb> them.</sd>

<sp><speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
Ohhh! <verb lemma="stand">Stand</verb> back, Artoo.</sp>

<sd>In a nearby tree, an Ewok raises a horn to his lips and sounds the EWOK 
ATTACK CALL. All hell breaks loose as hundreds of Ewoks <verb lemma="throw">throw</verb> their 
fuzzy bodies into the fray against the assembled stormtroopers and 
their awesome two-legged walkers. Biker scouts <verb lemma="dart">dart</verb> about blasting 
Ewoks, only to <verb lemma="be">be</verb> crushed by a volley of rocks tossed by Ewoks from the 
trees above.</sd>

<sd>In the confusion of the battle, Han and Leia <verb lemma="break">break</verb> away and <verb lemma="dive">dive</verb> for 
the <verb lemma="cover">cover</verb> of the bunker door as explosions <verb lemma="erupt">erupt</verb> around them. Han goes 
to the bunker door <verb lemma="control">control</verb> panel.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LEIA</speaker>
The code's changed. We <verb lemma="need">need</verb> Artoo!</sp>

<sp><speaker>HAN</speaker>
Here's the terminal.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LEIA	 (into comlink)</speaker>
Artoo, where <verb lemma="be">are</verb> you? We <verb lemma="need">need</verb> you at the bunker right away.</sp>

<sd>Artoo and Threepio <verb lemma="be">are</verb> <verb lemma="hide">hiding</verb> behind a log as the <verb lemma="battle">battle</verb> ragesaround 
them. Suddenly the stubby little astrodroid lets out a series of 
whistles and shoots off across the battlefield. Threepio, panicked, 
runs after him.</sd>

<sp><speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
Going? What <verb lemma="do">do</verb> you mean, you're going. But-- but going where, Artoo? 
No, what! Artoo! Oh, this <verb lemma="be">is</verb> no time for heroics. <verb lemma="come">Come</verb> back!</sp>

<sd>Biker scouts <verb lemma="race">race</verb> around and over the two droids, blasting away at the 
little Ewoks as the furries <verb lemma="scurry">scurry</verb> for cover.</sd>

<sd>A group of Ewoks <verb lemma="have">have</verb> moved a primitive catapult into position. They 
<verb lemma="fire">fire</verb> off a large boulder that hits one of the walkers. The walker turns 
and heads for the catapult, blasting away with both guns. The Ewoks 
<verb lemma="abandon">abandon</verb> their weapons and <verb lemma="flee">flee</verb> in all directions. Just as the walker 
moves in to <verb lemma="stomp">stomp</verb> the catapult, Ewoks <verb lemma="drop">drop</verb> vines restraining two huge 
logs that <verb lemma="swing">swing</verb> down and <verb lemma="smash">smash</verb> thewalker's <verb lemma="head">head</verb> flat.</sd>

<sd>A line of Ewoks <verb lemma="hang">hang</verb> desperately to a vine that <verb lemma="be">is</verb> <verb lemma="hook">hooked</verb> to a walker's 
foot. As the walker moves along, the fuzzy creatures <verb lemma="be">are</verb> dragged 
behind.</sd>

<sd>Two speeder bikes <verb lemma="chase">chase</verb> Ewoks through the underbrush. As the scouts 
<verb lemma="round">round</verb> a tree, they <verb lemma="be">are</verb> knocked off their bikes by a vinetied between 
two trees.</sd>

<setting>100  EXT SPACE</setting>

<sd>The Falcon and other Rebel fighters <verb lemma="be">are</verb> engaged in a ferocious combat 
with Imperial TIE fighters, the <verb lemma="battle">battle</verb> <verb lemma="rage">raging</verb> around thecruisers of the 
Rebel armada.</sd>

<setting>101  INT MILLENNIUM FALCON - COCKPIT</setting>
Lando <verb lemma="be">is</verb> in radio communication with the pilots of the other Rebel 
squads.

<sp><speaker>LANDO</speaker>
<verb lemma="watch">Watch</verb> yourself, Wedge! Three from above!</sp>

<sp><speaker>WEDGE</speaker>
Red Three, Red Two, <verb lemma="pull">pull</verb> in!</sp>

<sp><speaker>RED TWO</speaker>
Got it!</sp>

<sp><speaker>RED THREE</speaker>
Three of them coming in, twenty degrees!</sp>

<sp><speaker>WEDGE</speaker>
<verb lemma="cut">Cut</verb> to the left! I'll <verb lemma="take">take</verb> the leader! They're heading for the medical 
frigate.</sp>

<sd>Lando <verb lemma="steer">steers</verb> the Falcon through a <verb lemma="complete">complete</verb> flip, as his crew fires at 
the TIEs from the belly guns.</sd>

<sp><speaker>NAVIGATOR</speaker>
Pressure's steady.</sp>

<sd>The copilot Nien Nunb <verb lemma="chatter">chatters</verb> an observation.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LANDO</speaker>
Only the fighters <verb lemma="be">are</verb> attacking.  I wonder what those Star Destroyers 
<verb lemma="be">are</verb> waiting for.</sp>

<setting>102  EXT SPACE - IMPERIAL FLEET  </setting>

<sd>The giant Imperial Star Destroyer waits silently some <verb lemma="distance">distance</verb> from the 
battle. The Emperor's huge Super Star Destroyer rests in the middle of 
the fleet.</sd>

<setting>103  INT SUPER STAR DESTROYER - BRIDGE</setting>

<sd>Admiral Piett and two fleet commanders <verb lemma="watch">watch</verb> the <verb lemma="battle">battle</verb> at the huge 
window of the Super Star Destroyer bridge.</sd>

<sp><speaker>COMMANDER</speaker>
We're in <verb lemma="attack">attack</verb> <verb lemma="position">position</verb> now, sir.</sp>

<sp><speaker>PIETT</speaker>
<verb lemma="hold">Hold</verb> here.</sp>

<sp><speaker>COMMANDER</speaker>
We're not going to attack?</sp>

<sp><speaker>PIETT</speaker>
I <verb lemma="have">have</verb> my <verb lemma="order">orders</verb> from the Emperor himself. He <verb lemma="have">has</verb> something special 
planned for them. We only <verb lemma="need">need</verb> to <verb lemma="keep">keep</verb> them from escaping.</sp>

<setting>104  INT EMPEROR'S TOWER - THRONE ROOM</setting>

<sd>The Emperor, Vader, and a horrified Luke <verb lemma="watch">watch</verb> the aerial <verb lemma="battle">battle</verb> 
fireworks out the window and on the viewscreens. Another Rebel <verb lemma="ship">ship</verb> 
explodes against the protective shield.</sd>

<sp><speaker>EMPEROR</speaker>
As you can see, my young apprentice, your friends <verb lemma="have">have</verb> failed. Now 
witness the firepower of this fully <verb lemma="arm">armed</verb> and operational <verb lemma="battle">battle</verb> 
station.
(into comlink)
<verb lemma="fire">Fire</verb> at will, Commander.</sp>

<sd>Luke, in shock, looks out across the surface of the Death Star to the 
Rebel fleet beyond.</sd>

<setting>105  INT DEATH STAR - CONTROL ROOM</setting>

<sd>Controllers <verb lemma="pull">pull</verb> <verb lemma="back">back</verb> on several switches. Commander Jerjerrod stands 
over them.</sd>

<sp><speaker>JERJERROD</speaker>
Fire!</sp>

<setting>106  INT DEATH STAR - BLAST CHAMBER</setting>

<sd>A button <verb lemma="be">is</verb> pressed, which switches on a panel of lights. A hooded 
Imperial soldier reaches overhead and pulls a lever. A huge beam of 
<verb lemma="light">light</verb> emanates from a long shaft. Two stormtroopers <verb lemma="stand">stand</verb> to one <verb lemma="side">side</verb> 
at a <verb lemma="control">control</verb> panel.</sd>

<setting>107  EXT DEATH STAR</setting>

<sd>The giant laser dish on the completed half of the Death Star begins to 
glow; Then a powerful beams shoots out toward the aerial battle.</sd>

<setting>108  EXT SPACE - AIR BATTLE</setting>

<sd>The air <verb lemma="be">is</verb> thick with giant ships. In among them, Rebel X-wings 
dogfight with Imperial TIE fighters. Now an enormous Rebel cruiser <verb lemma="be">is</verb> 
<verb lemma="hit">hit</verb> by the Death Star beam and <verb lemma="be">is</verb> blown to dust.</sd>

<sd>The Millennium Falcon roars over CAMERA, followed closely byseveral TIE 
fighters.</sd>

<setting>109  INT MILLENNIUM FALCON - COCKPIT</setting>

<sd>The <verb lemma="ship">ship</verb> <verb lemma="be">is</verb> <verb lemma="buffet">buffeted</verb> by the tremendous explosion of the Rebel cruiser. 
Lando and his copilot <verb lemma="be">are</verb> <verb lemma="stun">stunned</verb> by the sight of the Death Star 
firepower.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LANDO</speaker>
That <verb lemma="blast">blast</verb> <verb lemma="come">came</verb> from the Death Star! That thing's operational! 
(into comlink)
Home One, this <verb lemma="be">is</verb> Gold Leader.</sp>

<setting>110  INT REBEL STAR CRUISER - BRIDGE</setting>

<sd>Ackbar stands amid the confusion on the wide bridge and speaks into the 
comlink.</sd>

<sp><speaker>ACKBAR</speaker>
We <verb lemma="see">saw</verb> it. All craft prepare to retreat.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LANDO</speaker>
You won't <verb lemma="get">get</verb> another chance at this, Admiral.</sp>

<sp><speaker>ACKBAR</speaker>
We <verb lemma="have">have</verb> no choice, General Calrissian. Our cruisers can't <verb lemma="repel">repel</verb> 
firepower of that magnitude.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LANDO</speaker>
Han will <verb lemma="have">have</verb> that <verb lemma="shield">shield</verb> down. We've got to <verb lemma="give">give</verb> him more time.</sp>

<setting>111  EXT FOREST - GENERATOR BUNKER</setting>

<sd>Artoo and Threepio <verb lemma="make">make</verb> it to the door, as Han and Leia <verb lemma="provide">provide</verb> <verb lemma="cover">cover</verb> 
fire.</sd>

<sp><speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
We're coming!</sp>

<sp><speaker>HAN</speaker>
<verb lemma="come">Come</verb> on! <verb lemma="come">Come</verb> on!</sp>

<sp><speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
Oh, Artoo, hurry!</sp>

<sd>The little <verb lemma="droid">droid</verb> moves to the terminal and plugs in his computer arm. A 
large explosion hits near Artoo, knocking him <verb lemma="head">head</verb> over heels, finally 
landing on his feet. The stubby astrodroid's <verb lemma="head">head</verb> <verb lemma="be">is</verb> spinning and 
smoldering. Suddenly there <verb lemma="be">is</verb> a loud SPROOING and Han and Leia <verb lemma="turn">turn</verb> 
around to <verb lemma="see">see</verb> Artoo with all his compartment doors open, and all of his 
appendages sticking out; water and smoke <verb lemma="spurt">spurt</verb> out of the nozzles in 
his body. Han rushes to the terminal, as Threepio rushes to his <verb lemma="wound">wounded</verb> 
companion.</sd>

<sp><speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
My goodness! Artoo, why <verb lemma="do">did</verb> you <verb lemma="have">have</verb> to <verb lemma="be">be</verb> so brave?</sp>

<sp><speaker>HAN</speaker>
Well, I <verb lemma="suppose">suppose</verb> I could <verb lemma="hotwire">hotwire</verb> this thing.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LEIA</speaker>
I'll <verb lemma="cover">cover</verb> you.</sp>

<sd>Ewoks in handmade, primitive hanggliders <verb lemma="drop">drop</verb> rocks onto the 
stormtroopers, divebombing their deadly adversaries.  One <verb lemma="be">is</verb> <verb lemma="hit">hit</verb> in the 
wing with laser <verb lemma="fire">fire</verb> and crashes. A walker lumbers forward, shooting 
laser blasts at frantic Ewoks running in all directions.  Two Ewoks <verb lemma="be">are</verb> 
<verb lemma="strike">struck</verb> down by laser blasts.  One <verb lemma="try">tries</verb> to <verb lemma="awaken">awaken</verb> his friend, then 
realizes that he <verb lemma="be">is</verb> dead.</sd>

<setting>112  EXT SPACE - DEATH STAR</setting>

<sd>The Rebel fleet continues to <verb lemma="be">be</verb> picked off, from one <verb lemma="side">side</verb> by the Death 
Star's deadly beam, from the other by the <verb lemma="rampage">rampaging</verb> Imperial Star 
Destroyers.</sd>

<setting>113  INT MILLENNIUM FALCON - COCKPIT</setting>

<sd>Lando <verb lemma="steer">steers</verb> the Falcon wildly through an obstacle <verb lemma="course">course</verb> of floating 
giants. He's been yelling into the comlink.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LANDO	 (desperately)</speaker>
Yes! I said closer! <verb lemma="move">Move</verb> as <verb lemma="close">close</verb> as you can and engage those Star 
Destroyers at point-
blank range.</sp>

<sp><speaker>ACKBAR</speaker>
At that <verb lemma="close">close</verb> range, we won't <verb lemma="last">last</verb> long against those Star Destroyers.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LANDO</speaker>
We'll <verb lemma="last">last</verb> longer then we will against that Death Star...and we might 
just <verb lemma="take">take</verb> a few of
them with us.</sp>

<sd>The Rebel cruisers <verb lemma="move">move</verb> very <verb lemma="close">close</verb> to the Imperial Star Destroyers and 
begin to <verb lemma="blast">blast</verb> away at point-blank range. Tiny fighters <verb lemma="race">race</verb> across the 
giant surfaces, against a backdrop of laser fire.</sd>

<sd>The <verb lemma="control">control</verb> tower of a Star Destroyer <verb lemma="be">is</verb> under attack.</sd>

<sp><speaker>REBEL PILOT</speaker>
She's gonna blow!</sp>

<sd>Y-WING PILOT
I'm hit!</sd>

<sd>The <verb lemma="damage">damaged</verb> Y-wing plummets toward the Star Destroyer, and crashes into 
the <verb lemma="control">control</verb> tower, exploding.</sd>

<setting>114  INT EMPEROR'S TOWER - THRONE ROOM</setting>

<sd>Out of the window and on the view screens, the Rebel fleet <verb lemma="be">is</verb> being 
decimated in <verb lemma="blind">blinding</verb> explosions of <verb lemma="light">light</verb> and debris. But in here there 
<verb lemma="be">is</verb> no <verb lemma="sound">sound</verb> of battle. The Emperor turns to Luke.</sd>

<sp><speaker>EMPEROR</speaker>
Your fleet <verb lemma="have">has</verb> lost. And your friends on the Endor moon will not 
survive. There <verb lemma="be">is</verb> no escape, my young apprentice. The Alliance will 
die...as will your friends.</sp>

<sd>Luke's eyes <verb lemma="be">are</verb> full of rage. Vader watches him.</sd>

<sp><speaker>EMPEROR</speaker>
Good. I can <verb lemma="feel">feel</verb> your anger. I am defenseless.  <verb lemma="take">Take</verb> your weapon! 
<verb lemma="strike">Strike</verb> me down with all your hatred, and your journey towards the dark 
<verb lemma="side">side</verb> will <verb lemma="be">be</verb> complete.</sp>

<sd>Luke can resist no longer. The lightsaber <verb lemma="fly">flies</verb> into his hand. He 
ignites it in an instant and swings at the Emperor. Vader's lightsaber 
flashes into view, blocking Luke's <verb lemma="blow">blow</verb> before it can <verb lemma="reach">reach</verb> the 
Emperor. The two blades <verb lemma="spark">spark</verb> at contact. Luke turns to <verb lemma="fight">fight</verb> his 
father.</sd>

<setting>115  EXT FOREST</setting>

<sd>The <verb lemma="battle">battle</verb> rages on. Stormtroopers <verb lemma="fire">fire</verb> on Ewoks with sophisticated 
weapons while their furry little adversaries <verb lemma="sneak">sneak</verb> up behind the 
Imperial troopers and <verb lemma="bash">bash</verb> them over the <verb lemma="head">head</verb> with large clubs.</sd>

<sd>A walker marches through the undergrowth blasting Ewoks as it goes. An 
Ewok warrior gives the signal, and a <verb lemma="pile">pile</verb> of logs <verb lemma="be">is</verb> <verb lemma="cut">cut</verb> loose. The 
logs <verb lemma="tumble">tumble</verb> under the walker's feet, <verb lemma="cause">causing</verb> it to <verb lemma="slip">slip</verb> and <verb lemma="slide">slide</verb> until 
it finally topples over with a great crash.</sd>

<sd>A scout bike races past and <verb lemma="be">is</verb> <verb lemma="lasso">lassoed</verb> with a heavy vine. The other end 
of the vine <verb lemma="be">is</verb> tied to a tree, and the bike swings around in ever-
tightening circles until it runs out of rope and
crashes into the trees with a huge explosion.</sd>

<sd>Chewie swings on a vine to the roof of one of the walkers. Two Ewoks 
<verb lemma="cling">cling</verb> to him. They <verb lemma="land">land</verb> with a thud on the top of the lurching machine, 
then <verb lemma="hang">hang</verb> on for dear life. One of the Ewoks peeks through the window.</sd>

<sp><speaker>WALKER PILOT #1</speaker>
Look!</sp>

<sp><speaker>PILOT #2</speaker>
<verb lemma="get">Get</verb> him off of there!</sp>

<sd>The walker <verb lemma="pilot">pilot</verb> opens the hatch to <verb lemma="see">see</verb> what's going on. He <verb lemma="be">is</verb> yanked 
out and tossed overboard before he can scream. The two Ewoks <verb lemma="jump">jump</verb> into 
the cockpit and <verb lemma="knock">knock</verb> the second <verb lemma="pilot">pilot</verb> unconscious. The Ewoks <verb lemma="be">are</verb> 
thrown violently as the mighty machine careens out of control. Outside, 
Chewie <verb lemma="be">is</verb> almost knocked overboard; he sticks his <verb lemma="head">head</verb> into the hatch 
with a series of angry barks. The Ewoks <verb lemma="be">are</verb> too busy and frightened to 
list<verb lemma="en">en</verb> to the Wookiee's complaint. Chewie slips inside the walker.</sd>

<sd>Chewbacca's walker moves through the forest, <verb lemma="fire">firing</verb> laser blasts at 
unsuspecting stormtroopers, and destroying other Imperial walkers. The 
Ewoks <verb lemma="shout">shout</verb> and <verb lemma="cheer">cheer</verb> as the giant machine helps <verb lemma="turn">turn</verb> the tide of the 
<verb lemma="battle">battle</verb> in their favor.</sd>

<setting>116  EXT FOREST - GENERATOR BUNKER</setting>

<sd>Han works furiously at the <verb lemma="control">control</verb> panel; wires <verb lemma="spark">spark</verb> as he attempts to 
<verb lemma="hotwire">hotwire</verb> the door. He <verb lemma="motion">motions</verb> to Leia, who <verb lemma="be">is</verb> blasting away at some 
stormtroopers.</sd>

<sp><speaker>HAN</speaker>
I think I got it. I got it!</sp>

<sd>The three wires <verb lemma="spark">spark</verb> as the connection <verb lemma="be">is</verb> made. With a LOUD WHOOSH, a 
second <verb lemma="blast">blast</verb> door crashes down in <verb lemma="front">front</verb> of the first.</sd>

<sd>Han <verb lemma="frown">frowns</verb> and turns <verb lemma="back">back</verb> to the wires again. Leia exchanges shots with 
stormtroopers in the bushes, then suddenly <verb lemma="cry">cries</verb> out in pain, her 
shoulder <verb lemma="hit">hit</verb> by a laser blast.</sd>

<sp><speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
Oh, Princess Leia, <verb lemma="be">are</verb> you all right?</sp>

<sp><speaker>HAN</speaker>
Let's see.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LEIA</speaker>
It's not bad.</sp>

<sp><speaker>STORMTROOPER	 (OS)</speaker>
Freeze!</sp>

<sd>They freeze.</sd>

<sp><speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
Oh, dear.</sp>

<sp><speaker>STORMTROOPER</speaker>
Don't move!</sp>

<sd>Leia holds her laser <verb lemma="gun">gun</verb> ready, behind Han, out of view of the two 
stormtroopers <verb lemma="move">moving</verb> toward them. Han and Leia's eyes lock; the moment 
seems suspended in time.</sd>

<sp><speaker>HAN</speaker>
I <verb lemma="love">love</verb> you.</sp>

<sd>Another shared <verb lemma="look">look</verb> between them, as she smiles up at Han.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LEIA</speaker>
I know.</sp>

<sp><speaker>STORMTROOPER</speaker>
Hands up! <verb lemma="stand">Stand</verb> up!</sp>

<sd>Han stands up slowly and turns, revealing the <verb lemma="gun">gun</verb> in Leia's hand. She 
<verb lemma="dispose">disposes</verb> of the stormtroopers in a flash. As Han turns <verb lemma="back">back</verb> toward 
Leia, he looks up to <verb lemma="see">see</verb> a giant walker <verb lemma="approach">approach</verb> and <verb lemma="stand">stand</verb> before him, 
its deadly weapons aimed right at him.</sd>

<sp><speaker>HAN	 (to Leia)</speaker>
<verb lemma="stay">Stay</verb> back.</sp>

<sd>The hatch on top of the walker opens and Chewie sticks his <verb lemma="head">head</verb> out and 
<verb lemma="bark">barks</verb> triumphantly.</sd>

<sp><speaker>HAN</speaker>
Chewie!  <verb lemma="get">Get</verb> down here!  She's wounded!  No, wait....  I got an idea.</sp>

<setting>117  INT EMPEROR'S TOWER - THRONE ROOM</setting>

<sd>Luke and Vader <verb lemma="be">are</verb> engaged in a man-to-man <verb lemma="duel">duel</verb> of lightsabers even 
more vicious then the <verb lemma="battle">battle</verb> on Bespin. But the young Jedi <verb lemma="have">has</verb> grown 
stronger in the interim, and now the advantage shifts to him. Vader <verb lemma="be">is</verb> 
forced back, <verb lemma="lose">losing</verb> his balance, and <verb lemma="be">is</verb> knocked down the stairs. Luke 
stands at the top of the stairs, ready to attack.</sd>

<sp><speaker>EMPEROR (laughing)</speaker>
Good.  <verb lemma="use">Use</verb> your aggressive feelings, boy!  <verb lemma="let">Let</verb> the hate <verb lemma="flow">flow</verb> through 
you.</sp>

<sd>Luke looks momentarily toward the Emperor, then <verb lemma="back">back</verb> to Vader, and 
realizes he <verb lemma="be">is</verb> <verb lemma="use">using</verb> the dark side. He steps back, turns off his 
lightsaber, and relaxes, <verb lemma="drive">driving</verb> the hate from his being.</sd>

<sp><speaker>VADER</speaker>
Obi-Wan <verb lemma="have">has</verb> <verb lemma="teach">taught</verb> you well.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
I will not <verb lemma="fight">fight</verb> you, father.</sp>

<sd>Vader walks <verb lemma="back">back</verb> up the stairs to Luke.</sd>

<sp><speaker>VADER</speaker>
You <verb lemma="be">are</verb> unwise to <verb lemma="lower">lower</verb> your defenses.</sp>

<sd>Vader attacks, <verb lemma="force">forcing</verb> Luke on the defensive. The young Jedi leaps in 
an amazing <verb lemma="reverse">reverse</verb> <verb lemma="flip">flip</verb> up to the safety of the catwalk overhead. Vader 
stands below him.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
Your thoughts betray you, father. I <verb lemma="feel">feel</verb> the good in you...the 
conflict.</sp>

<sp><speaker>VADER</speaker>
There <verb lemma="be">is</verb> no conflict.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
You couldn't <verb lemma="bring">bring</verb> yourself to <verb lemma="kill">kill</verb> me before, and I don't believe 
you'll <verb lemma="destroy">destroy</verb> me
now.</sp>

<sp><speaker>VADER</speaker>
You underestim<verb lemma="eat">ate</verb> the power of the dark side. If you will not fight, 
then you will <verb lemma="meet">meet</verb>
your destiny.</sp>

<sd>Vader throws the laser sword and it cuts through the supports holding 
the catwalk, then returns to Vader's hand. Luke tumbles to the <verb lemma="grind">ground</verb> 
in a shower of sparks and rolls out of sight under the Emperor's 
platform. Vader moves to <verb lemma="find">find</verb> him.</sd>

<sp><speaker>EMPEROR	 (laughs)</speaker>
Good.  Good.</sp>

<setting>118  EXT SPACE - AIR BATTLE</setting>

<sd>The two armadas, <verb lemma="like">like</verb> their sea-bound ancestors, <verb lemma="blast">blast</verb> away at each 
other in individual point-blank confrontations. A Star Destroyer 
explodes. The Rebel victor <verb lemma="limp">limps</verb> away, its <verb lemma="back">back</verb> half alive with a 
series of minor explosions. The Rebel cruiser <verb lemma="manage">manages</verb> to <verb lemma="move">move</verb> in next 
to a second Star Destroyer before it explodes completely, <verb lemma="take">taking</verb> the 
Imperial Star Destroyer with it. The Falcon and several fighters <verb lemma="attack">attack</verb> 
one of the larger Imperial ships.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LANDO</speaker>
<verb lemma="watch">Watch</verb> out. Squad at .06.</sp>

<sp><speaker>REBEL PILOT</speaker>
I'm on it, Gold Leader.</sp>

<sp><speaker>WEDGE</speaker>
Good shot, Red Two.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LANDO</speaker>
Now...come on, Han, old buddy. Don't <verb lemma="let">let</verb> me down.</sp>

<setting>119  INT BUNKER - CONTROL ROOM</setting>

<sd>Controllers <verb lemma="watch">watch</verb> the main viewscreen on which a vague <verb lemma="figure">figure</verb> of an 
Imperial walker <verb lemma="pilot">pilot</verb> can <verb lemma="be">be</verb> seen. There <verb lemma="be">is</verb> a great <verb lemma="deal">deal</verb> of static and 
interference.</sd>

<sp><speaker>HAN/PILOT	 (VO)</speaker>
It's over, Commander. The Rebels <verb lemma="have">have</verb> been routed. They're fleeing into 
the woods. We
<verb lemma="need">need</verb> reinforcements to <verb lemma="continue">continue</verb> the pursuit.</sp>

<sd>The controllers cheer.</sd>

<sp><speaker>CONTROL ROOM COMMANDER</speaker>
<verb lemma="send">Send</verb> three squads to help. <verb lemma="open">Open</verb> the <verb lemma="back">back</verb> door.</sp>

<sp><speaker>SECOND COMMANDER</speaker>
Yes, sir.</sp>

<setting>120  EXT FOREST - GENERATOR BUNKER</setting>

<sd>As the door to the bunker opens and the Imperial troops <verb lemma="rush">rush</verb> out, 
they're surprised to <verb lemma="find">find</verb> themselves surrounded by Rebels, their 
weapons pointed at them. Ewoks holding bows and arrows <verb lemma="appear">appear</verb> on the 
roof of the bunker. The Imperial troops <verb lemma="throw">throw</verb> down their guns
as Han and Chewie <verb lemma="rush">rush</verb> inside the bunker with explosive charges.</sd>

<setting>121  INT BUNKER - CONTROL ROOM</setting>

<sd>Han, Chewie, and several troops <verb lemma="rush">rush</verb> into the <verb lemma="control">control</verb> room and plant 
explosive charges on the <verb lemma="control">control</verb> panels and <verb lemma="rush">rush</verb> out.</sd>

<sp><speaker>HAN</speaker>
<verb lemma="throw">Throw</verb> me another charge.</sp>

<setting>122  INT EMPEROR'S TOWER - THRONE ROOM</setting>

<sd>Vader <verb lemma="stalk">stalks</verb> the low-ceilinged area on the <verb lemma="level">level</verb> below the throne, 
searching for Luke in the semi-darkness, his lightsaber <verb lemma="hold">held</verb> ready.</sd>

<sp><speaker>VADER</speaker>
You cannot <verb lemma="hide">hide</verb> forever, Luke.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
I will not <verb lemma="fight">fight</verb> you.</sp>

<sp><speaker>VADER</speaker>
<verb lemma="give">Give</verb> yourself to the dark side. It <verb lemma="be">is</verb> the only way you can <verb lemma="save">save</verb> your 
friends. Yes, your
thoughts betray you. Your feelings for them <verb lemma="be">are</verb> strong. Especially 
for...</sp>

<sd>Vader stops and senses something. Luke shuts his eyes tightly, in 
anguish.</sd>

<sp><speaker>VADER</speaker>
Sister! So...you <verb lemma="have">have</verb> a twin sister. Your feelings <verb lemma="have">have</verb> now betrayed 
her, too. Obi-Wan
<verb lemma="be">was</verb> wise to <verb lemma="hide">hide</verb> her from me. Now his failure <verb lemma="be">is</verb> complete. If you will 
not <verb lemma="turn">turn</verb> to the dark
side, then perhaps she will.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
Never-r-r!</sp>

<sd>Luke ignites his lightsaber and screams in anger, rushing at hisfather 
with a frenzy we <verb lemma="have">have</verb> not seen before. Sparks <verb lemma="fly">fly</verb> as Luke and Vader 
<verb lemma="fight">fight</verb> in the cramped area. Luke's hatred forces Vader to retreat out of 
the low area and across a bridge overlooking a vast elevator shaft. 
Each stroke of Luke's sword drives his father further toward defeat.</sd>

<sd>The Dark Lord <verb lemma="be">is</verb> knocked to his knees, and as he raises his sword to 
<verb lemma="block">block</verb> another onslaught, Luke slashes Vader's right <verb lemma="hand">hand</verb> off at the 
wrist, <verb lemma="cause">causing</verb> metal and electronic parts to <verb lemma="fly">fly</verb> from the mechanical 
stump. Vader's sword clatters uselessly away, over the
edge of the platform and into the bottomless shaft below. Luke moves 
over Vader and holds the blade of his sword to the Dark Lord's throat. 
The Emperor watches with uncontrollable, pleased agitation.</sd>

<sp><speaker>EMPEROR</speaker>
Good! Your hate <verb lemma="have">has</verb> <verb lemma="make">made</verb> you powerful. Now, fulfill your destiny and 
<verb lemma="take">take</verb> your father's
place at my side!</sp>

<sd>Luke looks at his father's mechanical hand, then to his own mechanical, 
black-gloved hand, and realizes how much he <verb lemma="be">is</verb> becoming <verb lemma="like">like</verb> his 
father. He makes the decision for which he <verb lemma="have">has</verb> spent a lifetime in 
preparation. Luke steps <verb lemma="back">back</verb> and hurls his lightsaber away.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
Never! I'll never <verb lemma="turn">turn</verb> to the dark side. You've failed, Your Highness. 
I am a Jedi,
<verb lemma="like">like</verb> my father before me.</sp>

<sd>The Emperor's glee turns to rage.</sd>

<sp><speaker>EMPEROR</speaker>
So <verb lemma="be">be</verb> it...Jedi.</sp>

<setting>123  EXT FOREST - GENERATOR BUNKER</setting>

<sd>Han and several of the fighters <verb lemma="run">run</verb> out of the bunker and <verb lemma="race">race</verb> across 
the clearing.</sd>

<sp><speaker>HAN</speaker>
Move! Move!</sp>

<sd>A shock <verb lemma="wave">wave</verb> knocks them flat as the bunker explodes, followed by a 
spectacular disp<verb lemma="lay">lay</verb> as the huge shield-generator radar dish explodes 
along with the bunker.</sd>

<setting>124  INT REBEL STAR CRUISER - BRIDGE</setting>

<sd>Ackbar, sitting in his <verb lemma="control">control</verb> chair, speaks into the radio.</sd>

<sp><speaker>ACKBAR</speaker>
The <verb lemma="shield">shield</verb> <verb lemma="be">is</verb> down! Commence <verb lemma="attack">attack</verb> on theDeath Star's main reactor.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LANDO</speaker>
We're on our way. Red Group, Gold Group, all fighters <verb lemma="follow">follow</verb> me. 
(laughs)
<verb lemma="tell">Told</verb> you they'd <verb lemma="do">do</verb> it!</sp>

<sd>The Falcon, followed by several smaller Rebel fighters, heads toward 
the unfinished superstructure of the Death Star.</sd>

<setting>125  INT EMPEROR'S TOWER - THRONE ROOM</setting>

<sd>Luke stands still, as the Emperor reaches the bottom of thestairs. The 
Emperor's laughter <verb lemma="have">has</verb> turned to anger. He raises his arms toward Luke.</sd>

<sp><speaker>EMPEROR</speaker>
If you will not <verb lemma="be">be</verb> turned, you will <verb lemma="be">be</verb> destroyed.</sp>

<sd>Blinding <verb lemma="bolt">bolts</verb> of energy, evil lightning, <verb lemma="shoot">shoot</verb> from the Emperor's 
hands at Luke. Even in his surprise, the young Jedi <verb lemma="try">tries</verb> to <verb lemma="use">use</verb> the 
Force to <verb lemma="deflect">deflect</verb> them. At first he <verb lemma="be">is</verb> half successful, but after a 
moment the <verb lemma="bolt">bolts</verb> of energy <verb lemma="be">are</verb> coming with such <verb lemma="speed">speed</verb> and power the 
young Jedi <verb lemma="shrink">shrinks</verb> before them, his knees buckling. The <verb lemma="wound">wounded</verb> Vader 
struggles to his feet, and moves to <verb lemma="stand">stand</verb> at his master's side.</sd>

<sp><speaker>EMPEROR</speaker>
Young fool...only now, at the end, <verb lemma="do">do</verb> you understand.</sp>

<sd>Luke <verb lemma="be">is</verb> almost unconscious beneath the <verb lemma="continue">continuing</verb> assault of the 
Emperor's lightning. He <verb lemma="clutch">clutches</verb> a canister to <verb lemma="keep">keep</verb> from falling into 
the bottomless shaft as the <verb lemma="bolt">bolts</verb> <verb lemma="tear">tear</verb> through him.</sd>

<sp><speaker>EMPEROR</speaker>
Your feeble skills <verb lemma="be">are</verb> no match for the power of the dark side. You 
<verb lemma="have">have</verb> paid the price for
your lack of vision.</sp>

<sd>Luke <verb lemma="writhe">writhes</verb> on the floor in unbearable pain, reaching weakly up toward 
where Vader stands watching.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LUKE	 (groans)</speaker>
Father, please. <verb lemma="help">Help</verb> me.</sp>

<sd>Again Vader stands, watching Luke. He looks at his master, the Emperor, 
then <verb lemma="back">back</verb> to Luke on the floor.</sd>

<sp><speaker>EMPEROR</speaker>
Now, young Skywalker...you will die.</sp>

<sd>Although it would not <verb lemma="have">have</verb> seemed possible, the outpouring of <verb lemma="bolt">bolts</verb> 
from the Emperor's fingers actually increases in intensity, the <verb lemma="sound">sound</verb> 
screaming through the room. Luke's body <verb lemma="writhe">writhes</verb> in pain.</sd>

<sd>Vader grabs the Emperor from behind, fighting for <verb lemma="control">control</verb> of the robed 
<verb lemma="figure">figure</verb> despite the Dark Lord's weakened body and gravely weakened arm. 
The Emperor struggles in his embrace, his bolt-shooting hands now 
lifted high, away from Luke. Now the white lightning arcs <verb lemma="back">back</verb> to 
<verb lemma="strike">strike</verb> at Vader. He <verb lemma="stumble">stumbles</verb> with his <verb lemma="load">load</verb> as the sparks rain off his 
helmet and <verb lemma="flow">flow</verb> down over his black cape. He holds his evil master high 
over his <verb lemma="head">head</verb> and walks to the edge of the abyss at the central core of 
the throne room. With one final <verb lemma="burst">burst</verb> of his once awesome strength, 
Darth Vader hurls the Emperor's body into the bottomless shaft.</sd>

<sd>The Emperor's body spins helplessly into the void, arcing as it falls 
into the abyss. Finally, when the body <verb lemma="be">is</verb> far down the shaft, it 
explodes, <verb lemma="create">creating</verb> a <verb lemma="rush">rush</verb> of air through the room.Vader's cape <verb lemma="be">is</verb> 
whipped by the wind and he staggers, and <verb lemma="collapse">collapses</verb> toward the 
bottomless hole. Luke crawls to his father's <verb lemma="side">side</verb> and pulls him away 
from the edge of the abyss to safety. Both the young Jedi and the giant 
warrior <verb lemma="be">are</verb> too weak to move.</sd>

<setting>126  EXT/INT - SPACE BATTLE - FIGHTER AND DEATH STAR</setting>

<sd>Rebel fighters <verb lemma="follow">follow</verb> the Falcon across the surface of the Death Star 
to the unfinished portion, where they <verb lemma="dive">dive</verb> into the superstructure of 
the giant <verb lemma="battle">battle</verb> station, followed by many TIE fighters.</sd>

<sp><speaker>WEDGE</speaker>
I'm going in.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LANDO</speaker>
Here goes nothing.</sp>

<sd>Three X-wings <verb lemma="lead">lead</verb> the <verb lemma="chase">chase</verb> through the ever-narrowing shaft, followed 
by the Falcon and four other fighters, plus TIE fighters who 
continually <verb lemma="fire">fire</verb> at the Rebels. Lights <verb lemma="reflect">reflect</verb> off the pilot's faces as 
they <verb lemma="race">race</verb> through the dark shaft.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LANDO</speaker>
Now <verb lemma="lock">lock</verb> onto the strongest power source. It should <verb lemma="be">be</verb> the power 
generator.</sp>

<sp><speaker>WEDGE</speaker>
<verb lemma="form">Form</verb> up. And <verb lemma="stay">stay</verb> alert. We could <verb lemma="run">run</verb> out of space real fast.</sp>

<sd>The fighters and the Falcon <verb lemma="race">race</verb> through the tunnel, still pursued by 
the TIE fighters. One of the X-wings <verb lemma="be">is</verb> <verb lemma="hit">hit</verb> from behind and explodes.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LANDO</speaker>
<verb lemma="split">Split</verb> up and <verb lemma="head">head</verb> <verb lemma="back">back</verb> to the surface. <verb lemma="see">See</verb> if you can <verb lemma="get">get</verb> a few of 
those TIE fighters to
<verb lemma="follow">follow</verb> you.</sp>

<sp><speaker>PILOT</speaker>
Copy, Gold Leader.</sp>

<sd>The Rebel ships <verb lemma="peel">peel</verb> off pursued by three of the TIE's, while Lando and 
Wedge <verb lemma="continue">continue</verb> through the main tunnel. It narrows, and the Falcon 
<verb lemma="scrape">scrapes</verb> the <verb lemma="side">side</verb> dangerously. Two other TIE fighters <verb lemma="continue">continue</verb> to <verb lemma="blast">blast</verb> 
away at them.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LANDO</speaker>
That <verb lemma="be">was</verb> too close.</sp>

<sd>Nien Nunb agrees. The <verb lemma="battle">battle</verb> between the Rebel and Imperial fleet rages 
on. Several cruisers <verb lemma="fire">fire</verb> at the giant Super Star Destroyer.</sd>

<setting>127  INT REBEL STAR CRUISER - BRIDGE</setting>

<sp><speaker>ACKBAR</speaker>
We've got to <verb lemma="give">give</verb> those fighters more time. <verb lemma="concentrate">Concentr<verb lemma="eat">ate</verb></verb> all <verb lemma="fire">fire</verb> on 
that Super Star Destroyer.</sp>

<sd>X-wings pilots <verb lemma="head">head</verb> across the surface of the huge battleship.</sd>

<setting>128  INT VADER'S STAR DESTROYER - BRIDGE</setting>

<sd>Admiral Piett and a commander <verb lemma="stand">stand</verb> at the window, looking out to the 
battle. They <verb lemma="look">look</verb> concerned.</sd>

<sp><speaker>CONTROLLER</speaker>
Sir, we've <verb lemma="lose">lost</verb> our bridge deflector shield.</sp>

<sp><speaker>PIETT</speaker>
<verb lemma="intensify">Intensify</verb> the forward batteries. I don't <verb lemma="want">want</verb> anything to <verb lemma="get">get</verb> through.</sp>

<sd>The commander <verb lemma="be">is</verb> looking out of the window where a <verb lemma="damage">damaged</verb> Rebel 
fighter <verb lemma="be">is</verb> out of <verb lemma="control">control</verb> and heading directly toward the bridge.</sd>

<sp><speaker>PIETT</speaker>
<verb lemma="intensify">Intensify</verb> forward firepower!</sp>

<sp><speaker>COMMANDER</speaker>
It's too late!</sp>

<sd>The Rebel <verb lemma="pilot">pilot</verb> screams as his <verb lemma="ship">ship</verb> hits the Star Destroyer, <verb lemma="cause">causing</verb> a 
huge explosion. The giant <verb lemma="battle">battle</verb> <verb lemma="ship">ship</verb> loses control, crashes into the 
Death Star, and explodes.</sd>

<setting>129  INT REBEL STAR CRUISER - BRIDGE</setting>

<sd>There <verb lemma="be">is</verb> excitement on the bridge as the <verb lemma="battle">battle</verb> rages on all sides. 
They <verb lemma="cheer">cheer</verb> as the giant Star Destroyer blows up.</sd>

<setting>130  INT DEATH STAR - MAIN DOCKING BAY</setting>

<sd>Chaos. For the first time, the Death Star <verb lemma="be">is</verb> rocked by explosions as 
the Rebel fleet, no longer backed against a wall, zooms over, unloading 
a heavy barrage. Imperial troops <verb lemma="run">run</verb> in all directions, <verb lemma="confuse">confused</verb> and 
desperate to escape.</sd>

<sd>In the midst of this uproar, Luke <verb lemma="be">is</verb> trying to <verb lemma="carry">carry</verb> the enormous 
deadweight of his father's weakening body toward an Imperial shuttle. 
Finally, Luke <verb lemma="collapse">collapses</verb> from the strain. The explosions <verb lemma="grow">grow</verb> louder as 
Vader draws him closer.</sd>

<sp><speaker>VADER	 (a whisper)</speaker>
Luke, <verb lemma="help">help</verb> me <verb lemma="take">take</verb> this mask off.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LURE</speaker>
But you'll die.</sp>

<sp><speaker>VADER</speaker>
Nothing can <verb lemma="stop">stop</verb> that now. Just for once... <verb lemma="let">let</verb> me <verb lemma="look">look</verb> on you with my 
own eyes.</sp>

<sd>Slowly, hesitantly, Luke removes the mask from his father's face. There 
beneath the scars <verb lemma="be">is</verb> an elderly man. His eyes <verb lemma="do">do</verb> not focus. But the 
<verb lemma="die">dying</verb> man smiles at the sight before him.</sd>

<sp><speaker>ANAKIN	 (very weak)</speaker>
Now...go, my son. <verb lemma="leave">Leave</verb> me.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
No. You're coming with me. I can't <verb lemma="leave">leave</verb> you here. I've got to <verb lemma="save">save</verb> 
you.</sp>

<sp><speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
You already have, Luke. You <verb lemma="be">were</verb> right about me. <verb lemma="tell">Tell</verb> your sister...you 
<verb lemma="be">were</verb> right.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LUKE</speaker>
Father...I won't <verb lemma="leave">leave</verb> you.</sp>

<sd>Darth Vader, Anakin Skywalker...Luke's father, dies.</sd>

<sd>A huge explosion rocks the docking bay. Slowly, Luke rises and, half 
carrying, half dragging the body of his father, <verb lemma="stumble">stumbles</verb> toward a 
shuttle.</sd>

<setting>131  EXT DEATH STAR</setting>

<sd>The Millennium Falcon leads a <verb lemma="swerve">swerving</verb> bomb <verb lemma="run">run</verb> through the immense 
superstructure of the half-built Death Star. The Rebel Star Cruisers 
outside continually <verb lemma="bombard">bombard</verb> the huge station. And each <verb lemma="direct">direct</verb> <verb lemma="hit">hit</verb> <verb lemma="be">is</verb> 
answered by resonating, chain-reaction explosions within the <verb lemma="station">station</verb> 
itself.</sd>

<setting>132  INT MILLENNIUM FALCON - COCKPIT AND GUN PORTS</setting>

<sd>Lando's crew fires away at the <verb lemma="pursue">pursuing</verb> TIE fighters as the dashing 
Baron of Bespin and his alien copilot home in on the main reactor 
shaft. It <verb lemma="be">is</verb> awesome. A lone X-wing <verb lemma="be">is</verb> just in <verb lemma="front">front</verb> of the Falcon.</sd>

<sp><speaker>WEDGE</speaker>
There it is!</sp>

<sp><speaker>LANDO</speaker>
All right, Wedge. <verb lemma="go">Go</verb> for the power regulator on the north tower.</sp>

<sp><speaker>WEDGE</speaker>
Copy, Gold Leader. I'm already on my way out.</sp>

<sd>The X-wing heads for the top of the huge reactor and fires several 
proton torpedoes at the power regulator, <verb lemma="cause">causing</verb> a series of small 
explosions.</sd>

<sd>The Falcon heads for the main reactor, and when it <verb lemma="be">is</verb> dangerously 
close, Lando fires the missiles, which <verb lemma="shoot">shoot</verb> out of the Falcon with a 
powerful roar, and <verb lemma="hit">hit</verb> directly at the <verb lemma="center">center</verb> of the main reactor.</sd>

<sd>He maneuvers the Falcon out of the winding superstructure just ahead of 
the <verb lemma="continue">continuing</verb> chain of explosions.</sd>

<setting>133  INT REBEL STAR CRUISER - BRIDGE</setting>

<sd>Ackbar and other Mon Calamari lean on the railing of the bridge, 
watching the large screen showing the Death Star in the main briefing 
room.</sd>

<sp><speaker>ACKBAR</speaker>
<verb lemma="move">Move</verb> the fleet away from the Death Star.</sp>

<setting>134  EXT DEATH STAR</setting>

<sd>An Imperial shuttle, with Luke alone in the cockpit, rockets out of the 
main docking bay as that entire section of the Death Star <verb lemma="be">is</verb> blown 
away.</sd>

<sd>Finally, just as it looks <verb lemma="like">like</verb> the Falcon will not <verb lemma="make">make</verb> it, Lando 
expertly pilots the craft out of the <verb lemma="explode">exploding</verb> superstructure and 
whizzes toward the Sanctuary Moon, only a moment before the Death Star 
supernovas into oblivion.</sd>

<setting>135  INT MILLENNIUM FALCON - COCKPIT</setting>

<sd>Lando and Nien Nunb <verb lemma="laugh">laugh</verb> and <verb lemma="cheer">cheer</verb> in relief.</sd>

<setting>136  EXT ENDOR FOREST</setting>

<sd>Han and Leia, Chewie, the droids, the Rebel troops, and the Ewoks all 
<verb lemma="look">look</verb> to the sky as the Death Star reveals itself in a final <verb lemma="flash">flash</verb> of 
self-destruction. They all cheer.</sd>

<sp><speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
They <verb lemma="do">did</verb> it!</sp>

<sd>Han looks town from the sky to Leia, a <verb lemma="look">look</verb> of <verb lemma="concern">concern</verb> on his face. 
Leia continues to <verb lemma="look">look</verb> at the sky as though listening for a silent 
voice.</sd>

<sp><speaker>HAN</speaker>
I'm <verb lemma="sure">sure</verb> Luke wasn't on that thing when it blew.</sp>

<sp><speaker>LEIA</speaker>
He wasn't. I can <verb lemma="feel">feel</verb> it.</sp>

<sp><speaker>HAN</speaker>
You <verb lemma="love">love</verb> him, don't you?</sp>

<sd>Leia smiles, puzzled.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LEIA</speaker>
Yes.</sp>

<sp><speaker>HAN</speaker>
All right. I understand. Fine. When he comes back, I won't <verb lemma="get">get</verb> in the 
way.</sp>

<sd>She realizes his misunderstanding.</sd>

<sp><speaker>LEIA</speaker>
Oh. No, it's not <verb lemma="like">like</verb> that at all. He's my brother.</sp>

<sd>Han <verb lemma="be">is</verb> <verb lemma="stun">stunned</verb> by this news. She smiles, and they embrace.</sd>

<setting>137  EXT ENDOR FOREST - NIGHT</setting>

<sd>Luke sets a torch to the logs <verb lemma="stack">stacked</verb> under a funeral pyre where his 
father's body lies, again <verb lemma="dress">dressed</verb> in black mask and helmet. He stands, 
watching sadly, as the flames <verb lemma="leap">leap</verb> higher to <verb lemma="consume">consume</verb> Darth Vader -- 
Anakin Skywalker.</sd>

<sd>In the sky above, fireworks <verb lemma="explode">explode</verb> and Rebel fighters <verb lemma="zoom">zoom</verb> above the 
forest.</sd>

<setting>138  EXT EWOK VILLAGE SQUARE - NIGHT</setting>

<sd>A huge bonfire <verb lemma="be">is</verb> the centerpiece of a wild celebration. Rebels and 
Ewoks <verb lemma="rejoice">rejoice</verb> in the warm <verb lemma="glow">glow</verb> of firelight, <verb lemma="drum">drums</verb> beating, singing, 
dancing, and laughing in the communal language of victory and 
liberation.</sd>

<sd>Lando runs in and <verb lemma="be">is</verb> enthusiastically hugged by Han and Chewie. Then, 
finally, Luke arrives and the friends <verb lemma="rush">rush</verb> to <verb lemma="greet">greet</verb> and embrace him. 
They <verb lemma="stand">stand</verb> close, this hardy group, <verb lemma="take">taking</verb> <verb lemma="comfort">comfort</verb> in each other's 
touch, together to the end.</sd>

<sd>Rebels and Ewoks <verb lemma="join">join</verb> together in <verb lemma="dance">dancing</verb> and celebration. The original 
group of adventurers <verb lemma="watch">watch</verb> from the sidelines. Only Luke seems 
distracted, alone in their midsts, his thoughts elsewhere.</sd>

<sd>He looks off to the <verb lemma="side">side</verb> and sees three shimmering, <verb lemma="smile">smiling</verb> figures at 
the edge of the shadows: Ben Kenobi, Yoda, and Anakin Skywalker.</sd>

<sd>FADE OUT</sd>

<sd>END CREDITS OVER STAR FIELD</sd>
</script>


</root>